We've spent a lot of time working out the dynamic model of a fixed-wing aircraft,
and we have an understanding of
the different dynamic modes that the vehicle will exhibit.
But how do we actually put all this together to
get our flying car to follow a particular trajectory?
The dynamics of a fixed-wing vehicle mean,
that there are lots of plans that we just can't follow.
The vehicle obviously can't go backwards,
but it also use a stall speed and it has
a maximum bank angle that limits our turning radius to some minimum.
To simplify our planning problem and also simplify the control problem,
we're going to define a set of trim states that we can be
in and the goal of the autopilot is to move us from
trim state to trim state and keep us in
those trim states when the vehicle is perturbed by things like wind gusts.
These trim states are generally straight-line paths or curved orbits.
By restricting our trajectory to these states,
we're basically restricting ourselves to
either longitudinal dynamic modes or we're in level flight climbing or
descending or lateral directional flight where
we're doing a coordinated turn in one direction or another.
Can the vehicle do more things than that?
Of course, but more sophisticated maneuvers are a lot
harder to both plant and control so we're going to leave those for another day.