The controller you'll implement for the final project will consist of many control loops,
some of these will be nested inside other loops while others will not.
Some will have integral terms, some won't.
Some will have derivative terms and others will not.
Before we dive into the details of
the fixed-wing control architecture that you'll be implementing in the final project,
I'd like to discuss a few of the design considerations behind this architecture.
We're going to use the same kind of PID loops you saw in the control module,
but not every loop is going to look the same,
and it's important to understand how we're
making the design decisions of our controllers.
Firstly, we'll get simplicity of design by decoupling
the longitudinal and lateral control with two separate controllers.
When we get to longitudinal control,
we'll use this decoupling strategy again by defining
separate controllers for separate longitudinal flight regimes.
Secondly, every loop will have a proportional term,
but not all will have derivative terms and not all will have integral terms.
We'll also want much more responsive control
on some of the state variables than on others.
We always want the P term since that's the term that
actually steers the system towards the desired value.
Integral terms are good to have on the outermost loop of
a control system because they can account for any errors in our model,
and they ensure that the system eventually reaches the target state.
But I terms also add instability to the system.
So, in general, we want to avoid adding I terms to
inner loop controllers where instability can cause serious problems.
Differential terms damp out
oscillations and prevent overshoot in systems that have a lot of inertia,
but not much inherent damping.
As an example, we'll use a D term in the controller that sets
the elevator deflection based on error and pitch because without this term,
we'd get more oscillations.
By being careful with how we design
our control loops and what terms we include in each loop,
we can make the job of tuning a lot easier.