We're going to separate the control problem into
two separate autopilots: the lateral directional autopilot,
and the longitudinal autopilot.
Let's start with the lateral directional autopilot.
The lateral directional autopilot has two jobs: maintain the desired heading,
and keep sideslip to a minimum.
Each of these responsibilities is handled through its own controller.
The course controller maintains heading by controlling the ailerons.
So, it takes a commanded heading angle as input,
and produces an aileron command as output,
and this controller is actually a nested controller.
The outer loop uses the heading to generate a target roll angle,
and the inner loop uses the error enroll angle to command the ailerons.
This inner loop will be a PD controller.
Why don't we have an integral term in this inner loop?
Remember that the integrator's job is to handle any modeling errors,
but it can take some time for the integrator to get to the right value,
which limits how quickly the inner loop can respond.
We're going to try and get the inner loop's model of
the vehicle dynamics as accurate as possible to avoid needing an I term,
which will make the inner loop more responsive to disturbances.
Of course, if we have a more responsive inner loop,
we also want to make sure it doesn't over react to disturbances,
so we definitely want a D term to damp this loop.
This outer loop will be a PI controller.
Here is where we can use an I term to handle any errors in our model,
and because it'll be a much slower loop,
we don't need to damp it with a D term.
Responsiveness isn't as much an issue here.
The sideslip controller controls the sideslip angle with the rudder.
Generally, the target sideslip angle will be zero,
but there are some situations where that won't be the case.
This controller will be a PI controller.
Together, these three controllers,
each with two tunable parameters will be
enough to control the lateral directional motion of the vehicle.