Now that we can follow curved orbits with a lateral directional controller,
we can build a similar cascaded controller for straight line flights.
This controller will be responsible for getting
the vehicle to the correct altitude and their speed,
by controlling the elevator deflection and the thrust.
Before we build the longitudinal controller,
notice that we have some redundancy here,
since the pitch and the throttle could each
have an effect on the vehicles altitude and their speed.
To handle the redundancy,
we typically divide longitudinal flight into four zones.
In the takeoff zone, we want to climb at a specific pitch angle as quickly as possible.
So, we fly at full throttle and simply
use the elevators to keep our pitch at the desired angle,
how do we know what the pitch angle at takeoff is supposed to be?
It depends on properties of the vehicle,
things like the tail clarence which constrains
how much the vehicle can pitch, near the ground.
The takeoff angle also depends on what's around the runway.
The vehicle needs to be pitched enough to clear nearby buildings and trees.
Once airborne, we enter the climb zone,
here our goal is to climb to the target altitude as quickly as possible.
We still keep the full throttle here,
but now we use our pitch to control the air speed.
For going forward too fast,
we can pitch up and climb faster,
and if we're going too slow,
we can pitch down to avoid stall.
Once we get close to our desired height,
we're in the altitude hold zone.
In this regime, we regulate
our altitude with our pitch and our air speed with a throttle.
This zone is where we'll spend the majority of our flight time.
When the target altitude is well below the vehicle altitude,
we're in the descent zone.
This is similar to the climb zone,
except now we set the throttle to zero and use the pitch to control the air speed.
Flying in these four zones requires four control loops: pitch attitude hold,
altitude hold using pitch,
airspeed hold using pitch,
and airspeed hold using throttle.
Let's look at each of these loops a little more closely.