At this point, you're ready for the final project.
In this project, you'll use what you've learned about fixed-wing dynamics and control,
to implement an autopilot for a fixed-wing vehicle.
This autopilot will issue commands to the propulsion system and control surfaces,
to control a fixed-wing vehicle as it navigates from trim state to trim state.
The project is broken into scenarios which are meant to help you individually
isolate and tune all of the control loops that you learned about in this lesson.
You don't necessarily need to go through these scenarios in order,
but you'll probably find it easier to converge on
a working set of control parameters if you do. Good luck.