If you were able to implement all of the methods in this section on your own,
congratulations, because this math wasn't trivial.
If you needed to consult the solutions, that's okay too.
But either way, hopefully,
you saw that the maths gets more complicated when you transition to three dimensions.
This will become easier with experience and practice.
But I want to point out,
that trying to implement and code an equation that's given to you
in math is something you will have to do when working in this field.
As you move to different vehicle designs,
or work on different systems within a vehicle,
you'll likely have to acquaint yourself with a new domain by reading
papers and trying to reimplement something
that someone has already described mathematically.
For example, in the second half of the Nanodegree,
you'll learn about fixed wing aircraft,
and you'll find that while most of the controls concepts still apply,
some of the details of the dynamics will change.
So, with this in mind,
as we transition into full three-dimensional control,
we will also be introducing you to some technical papers
from the field and asking you to read sections of these papers.