So, finally after understanding the 3D dynamics of a quadrotor,
we can now think about controlling the vehicle.
Lots of the ideas that we saw for
the 2D quad control are essential for 3D controller as well.
For example, we use the same cascaded PD or PID control structure.
We also need a non-linear transformation in order to
translate target accelerations to motor forces and torques.
Let's look at the 2D control from last lesson.
A drone flying in the vertical plane with two propellers was an under actuated system.
This meant we could only choose two quantities we wanted to control,
and then we have to use the dynamics to design a control knob for those quantities.
For the 2D quad we wanted control knobs that could control Y and Z motion.
Our control knob for Z was the thrust.
In the non-linear case we had to increase the thrust when the vehicle was tilted.
Our control knob for Y was less immediate.
We had to first design a controller that linked phi to Y motion,
and then we designed a controller that linked the differential thrust to phi.
In 3D, we want control over X, Y and Z.
So, we can move the quad where we want it in space.
Then we typically choose yaw as our fourth controllable state variable.