We're going to talk more about a couple of
the individual controllers in this architecture.
But for now, I want to help you understand some
of the thinking that went into the controller design.
On the left, we have a trajectory.
For now, let's assume a trajectory contains target values for x,
y, z, yaw angle,
and the associated velocities.
It could also contain acceleration targets.
This trajectory gets split into three parts: a z part,
a lateral x and y part, and a yaw part.
The z trajectory is handled by the altitude controller.
The role of the altitude controller here is identical to what it was in the 2D case.
It sets the collective thrust.
The x and y trajectory is first handled by the level position controller.
This is almost identical to the y position controller from the 2D case.
The only difference is that,
this controller outputs acceleration targets rather than angular targets.
But this was just a design decision so that we could keep
all the more complicated angular control logic in the roll-pitch controller.
Finally, the yaw trajectory is handled by the yaw controller.
Now, let's go into each of these path in more detail.
Path one, altitude.
The altitude controller is responsible for ensuring the vehicle stays close to
the commanded set position and velocity by computing a target thrust value.
Now, note the inputs to the altitude controller,
everything related to the target and actual z,
plus it takes the quads current estimated attitude.
Intuitively, that's so that it can adjust its thrust when it's tilted.
And one more thing worth noting is that the output of
the altitude controller gets sent to the roll-pitch controller.
That's because the current commanded thrust is going to be shared in the x, y,
and z directions, and the portion that points in
the x and y will determine acceleration in those directions.
The other input to the roll-pitch controller comes from the lateral position controller.
Paths to lateral position.
Controlling lateral position is the most involved control loop.
The position controller is pretty straightforward.
It is just a PD controller on the x and y trajectories,
similar to what we saw for Y in the 2D case.
It generates an acceleration command in the x and y directions,
which is sent to the roll-pitch controller.
We have seen this cascaded structure before
a 2D and this roll-pitch controller is the most interesting of all of them.
Its job is to take a thrust command as well
as the desired x and y accelerations and the attitude,
pitch, roll, yaw, and p, q, r,
and output a target roll and pitch rate,
p command and q command.
These commanded p and q values get sent to the body rate controller.
The body rate control is just the p controller that converts p,
q, and r commands into three rotational moment commands.
The r commands come from the yaw controller.
Path three: Yaw.
As you can see, yaw is the least interesting of these loops and that's because it's
controlled through the reactive moment command and that command only affects yaw.
So yaw can really be treated almost in isolation.
In practice, if yaw does not matter for a specific application,
we often just try to keep the rate to zero and do not
even care about the exact yaw angle the vehicle is at.
By doing this, we ensure that all available thrust and
differential thrust is used for the translational motion that matters.