Before we jump into each of these individual blocks on this diagram,
it's important to point out that not every one of
these blocks will be filled with a PID or even a PD controller.
And that's because some of these blocks do not represent second order systems.
Recall the control diagram from the previous lesson,
each of the blocks of this diagram represent the second order systems.
The altitude controller took a z target,
along with its first and second derivative as an input.
And as an output, it produced a thrust which maps directly to
an acceleration which is the second derivative of the input z.
Since this controller was responsible for hitting
a target z by commanding its second derivative,
this was a second order system.
To stably control a second order system without oscillations,
you need to have a PD controller at the very least.
Sometimes, an I term is also useful but it can often be safely ignored.
The other two blocks in the 2D control diagram represented second order systems as well.
For the 3D diagram,
that isn't the case.
The altitude controller in 3D will still be
a PD controller since it's clearly a second order system.
But look at the yaw controller.
Its job is to take a yaw command as input and produce a yaw.command as output.
That's only a single derivative and that makes the yaw controller a first order system.
And this means that the yaw controller will ultimately be
implemented as a key controller without any d term.
The yaw controller isn't the only first order system in this diagram.
The body rate controller and the role-pitch controller are
also first order systems which will be controlled with p controllers.
The implementations of the yaw and body rate controllers will be pretty straightforward.
The role-pitch controller will be more complex and
that's because the role-pitch controller is responsible for handling
all the mathematical realness associated with
transformations between the world and the body frames.
At this point, I want you to read through a couple of sections of
a paper which gives an overview of how this math works.
As you read through some of this paper,
keep an eye out for the first auto p control equation.