When, you draw a box around all three of
these controllers and think of the inputs and outputs to this box,
you can see that this box is really controlling second order systems.
For example, yaw goes in as input and some moment is produced as output.
Since that moment controls the second derivative of yaw,
that makes the whole thing a second order system.
Likewise, the roll-pitch and body rate
controllers together make up a second order system.
The roll-pitch controller handles the first half of that system.
The job of the roll-pitch controller is to take command at x,
y accelerations, a thrust,
and the vehicle's attitude,
and produce a roll rate command,
abbreviated P subscript c in the paper,
and a pitch rate command,
Q sub c. This is the first order system.
For our purposes, the key equations in this paper are equations two and six.
Together, they represent some of the most complex math that you
will be implementing in Python and C++ in the final project.
Here, in equation two,
we start to see our control knobs for x and y emerging.
Here, in these equations,
c is the total commanded thrust,
and in this equation two,
we can see that the x acceleration, for instance,
is the product of this commanded thrust times this bx term.
It turns out that the x is the element in
the rotation matrix that must set in the body frame to x in the build frame.
This is just R13.
In effect, we are going to think of these elements in the rotation matrix,
R13 and R23, as the control knobs,
which are eventually going to control our x and y motion.
So, we want to command the value of these matrix elements,
but we need to know exactly how to do that.
Eventually, this controller needs to output commands for P and Q.
But we want to issue these commands by first,
setting targets for these matrix elements.
But how do we convert matrix element targets into P and Q commands?
Later in the paper,
in equation six, we are told how.
This equation gives us a P command and a Q command,
which is what we want our controllers to output and it does so,
in terms of the rotation matrix elements on
the left multiplied by these other two terms on the right.
And you have to be a little persistent in reading
the paper to realize what these terms mean
because this is where the actual P controller code for
the first order system comes in and it does so through this equation.
And this equation is given in the paragraph just before equation six.
This tau rp is the time constant in the pitch and roll directions.
And this bx, remember,
is an element of the rotation matrix,
and bx with a c subscript is our commanded value of this rotation matrix element.
And this looks exactly like
the first order math that I showed you earlier for the yaw controller.
Now, if you are careful and put this all together just right,
you will have a nice controller,
which realizes x and y accelerations by properly
controlling the value of elements of the rotation matrix itself.