The roll-pitch controller is
the most mathematically involved controller in this architecture.
We covered it first because we wanted to stay focused
on the math associated with 3D rotations.
But this isn't the first controller you would implement
if you were actually implementing this architecture from scratch.
The sequence you would want to take would be to
implement and tune the inner control loops first.
Remember, these inner loops generally
operate on a faster time scale than the outer loops.
So if you were just looking at the position controller,
roll-pitch controller and body-rate controller,
what sequence would you want to implement these controllers in?