You would want to implement and tune the body rate control at first.
Once you could rely on that controller to hit
its roll-pitch yaw rate commands, then implement roll-pitch.
To do that in practice,
you manually control the thrust to roughly counteract gravity.
Then, you implement the altitude controller because it's so critical to avoid crashes.
And finally, you implement the lateral position controller.
The majority of the rest of this lesson will involve
filling out and tuning the rest of these control loops.
The order we would ideally go in is: first, body rate; next,
pitch-roll; then yaw, and after that,
altitude, and finally, lateral position.
But you already saw the pitch-roll controller,
so the order will adjust slightly.
Each of these controllers will be presented in isolation,
and you'll be asked to implement a working solution for each of them.
We'll also be providing solutions for each,
but I highly recommend you implement
your own working controller at each step before looking at the solution.
If you do get really stuck, consult the solution,
understand it, and then go back and implement it yourself.
Even when you do get a working solution on your own,
you should also compare your version to the solution and note any differences.
This will also be a great opportunity to ask questions,
compare code, and discuss the material in the Nanodegree's Slack channels.
For the Python portion of the final project,
you will be combining these into a single file which will control a simulated 3D quad.