Congratulations!
I hope you enjoyed implementing each of those control loops.
At this point, you may have noticed that
these controllers seem to work with wide range of parameters.
Specifically, you may have noticed that
really aggressive proportional gains always seemed to make the controller perform better.
The reason you may have noticed this has to do with some of
the practical considerations we've
ignored in the quadrotor model you've been controlling.
So far, we've been assuming that the rotors can generate infinite thrust,
generate upward and downward thrust,
and instantaneously change thrust.
If rotors could really do that,
then any time the quadrotor deviated from the target trajectory,
the vehicle could instantly command
whatever massive force of torque was required to immediately correct itself.
In reality, all of these assumptions are wrong.
In reality, the motors have a minimum and maximum thrust that they can produce.
And the minimum thrust is a small positive number.
What that means is,
that the motors on a quad can only generate thrust in one direction.
Additionally, they have a minimum and maximum rate
at which they can change the thrust that they produce.
Parameter tuning becomes much more important
when these actuation constraints are taken into account.
In part of the final project,
you will get to work with a vehicle model that isn't quite
as forgiving as the model you have been working with in this lesson.
In fact, in the real world,
gains that are too high can actually cause instability.
Be on the lookout for this as you implement the final project.