Before you jump into the final project it's important
to connect what you did in path planning to what you'll be doing now.
In the previous project,
you implemented a 3D Motion Planner.
The output of that planner was a sequence of x, y, z waypoints.
Now, you are about to implement
a full controller and this controller really needs to target x,
y, z and yaw coordinates as a function of time.
Additionally, this controller will ideally need the first derivatives of the x,
y, and z coordinates as well.
So there are three main gaps between what you produce as
output and what the controller you'll write needs as input.
The first gap is the yaw information.
In order to control yaw,
your controller needs a target yaw value for any time in flight.
This is something that we will be providing on top of the x and y and z targets.
But you can think of yaw as a completely separate variable which
you may want to use to orient a camera on the drone for example.
The second gap is in the velocities.
Your controller needs to be passed target velocities and that's not
something that you thought about when doing path planning in the previous course.
You will be assuming constant velocity motion with some speed that we decide in advance.
The third gap is the time information.
You'll assume the vehicle travels in a straight line between
adjacent waypoints and use distance and velocity to assign target time to each waypoint.
You'll use some linear interpolation between
waypoints to find the target position at any arbitrary time.
Now, I want to point out that this is a very rudimentary technique for smoothing the waypoints.
And it results in trajectories with instantaneous changes in velocity at the case.
And these trajectories are actually impossible for the vehicle to fly.
Now, that's fine so long as you accept that
your vehicle's actual trajectory you will have to deviate slightly from the target.
And you give your vehicle enough of a buffer,
so that it doesn't collide with any obstacles.
In a more robust design,
you would want to take a different approach to this waypoints moving step.