In this lesson, you've seen how we can break
a complex controls problem into a sequence of first and second order systems.
And you've seen that second order systems can be controlled
with PD or with PID controllers.
You've also seen how a second order system can
sometimes be controlled with two cascaded P controllers,
which each control a separate first order system.
And in both cases,
there are going to be some physically meaningful parameters
that we can tune to adjust the behavior of the system.
These ideas of cascaded control and first and second order systems apply in 2D as well.
The main thing that changed in going from
two to three dimensions was how we had to think about attitude and rotations.
That's right. In three dimensions,
we really have to think in both the body frame and the world frame,
and converting between the two introduces
a mathematical complexity that controller just has to handle.
And just now, you saw how to use way points generated by
a 3D motion planner as input to a 3D quadrotor controller.
That means that you are ready for the final project for this course.
And this is a big deal.
Once you've completed this project,
you'll have implemented a large portion of
the full stack of a flying vehicle. Congratulations.