Welcome back. In the first three lessons of this course,
you've learned about quadrotor dynamics and quadrotor control in one and two dimensions.
And remember what it means to
understand the dynamics of a quadrotor.
It means that when we know the forces and the moments that are acting on the vehicle,
we can predict what the state of the vehicle will be in the future.
That's right. And understanding the dynamics is
really helpful for solving the problem of vehicle control.
When we solve a control's problem,
we go the other way.
We start with the desired motion and then we determine what forces and moments we need to
command to the vehicle based on
our current knowledge of the state of the vehicle compared to the target state.
And in this lesson, you're going to complete two major tasks.
First, you're going to model the dynamics of
a 3D quadrotor by implementing an advanced state function.
And once you've modeled the dynamics,
you'll learn how to solve the problem of three-dimensional control of a quadrotor.
Now, this lesson won't require introducing any brand new controls concepts,
but some of the math is going to get a little trickier than it's been up till now.
But I promise, it will all be worth it.
Because at the end of this lesson,
you will be able to design a full controller that can actually control a real quadrotor.