In 3D, we are going to do the same general sequence of steps to keep track
of the vehicle state but with slight modifications to keep track of rotations.
Remember we also call this attitude of the vehicle.
So, to do this,
we are going to need to think in two different coordinate systems,
something you saw in the Motion Planning Course.
The first is the world frame which is fixed in the world and
the other one is the body frame and that is attached to the quadrotor.
And as a reminder, when we look at the quad from above,
the body frame x-axis goes from the center of
the vehicle out between the two forward propellers.
The y axis then points to the right and
the z axis goes into the screen which would be down.
And the thing that makes 3D more difficult is keeping track of these two frames.
Especially when we have to do mass inside of
the rotating frame and then convert those rotations into
Euler angles in the world frame
because ultimately we want to control the drone in the world frame.
But we get some of our sensor measurements from the IMU which
measures turn rates in the body frame and our controls,
especially the moments that we command,
have a much more intuitive interpretation when we reason in the body frame.
Because of this, we really have no choice but to think
both in the world frame at some times and in the body frame at others.
So, let's go through the steps we outlined for 2D and make some additions and changes.