Just like we did in 2D,
we need to keep track of our vehicle's state,
but this time, we need 12 variables instead of six.
These variables specify the location of the vehicle as x, y, and z.
They specify the orientation of the vehicle in Euler angles, for roll,
pitch, and yaw, which we abbreviate with phi, theta, and psi.
We use Euler angles here because they are intuitive.
But we could equally use quaternions, for example,
or any other representation that describes orientation.
The 12 state variables also specify that x,
y, and z velocities,
which shouldn't be a surprise.
And then finally, they need to specify rotation rates.
For the 2D case,
that was a single quantity phi-dot.
In 3D, we must consider rotation rates about all three axes.
We will call them the body rates of the vehicle and the name is p, q,
r. Now, the important thing to note is that
these are not the same as phi-dot, theta-dot, and psi-dot.
And that's because the Euler angles phi,
theta, and psi are world frame coordinates.
To be precise, they describe the rotations
necessary to rotate the world frame into the body frame.
By the p, q, r variables,
give the angular rate of change of the vehicle in the body frame of the vehicle.
So p, q, r are the turn rates about the body x,
y, and z axis, respectively.
These are the rotational velocities that would be
measured by a gyroscope mounted on the vehicle itself.
It turns out, it is easier to work with p, q,
r than it is to work with Euler angle rates.
So tracking vehicles data looks similar in 2D and 3D with this one exception: p,
q, r are not the derivatives of phi, theta, and psi.
Next, we have step two,
figure out the forces and movements acting on the vehicle in the body frame.
Remember, these forces come from the rotation of the motors,
and in a body fixed frame,
the location of the motors are fixed which is to desirable.
All four motor forces point up in the frame of the body.
The net force in the body frame will be
the collective thrust from
the four rotors and it will be negative in the z direction,
since down is positive and up is negative.
The net torque should be easy to calculate in the body frame as well,
because the orientation or attitude of the vehicle doesn't matter.
At this point, we have two separate mathematical paths we have to take.
We have to figure out translational motion from the forces,
and then on a separate path,
we are going to consider how the moments influenced the rotational motion,
that will be a little trickier.
So we've got three things on our to-do
list before we can really solve the 3D dynamics case.
One, figure out exactly how four propeller turn rates,
turn into a net force and three moments.
Two, track the influence of force on translational motion.
And three, track the influence of the three moments on rotational motion.
We will walk through the first two in programming activities,
and then we'll come back for a bit more explanation about number three.