You're about to start your first programming exercise for this lesson.
But before you do, I want to walk through
this notebook and just make some points about it.
There are some differences between what we're
doing here and what we've been doing previously.
The first thing I want to point out is just how long this notebook actually is.
All of these exercises are actually going to take place in the same notebook,
every single exercise for this lesson.
And what that means for you is that any changes you make to this notebook in,
for example, the next exercise,
they'll show up in all future exercises as well.
So, what this means for you is that you should really
try to keep your code tidy if you can.
If you ever want to reset the notebook to where it began,
you can hit menu,
reset data, and go through this whole flow.
But keep in mind, if you do that,
you'll lose all your work,
all the changes you made up to that point.
So, just be careful. The second thing I
want to point out is some strange Jupyter notebook syntax.
So down here, you can see,
we defined a DroneIn3D class,
but we don't define the entire class in the cell.
In fact, in the cell, all we defined is the initializer.
Then we have some text and then down here,
we continue working on that same class.
We're adding to this DroneIn3D class and that's all that this syntax means.
So, don't be surprised when you see it.
The reason we're doing it this way is because it let's us
incrementally build up the class cell by cell.
Third thing I want to point out is how solutions are used in this notebook.
If you look here at this cell with all the imports, you see this line.
And in fact, UDACITYDroneIn3D and UDACITYController are actually
fully implemented versions of
the two classes that you will be implementing throughout this lesson.
And if you click up here on the Jupyter logo,
you could actually inspect that solution code by opening solution.py,
but you should try your best to solve these on your own before you do that.
So, let's go back down to this first class definition.
Here, you can see this DroneIn3D class actually inherits from the solution class.
And the reason we're doing it this way will be a
little more clear if we actually look at the first exercise.
So here, you can see exercise 1.1,
and this exercise actually already has a working implementation.
So, if I execute this cell and then run the testing cell,
you see test pass for exercise 1.1.
Now, the reason that worked is because what
this function is currently doing is just deferring to the super class implementation,
the solution class implementation of the same function.
What's nice about that is if you went through,
you could run this whole notebook and everything would actually work and
you would get a good sense for what it is you're going to be doing in this lesson.
But the only reason this code is passing is
because it's calling this super class implementation.
What you'll actually want to do when you get to these exercises is first,
maybe comment out the super class implementation and then start writing your code here.
You can see that if I comment out the super class and then rerun the cell,
the test isn't going to pass anymore.
All right, you're about ready to start exercise one.
In this exercise, you're going to
first define this set_propeller_angular_velocities function.
Then you'll write code to just calculate the rotation matrix.
Then you'll use that rotation matrix to calculate
the linear acceleration of the drone regardless of what state it's in.
So now, you should go through,
complete those three exercises,
and once you get test pass here,
you can see it says, Exercise 1 ends here.
At that point, you should press "Next",
and continue with the lesson. Good luck.