You've seen how to go from rotor rotation rates to controls.
And you've seen how those controls can be thought of
as a single collective thrust and three differential thrusts,
which have torques about the three rotation axes.
You've seen how to use the collective thrust,
a rotation matrix, and
two type integrals to advance the translational motion of the vehicle.
Now, it's time to use the differential thrusts to advance the rotational motion.
Let me walk you through how we're going to do that.
First, we are going to use Euler's equation to
calculate the rotational acceleration of the vehicle in its own body frame.
Next, we're going to integrate that rotational acceleration to find the new p,
q, r rotational velocities of the vehicle in its own frame.
Then, we're going to use some clever math to convert
the rotational velocity in the body frame to a phi-dot,
theta-dot, and psi-dot in the build frame.
Finally, we will integrate these quantities to get
the final Euler angle orientation of the vehicle in the world frame.
Depending on what representation of attitude you use,
the last set may look slightly different.
But in any case, we need to translate
body rotation rates into world frame attitude representation.