In lesson one, you saw the following equation.
And this equation says that a moment will cause a rotational acceleration.
And in this equation, all of these variables are just plain scalar numbers.
In three dimensions, this equation changes.
Note that this omega here is a length three vector with the three rotation rates.
And M is a length three vector giving moments about the x,
y, and z axis.
And the I term is a three by three inertia matrix summarizing all moments of inertia.
This is a nice equation but unfortunately,
it is only valid if we work in the world frame.
And it turns out that there are lots of
mathematical reasons why we don't want to work in the world frame for the step.
Namely, we want to calculate accelerations in the body frame.
Remember, all of our moments are relative to the body frame,
and our gyros measure rotation rates about the body frames axis.
And this moment of inertia is only a nice constant in diagonal matrix in the body frame.
So, to get a version of this equation where torques and
moments of inertia are expressed in the body frame,
we need to add some mathematical complexity.
And now, when we work in the body frame,
we have this additional term which you can read as omega cross I omega.
And this cross operation is a way of multiplying vectors called the cross product.
The details of the cross product, I explained below.
But honestly, any matrix math library has a cross product function you can simply call.
Now, at this point,
you might be feeling a little overwhelmed by math.
And understand that everything we are talking about right now really is math and physics.
And it's incredibly useful math and physics
because it tells us how our quad moves in three-dimensions.
It tells us what a quad can and cannot do.
But the details of this math and physics are beyond the scope of this course.
So for now, understand that you don't need to memorize these equations.
The important thing is that you can implement them, when you need to.
And now you will do exactly that.