Hopefully, you were able to use this equation along with the moments
and the moment of inertial matrix to calculate omega-dot.
You could then perform an integration of this omega-dot to figure out what the new p,
q, r all were.
This is analogous to using the linear accelerations to update the linear velocities,
and this means that nine of our 12 variables have been updated.
We are almost there.
All that's left is to update our Euler angles phi, theta, and psi.
Now unfortunately, this is not just a straightforward integration.
As I mentioned earlier, p, q,
r are not the same as phi-dot, theta-dot,
and psi-dot, so we can't directly integrate
them and we have one last tricky bit of math to do.
We'll link to papers that explore this math in detail,
but the equation we care about is this.
And conceptually, what this equation does is relates
an instantaneous turn rate in the body frame to
an instantaneous change in the Euler angles.
And note that we are using Euler angles under the hood
because they have a more intuitive interpretation than quaternions.
If you use a different attitude representation,
this above equation would change,
but would essentially do the same thing going from
rotation rates in the body frame to turn rates in the build frame.
And once again, you don't need to memorize these equations,
but when you work in this field,
and you see equations like this,
you now know why we need them,
and you should be able to implement them.
It's also important that you remember that these equations exist.
The dynamics of a quadrotor are pretty well understood.
And before you try throwing machine learning or neural networks and control problems,
it's usually helpful to first consult the physics.