So, now we are ready to write the code that you
would actually put in a drone to fly a real physical drone.
We're going to start a bit with
the proto-typing setup where we're going to do code in Python,
and we have a simulation of a join that you can then control.
You should start not just writing the code but also kind
of tuning the various gains of the controller because it's actually do matter a lot.
Then, we're going to import this code from Python to C plus plus
which is the preferred systems language because it's much more predictable in execution.
In C plus plus, you can do a few exercises.
We're going to tighten the dynamics of
your drone a little bit to make it even harder to control.
So, you get a flavor for how hard it actually is to make a drone fly.