We now have a notion of cost,
a function that provides a measure of how good or bad a partial plan is.
We can start to add in some guidance about how to make progress towards the goal.
Given a map of the world,
I can make a rough estimate of how far it is,
or in other words, how much it's going to cost to get
from the last state in any given partial plan to the goal.
In much the same way, you decide which way to go
when walking through the city on your way to your destination.
There are a couple of common ways to do this.
One example is estimating that the remaining cost to get to the goal,
is the euclidean distance from the last state in the partial plan to the goal state.
In our grid world, that looks like this.
Now, the value in each cell is the euclidean distance to the goal,
or in other words, the square root of the sum of the square of the x and y distances.
Such an estimate ignores obstacles,
and is going to be an underestimate,
but it will tell you whether the last state in
the partial plan is making progress towards the goal,
because progress means that the euclidean distance will get smaller and smaller.
Similarly, if you're moving away from the goal,
the euclidean distance will get larger.
Another common choice is the so called Manhattan distance,
which is just the sum of the x and y distances remaining to get to the goal.
The name comes from assuming you need to move through your grid based discritization,
like you would move through the city of Manhattan.
Lineally along the streets to form square blocks.
These distance estimates are what are known as heuristics,
and they help tremendously in finding a solution to the planning problem efficiently.
Your heuristic estimate doesn't have to be perfect,
but it does need to have one important property,
which is that it does need to always be an underestimate of the true cost.
This property of being an underestimate is known as being admissible.
One way to ensure that your heuristic is admissible is to ignore obstacles,
which is to say ignore the cost of going around obstacles.
The important thing about being at admissible heuristic,
is that if we incorporate the heuristic into our notion of the total cost of a plan,
they will never ignore plans or fail to expand plans,
because we overestimated their cost,
which ensures that we'll always find the lowest cost plan from start to goal.
We've got a cost function and a heuristic.
It's time to combine them to solve our planning problem.