In this lesson, we covered the foundations of solving the planning problem.
You looked at how to set up your search space which involve discretizing the world
into a set of individual states with a start and goal state for your vehicle.
You defined actions that describe how your vehicle moves from state to state.
And finally, you assigned a cost to each action that describes how
difficult or complex each action is relative to all the others.
After that, we looked at heuristics for estimating
the total cost remaining from the last state of a partial plan to the goal.
With a cost function and a heuristic that was both admissible and consistent in hand,
you implemented the famous A* algorithm to
utilize a map of the world to make your search more efficient.
These concepts are really at the heart of
any autonomous system when it comes to solving the planning problem,
but this is just the beginning.
Next up, we'll be looking at how to represent your vehicle within
the search space and other clever ways of discretizing your world.