Planning is a core capability of any autonomous vehicle.
But in reality, it's also central to your everyday life.
Before you leave your house to go somewhere, you make a plan.
In many cases, it might not even occur to you that you've made a plan.
But, in fact, throughout the day,
you're coming up with a detailed series of actions you need
to take to get from wherever you are to wherever you're going.
Flying cars operate in much the same way.
Suppose your flying car is located somewhere in the city and
is tasked with flying to some other location or series of locations.
Before setting out, it needs to make a plan,
which will require making decisions about
which path to take based on where obstacles or
no fly zones are and any other factors you want to take into account.
For example, you might want your flying car to focus on fuel efficiency,
or speed, or maybe even take the smoothest possible path to ensure passenger comfort.
Even more complicated, the flying car
might not know everything about the state of the world ahead of time.
A good planner might consider
possible contingencies and take various uncertainties into account.
Finally, there's more to planning than simply navigating and finding motion plans.
For example, for delivery vehicles,
there are decisions to be made about what order to make deliveries,
when to return home for fuel, and so on.
In this module, we'll focus on the 3D motion planning problem.
But in later modules, we'll look at these higher level mission planning problems.
All of these things taken together form the planning problem.
And at the end of the day,
solving the planning problem mostly comes
down to setting up what's known as your search space,
and then conducting a search through that space.
In this module, I'll be showing you how to represent
the 3D motion planning problem and how to conduct a search to find a viable plan.
We'll start off by solving some relatively simple two-dimensional planning problems,
and we'll talk about different ways to solve these problems efficiently.
However, 3D motion planning makes us think
about how we actually represent the vehicle and the world,
and we'll look at different representations.
Air vehicles often have complex dynamics.
They can't always move in arbitrary ways.
And we'll look at putting the dynamic constraints of the vehicle into the planner.
Finally, we'll examine some practical considerations to
keep in mind when executing a plan within a finite state machine.
At the end of these lessons,
you'll get to test your skills by implementing
a 3D path planning algorithm for your quadcopter.