Before your flying car can embark on a mission to pick up or drop off passengers,
it needs to have a plan.
A plan is really a series of actions that your vehicle must take in order to safely
and efficiently move from some initial location to some goal location.
Or, more generally, to transform the initial state into the goal state.
Let's consider a case where your flying car is at
the start location and you'd like to find a path to
a goal location and there are obstacles and
other things like no fly zones that you need to avoid along the way.
One way to think of a path from start to goal would be as
a continuous curve through their free space between the obstacles.
If you think about the infinitely many decisions the vehicle would need to
make along a flight path to follow any continuous curve to the goal,
the number of possible different action plans becomes infinitely large very quickly.
When it comes to solving the planning problem,
you will often be faced with constraints in terms of time and computational resources,
such that the real goal is not to find the perfect solution,
but rather to come up with a reasonable solution in a reasonable amount of time.
This is why your choice of representation of the problem, or in other words,
choosing the right search space is key to solving the problem as efficiently as possible.
So let's talk more about just what goes into choosing a representation.
Since reasoning about all the possible continuous curves from
start to goal would be super complicated, unnecessarily complicated,
we need a way to recast the problem and the natural way to do this,
as you would with most any computational problem,
is to break the continuous universe up into a finite set of discrete states.
Rather than describing our vehicle's path as a smooth curve,
we'll describe it as a series of states
the vehicle must pass through to get from start to goal.
Sometimes this is just a regular grid.
Sometimes there are more exotic ways to define
the states unevenly across the state space.
The definition of states only gets us
part of the way toward a representation of the problem.
We must also define actions which describe how the vehicle moves from state to state.
We'll see shortly that the choice of
state space and action space are really closely connected.
And to each type of action,
we must assign a cost which describes
how desirable or easy actions are relative to one another.
In summary, to represent your planning problem and define your search space,
you must have the following.
First, a set of all possible states in which a vehicle might find itself in the world.
Next, you need a start state and a goal state.
You also need to know the set of actions that
allow the vehicle to move from one state to the next.
And finally, you need to assign a cost to each possible action.
And there you have it, a representation of your planning problem and your search space.