What's the simplest representation I could choose for a search space?
Well, for starters, I'm going to ignore the vehicle's orientation.
I'll assume that the attitude of the vehicle doesn't matter,
and the vehicle is capable of moving in any direction at any point in time.
For now, I'll just consider a top-down two dimensional view of the world.
Then, I can put down
a regular grid-based discretization over the flight volume of the vehicle.
But now, I have a design issue,
which is how big to make the grid cells.
And that creates some issues in terms of how
computationally complex the planning problem is.
If I use a really fine grid,
I get better resolution of obstacles and freespace,
but solving the planning problem will be more computationally expensive.
If instead, I use a very coarse discretization.
I reduced computation time,
but might risk losing too much information regarding potential solutions.
Let me choose a grid resolution that seems to give
the right balance between resolution and speed,
and then I need to decide how I want to incorporate obstacles into this representation.
A common way to do this is to say that any
grid cell that contains an obstacle or part of an obstacle,
I'll label as off limits or infeasible shown here in red.
Now, the vehicle won't be allowed to enter these cells.
I'll label all the remaining grid cells as free space.
And that means that the plan,
given this representation, is a sequence of grid cells through the frees pace.
Those that don't contain obstacles from the start state to the goal state.
I now have the first three things I need for defining the search space.
I have my grid-based representation of the world, my start state,
which is whatever grid cell the vehicle happens to be in at the beginning of the mission,
and my goal state, which is
whatever grid cell contains the goal location for this mission.
The next thing I need is the action set.
Actions are, in this case,
whatever moves this from one grid cell to the next grid cell.
In a grid-based representation like this,
I can consider actions that move the vehicle right,
left up, or down,
or even diagonal motions,
if I want to allow for more complex plans.
The last thing I need is a cost function.
And to start with, I'll just choose something super simple.
I'll assume that every action has the same cost. A cost of one.
And with that, I have a complete representation of the problem.
But notice that I'm giving something up with this very simple representation.
There are going to be certain kinds of plans that I might not be able to capture.
For instance, if I have a course discretization where grid cells are relatively big,
and I have a small obstacle spanning several cells.
I'm going to label all those cells as infeasible.
Even though there may be a path that is feasible through those grid cells.
As a designer, when it comes to choosing a search space representation,
you have fundamental decisions to make in terms of how to discretize the world,
what actions are allowed,
and what the costs are that are associated with each action.