Okay, I've said that in our simple grid world example,
a plan is a sequence of states from the start state to the goal state.
How do I build that plan?
The process of building a plan is the essence of the search process.
The way that I'm going to conduct a search is by taking a partial plan,
applying an action, and adding
the resulting state to the end of the previous plan to get a new partial plan.
Let's look at an example.
Imagine that we have a simple 2D grid world
and we have a start state and we have a goal state.
And we start with a very simple initial plan of just being at the start state.
One state sequence is still a sequence.
Now, let's imagine that I only have one possible action which is to move right,
and so I always apply the same action.
I take my initial partial plan of being at the start state,
and I move right and end up here.
That's a new partial plan.
It doesn't get me all the way to the goal but it is a partial plan.
Let's do the same thing over again.
Apply my action, I end up with this state.
Now, I have a new partial plan.
Start, right, right.
I do that a couple more times and I end up with a plan that looks like start state,
right, right, right Goals state.
That's a successful plan.
Now, it's a silly plan because I only ever considered moving right.
And I got lucky that I didn't have to turn or go around any obstacles.
The next thing we want to look at is,
how do we incorporate the other actions that we might need to
take in order to get more complicated plans,
and plans that move around obstacles?