Let's go back to our grid world example where I have my start state and my goal state.
But now, let's put an obstacle right in the middle.
What happens now is that grid cell becomes infeasible.
I have my array in memory of all my grid cells where zeros indicate
freespace and ones are infeasible space and that one cell is now labeled as infeasible,
which means that actions are not allowed to move into that cell.
Let's run the same planning process as before.
I take my initial partial plan, just the start state,
and I apply the action of moving one step to the right and I end up here.
Very good. I have a new partial plan just as I did before,
start state right here.
If I try to apply the same action to move right again
I now run into the obstacle here. What do I do now?
Well, really, what I should be doing is every time I expand a partial plan I should
be expanding all possible actions and expanding any partial plan gives me,
in this 2D example,
as many as four new partial plans because I have
four actions or if there's an obstacle in the way,
I don't get as many.
What I should have done, is it when I tried to expand my partial plan from the start,
is not just create a partial plan for moving right,
but also create partial plans that move left,
move up, move down from start as well.
Then from here, I should have had plans that moved up and
down as well as a plan that tried to move into the obstacle and failed.
Really, what I'm doing is I'm constructing a list of partial plans as I go,
and every time I want to consider a new plan,
I pick one partial plan from my list and I
apply all feasible actions to the last state of that partial plan.
Through that process, I get a new set of
partial plans to add to my list of possible plans.
To explore all possible plans,
I need to be doing this from the very beginning.
And this is really how search works.
I have my initial state,
my start state and I apply all possible actions.
In this case, one that moves left from the start,
one that moves right, one that moves up one that moves down.
I have four partial plans.
I pick one, I expand it,
and repeat the process.
In this case, I get two new partial plans because
moving to the right is infeasible and to the left is where I came from.
Oh, that's one other wrinkle we have to think about.
Notice that if I have a partial path from the start moving right one state,
a perfectly reasonable expansion of that partial path is to then move left.
The plan would be move right,
then move left, taking you back to the start. That's a dumb plan.
And in fact, any plan that returns to a previously visited state is a bad plan.
If every time we find a path to a state we added to a visited list we
can avoid creating new partial plans that are simply different routes to the same state.
Ultimately, I'm generating a list of partial plans that
don't revisit previous locations and don't run into obstacles.