Throughout the process of building out a plan,
I'm maintaining a list of partial plans and
expanding each one of them one by one to update my list.
The thing to think about now is,
which is the best choice for the next partial plan to
expand from the list of partial plans I have so far?
Well, there are a few options here.
If, for example, I prefer shorter plans,
then the best choice is to always expand
the shortest plan that I have so far in my list of partial plans.
The process of always choosing to expand
the shortest partial plan is called Breadth-First Search.
This algorithm has the nice property that it's guaranteed to find
the shortest path from start to goal first before any other paths.
That means that as soon as you find a plan from the start to the goal,
you know you've found the shortest one.
One other wrinkle is that we should modify how our visited list works.
If you think about how Breadth-First Search works,
if we extend a partial path from some state,
it must not only be the lowest cost path on the stack,
but it must also represent the lowest cost path to that state.
We don't actually know which partial path is the lowest cost path to
a state until we take the partial path off the stack ending in that state.
The modification to our visited list is therefore the only label a state as
visited once we pick a partial path off
the stack and create new partial paths from that state.
While Breadth-First Search has this nice property of finding the shortest path,
the downside is that it can end up keeping around an awful lot of
partial plans as it's trying to expand the path away from the start towards the goal.
It can be very intensive in terms of memory or
storage which could be computationally costly too.
Another approach is to simply expand
a partial plan using some action and if that action is successful,
keep applying that action to try to make progress towards the goal.
Kind of like you saw in a previous example when I
kept expanding the plan using just the move right action.
That particular approach is called Depth-First Search.
The problem with Depth-First Search is that while it works really
well if you get lucky and find a good action to keep using,
you never know when you find a successful plan to the goal if
that's the shortest possible plan or the best plan in any sense.
And sometimes, you can be really unlucky and keep
successfully applying an action but not making any progress towards the goal.
What we would like to do is devise a method that's sort of a hybrid of Breadth-First and
Depth-First Search and then takes advantage of the fact that in motion planning problems,
especially for things like flying cars.
We actually have some information about
which direction we need to go in order to make progress towards the goal,
which is to say, we have a map.
And we should be using that knowledge of
our environment in deciding which partial plan to expand next.