Before I can incorporate any guidance about how to make useful progress towards the goal,
I need to add the notion of a cost function to my search process.
Up to this point,
I have assumed that every action had the same cost,
and I've been assuming that the length of
the plan was exactly the same thing as the cost of a plan.
But that might not be the case.
Some actions might actually cost more than others.
For instance, in our grid example,
you've seen plans that consist of motions moving right,
left, up, and down.
But what about diagonal actions?
Well, in the simplest sense,
a diagonal motion on a grid traverses a distance of square root two,
compared to lateral and vertical motions that traverse a distance of one.
We could say that in this case,
diagonal motions have a cost of root two.
With a cost function,
which is really just the cost associated with all the actions and a partial plan,
I can add up these costs and use them as a way to compare different plans.
If my ultimate goal is to find the lowest cost plan as part of a search process,
then instead of expanding the shortest plan or the most recent plan,
I could be thinking about expanding the lowest cost plan.
This particular algorithm is called uniform cost and it's guaranteed
to find the lowest cost plan first as part of the search process.
Next, we'll look at how to incorporate your map
of the environment in guiding the search process.