So, the world is a continuous space.
There's infinitely many places where a drone could be.
And to make this computation interactable what we've done is we've
chop the world into little kind of blocks called a grid.
And then we believe that inside the grid,
the detail doesn't matter, and the we have finally many of these boxes.
Problem with that is for a three dimensional space as big as your city,
you have an awfully many grid blocks to represent.
And that means a lot of storage and lot of computation.
Now, people discritize the space in different ways.
Grid is just one is a uniform discritization,
but sometimes it makes sense to discritize in different means.
For example, you might talk about intersections and road segments.
Those are typically thought as a graph.
A graph is a discritize of space with discrete notes that correspond,
for example, to intersections and discrete arcs in between.
And you might say, "That's crazy for the skyward."
If you fly a viewer plane today in
the United States or anywhere in the world you'll find that the FAA,
the Federal Aviation Authority or whoever it
is has already chopped your sky into a graph.
There is Jet ways and Victor Vaisse and via points and
view hours that define an invisible graph in
our sky and on in which each commercial plane flies.