You've now got a bunch more tools in your kit for
planning but when it comes to executing a plan,
one issue that we've ignored so far is how to execute the plan
smoothly without actually stopping at each waypoint.
At this point, your planning solution looks more or less like this.
You have an environment with some obstacles and a plan consisting of
a set of waypoints and just like in the very first project,
you have a finite state machine that takes you from waypoint to waypoint.
This is a perfectly reasonable starting point but for outdoor flight in the real-world,
your vehicle will be relying on the GPS to track its position in the geodetic frame.
There are a lot of ways in which this position estimate can be imprecise.
The quality of the GPS estimate can be affected by a lot of factors,
such as the quality of electronics,
the local environment, even changes in the atmosphere.
As a result, most hobbyists GPS receivers
are really only accurate to a dozen meters or so,
and the errors in the GPS can change over time.
To your autopilot, GPS errors
are going to make it look like the waypoints are actually moving.
To deal with this issue,
you'll generally have your autopilot setup to get as close
as possible to the commanded waypoint within a certain radius.
For the mavlink autopilot,
this is known as the acceptance radius and is given in meters.
As a natural consequence,
if your acceptance radius is on the same order or smaller,
then the typical GPS errors then as you move from waypoint to waypoint,
the vehicle can spend a lot of time chasing
a waypoint that seems to be jumping around and changing location.
In order to have better control over what it actually means to
arrive at a waypoint and handle noise in your position estimates,
you can introduce something called a deadband,
which is a region of input values.
In this case, GPS measurements of the vehicles
position where the control system will take no action.
For example, you can think of the acceptance radius around each waypoint as a deadband.
Once the vehicle is inside the acceptance radius,
it will take no further control action to try to move closer to the waypoint.
Once your vehicle reaches a deadband, for example,
you can explicitly tell the autopilot to stop
trying to arrive at that waypoint and move on to the next one.
In many cases, you won't want
the same size acceptance radius or deadband for all waypoints.
For instance, you might want to make intermediate waypoints
have wider deadbands where you move onto the next waypoint sooner,
than when you're trying to stop precisely at the goal waypoint.
You could even make your deadbands be a function of velocity.
If you're moving fast, expand the deadbands and only enforce
greater position accuracy when you're moving slowly or attempting to stop.
You can think about ways in which you might modify your state machine to
ensure the right logic of a deadband around each waypoint.
In the next exercise,
you'll get a chance to play with different deadband logic in your project code