In this lesson, you've expanded your set of tools for discretizing your environment.
You've seen how a path that you planned through a grid can be simplified
or condensed into a series of waypoints by finding connections through free space.
You also saw that if you like,
you can toss out the grid-based discretization entirely and directly
construct a graph of nodes connected by edges that represent your search space.
There are tradeoffs, however,
between using grids versus graphs when it comes to solving the planning problem,
and you need to ensure whatever representation you choose,
that it satisfies your requirements for completeness and optimality.
In real-world robotics applications,
there's typically no one right answer for how to represent your planning problem.
And in many cases,
using some combination of grid and graph-based representations
as you did with the medial axis transform can give you the best of both worlds.
So far, we've been working in two dimensions,
but all of these techniques are equally valid in three dimensions.
So that's where we're headed next.