In the previous lesson, we saw how to take a set of obstacles,
and render them into a discrete grid with each cell
marked as feasible or infeasible based on the location of obstacles.
And that labelled grid then became your state space for the planning process.
You've seen that you can use an algorithm like A* to find
a minimum cost sequence or grid cells that
represents the path that you want your vehicle to follow.
Turns out however, that representing a plan is a sequence of
discrete grid cells isn't really the best plan for a vehicle to follow.
Fact, given your autopilot a list of all the grid cells in a path,
it's a bit like someone giving you directions to walk to
the local supermarket by saying something like, "Open the door,
step out of the house by putting your left foot forward,
and do the same with your right foot,
then again with your left foot,
and again with your right."
Rather than just saying, "Head down to the corner.
Make a left, and go up half a block."
In this lesson, the first thing we're going to look at is how to convert your list of
grid cells into a better plan that represents what you actually want the vehicle to do.
After that, we'll look at new ways to discretize
your world that don't rely on a grid representation.
And you'll see that how you choose to represent obstacles and
freespace really has an impact on your ability to find not just collision free plans,
but optimal plans. Let's get started.