Using the techniques presented in previous lessons,
we saw that in a grid world like this,
place an obstacle right here,
you can find a plan that takes the vehicle,
for instance, up and over a sequence of cells and then down.
Now, let's think about what this plan actually means.
If you send this plan,
the sequence of grid cells to the autopilot,
what you're really asking the vehicle to do
this to travel through a sequence of short goals.
So, you're telling the autopilot to go from
the start location up to some intermediate goal and then stop.
The vehicle asked to turn and it goes to the next intermediate goal and stops again,
and it goes to the next cell and stops and then over and stop and then over and stop and
then turn again and go down and then finally arrive at the final goal.
What a cumbersome plan.
Now, the reason that the autopilot is going to
stop in each grid cell is because remember,
the autopilot is just the lizard brain of the vehicle.
What's really happening is that the flight computer is sending
the autopilot the next goal or waypoint one location at a time.
What we really want the vehicle to do in this case is to go up,
then turn and travel a long distance to the next goal,
and then turn and then go down.
We don't really want so much a sequence of grid cells for the vehicle to follow.
What we really want is a sequence of waypoints for the vehicle to travel between,
rather than all of these grid cells.
We'd rather tell the vehicle to travel to one, two,
three waypoints and the autopilot will have
a lot easier time following this plan of
just a few waypoints than the original series of grid cells.
The question that arises then is
how do I take that sequence of grid cells and turn it into a sequence of waypoints?
There's more than one way to go about this,
but next we'll look at a simple test you can use to
remove intermediate grid cells that lie along a line
and find a set of waypoints that approximates
the original plan and still keeps the vehicle safe and collision free.