One method you can employ is to take your original plan of a list of grid cells,
and extract as way points the beginning and end
state of any sequence of states that lie along a straight line.
The sequence of states like this are said to be collinear.
Notice that these states right here collinear.
Which if'd like to do, is put a way point at the beginning of that sequence of states,
and a way point at the end of that sequence.
And the way to do that is take all the states in your plan,
identify each subsequence of collinear states,
and keep just the beginning and end point of each subsequence as way points.
Let's take a closer look at this.
Here I have three points p1, p2, p3.
If these three points are collinear,
then the area of the triangle defined by these three points is zero.
In this case, my triangle has non-zero area.
On the other hand, if I have three points that are collinear like these ones here,
then this triangle has zero area and there's a nice trick from
linear algebra to determine whether the area of a triangle defined by three points is,
in fact, equal to zero.
The way to perform this trick is to take these three points,
and put them into a matrix.
So, let's say that each one of these is x1, y1,
z1, x2, y2, z2,
and x3, y3, z3.
Now, if the determinant of that matrix is equal to zero,
the area of the triangle is zero,
and these three points are collinear.
Another way to look at this is that the rank of this matrix is less than three,
which for linear algebra people makes sense.
Now, that was in three dimensions,
but if you're just working in two dimensions as I've drawn here,
you can just set that z coordinate to one,
and apply the same test.
We can write x1, y1,1,
x2, y2, 1, x3, y3,
1, and again, the determinant of this matrix
is equal to zero when these three points are collinear.
And when you work it out,
the simplified form to evaluate this determinant is going to be equal to x1 times
y2 minus y3 plus x2 times y3 minus y1 plus x3 times y1 minus y2.
And if that quantity is equal to zero,
then these three points are collinear.
You can step through your list of grid cells and evaluate all triplet's of
adjacent points and every time you find
a sequence of three points that collinear according to this equation,
you can simply delete the middle point from the path.
And this particular equation for 2D is very efficient to evaluate.
So, building this step into your planning process will look like this.
First, discretize your world into a grid.
Second, use A* to get a sequence of cells from the start state to the goal state.
Third, test for collinearlity already to see
if you can delete some cells from the initial path.
And as easy as that,
you're left with a reduced path of way points.
Remember our trajectory from the previous example that looks like this.
Our collinearlity test will eliminate that point,
that point, and that point.
Leaving this way point,
this way point, and this way point.
This is a simple method for finding a set of way points that in this case,
exactly approximates your original plan,
but doesn't have the autopilot making the vehicle stop and
start unnecessarily as it travels through the grid.