The collinearity test is one way to identify which cells don't actually need to be
used in order to express the path, but it doesn't necessarily lead to the optimal result.
You saw that one representation of this simple path is to go to here, and here,
and then down to the goal, but you could imagine
an even more efficient approximation of this path.
Which is to go from start,
cut across through here,
and then cut down to the goal.
Now, a collinearity test is not going to tell you that you don't actually
need to go up to this intermediate state here but can cut right across.
But clearly this path here is still very much in
free space and this path here is also in free space.
In order to find line segments that approximate
our original sequence of grid cells and ensure that the path is still in free space,
we'll use a technique called ray tracing.
For this first segment, what we want to do is to determine what grid cells lie on
the line from the start state up to here and are they in free space or collision.
Given two points, for instance P1 and P2,
which cells lie along that line?
Well, if P1 is at location X1,Y1 and P2 is at X2, Y2,
then any point on that line,
y of x is going to be given by Y2 minus Y1 over X2 minus X1 times X plus Y1.
Just the equation of the line.
You can then iterate X from X1 to X2 and evaluate each pair X,
Y of X for collision.
If you'd get from X1 to X2 and every value X,
Y of X is not in collision,
not inside an obstacle,
then you know that the entire line must lie entirely in free space.
You can start with X1,
then X1 plus one, X1 plus two,
all the way to X2 and you can look at
the corresponding Y-values and check to see if each cell is in collision.
And in this case, what you'd see is that when you get to X1 plus two Y of X1 plus two,
right here, you can see you're in collision.
Your ray tracing method will tell you that this line is in collision and you cannot
in fact fly in a straight line from this point here to this point here.