Now, although that ray tracing algorithm works very well,
there is one minor problem which is that,
calculating the y coordinate for any given x is really
a floor operation on y2 minus y1 over x2 minus x1 times x plus y1.
And this term here involves a number of floating point operations,
even if we catch the slope here and just
multiply that single floating point number times the integer x,
that's a floating point multiplication.
And then, we have to take a floor of that in order to
figure out the integer value of y of x,
including the integer coordinates, x and y, in the grid.
And those floating point operations,
the floating point multiplication,
and the truncation in the floor have historically been quite computationally expensive.
A modern CPU, these operations may no longer be
a big deal but on a low-power flight computer,
you typically want to reduce
floating point operations and use integer arithmetic, as much as possible.
The same thing has been true in computer graphics for a long time as well.
And in 1965, Bresenham developed
a much more efficient ray tracing algorithm
that uses only integer addition and subtraction.
The key idea is it will compute an increment for
both x and y as we iterate from x1 to x2.
So, again, if I have a point p1 and a point p2,
I can iterate from x1 to x1 plus one to x1 plus two all the way to x2.
And rather than calculating the value y of x1 plus one,
y of x1 plus two, and so on,
I'm going to store an increment for x and an increment for y,
and I'm going to store whether or not that increment is
above or below the line of y plus 0.5.
So, given the current value x and y and the line slope m,
I'm going to ask the question,
is x1 plus one,
y plus m above x plus one, y plus 0.5?
And the idea is that, if I'm right here at x,y,
and I want to know whether the value of y plus m,
is going to be this here,
the value of y plus m is less than y plus 0.5,
as it is right here, then I will not increment y.
On the other hand, if it's above that value, then I do increment y.
What I need to do is define some terms.
First of all, if y plus m is above y plus 0.5,
then set x equal to x plus one, y equal to y plus one.
Otherwise, set x equal x plus one,
leave y as it is, y equals y.
The idea is that these calculations can be done using integer arithmetic.
This might look like it requires a floating point operation
but if you double all the quantities then everything works out using integers.
This process can be done extremely efficiently
and this entire algorithm is known as Bresenham's algorithm.