It's important to notice that as we're going through this waypoint extraction,
we're doing an awful lot of work in order to get
at a sparse set of waypoints connected by
relatively long distances to get
the vehicle through the free part of the configuration space.
We started in each of the previous cases by discretizing our world into a grid,
but now we're going to look at a different way of
discretizing the world into a graph rather than a grid.
If you're not already familiar with graph representations,
don't worry, they're easy to understand.
In general, you can think of a graph as a collection of what are called nodes.
To form a graph, you'll connect these nodes with lines called edges.
Creating a graph like this is another way of discretizing your environment,
where now the nodes are like grid cell locations or states,
and the edges show where an action connects to states.
Instead of forming a plan that traverses across a grid cell by cell,
you can form a plan that traverses a graph by moving from node to node via edges.
Remember, what you need to solve the planning problem.
You need to define a state space,
a set of actions to move through your state space,
a cost function that captures the cost of each action,
as well as start state and a goal state.
And once you've got all that,
you need some way of searching for the sequence of
actions that take you from start to goal,
you could define a graph through your environment whatever you like.
But in some cases your environment may
feature a sort of natural underlying graph structure.
When you think about it, most urban environments actually have
a set of waypoints already encoded in their layout which is to say,
the road network in any city is effectively
a graph where the roads are edges connecting nodes at each intersection.
The convenient thing about how we've set up the planning problem with A*,
in terms of states and actions that take us from state to state,
is that we really don't care whether it's a grid or a sparse graph.
That means you can very easily take all of
the code that you've written so far in the previous exercises,
and replace the grid based representation with a graph based representation.
What modifications would you need to make to your planner in that case?
Really, the only modification is that when you extend
a partial plan rather than expanding into adjacent grid cells,
you expand to all possible nodes reachable via edges.
If you have a start location and
a goal location and your graph is defined by a road network like this,
then you would extend from the start to these nodes choosing this direction to expand,
then expanding your partial plan again like this and so on until you reach the goal.
You can include a similar heuristic of an estimated distance to
go and your A* algorithm will work more or less unchanged.
A road network is just one example of how
you might discretizing an urban environment into a graph.
But next we'll look at other ways you can think of
implementing a graph based representation of your state space.