At this point, you've solve the planning problem two different ways.
One is by taking the obstacles from a 2D map,
rendering them into a grid,
and then finding a plan extracting waypoints.
And the second method you implemented was to load in the road network,
and use the intersections of the roads as nodes in a graph to find a plan,
and that worked as well.
What's interesting is that the same algorithm, A*,
was able to find paths more or less without modification to the implementation.
One of the nice things about using the road network is that
you can more efficiently find much longer plans.
You also avoided the time and effort of
converting the plan into a set of sparse waypoints.
A road network allows you to make a graph quite easily.
But for flying cars or for any flying robot for that matter,
there's really no need to restrict yourself to roads.
And you can be more creative in thinking about how to assemble a state space graph.
In constructing a graph,
there are a few questions you'd like to consider.
One question that arises is, does the planner complete?
Meaning that if a viable plan exists,
is your planner guaranteed to find it?
Another question to ask would be, is the planner optimal?
Meaning that if you find a plan,
do you have any guarantee that it's the best plan or at least close to an optimal plan?
In using a road network as a graph to plan for a flying car,
you can see that it's entirely possible that
your planner will be neither complete nor optimal.
In fact, the specific representation of your planning problem affects the answer to
these questions much more than the algorithm you use to actually solve the problem.
For example, grids are useful because they preserve the entire geometry of the problem.
If there is a feasible path,
then the plan can be expressed by the grid up to the limits of the grid resolution.
In terms of optimality,
the lowest cost path through a grid is typically going to be pretty
close to the true lowest cost path that the vehicle could fly,
again, limited by the resolution of the grid.
So, modulo resolution limits, a grid-based representation,
is going to be both complete and optimal
because it's expressing the geometry of the problem.
It's expressing where obstacles are,
and giving you the best understanding of what the possible plans are.
The trade-off is that grids are computationally expensive.
Just representing the grid alone grows
exponentially with the number of state variables that you have to keep track of.
As you go from 2D to 3D,
and eventually adding even more dimensions to incorporate
the orientation of the vehicle into the representation of states,
the complexity of the planning problem will grow exponentially.
And what's worse is,
search through a grid is exponential in the length of the plan.
And the length of the plan is going to grow with the resolution.
That means that although grids capture the free part of
the configuration space, they are expensive.
Graphs on the other hand, like that of the road network,
let us represent the topology of the space.
What that funny word means is,
how different states in the space are connected
regardless of the distances involved and the geometry of the space.
We can actually set up a spectrum with grids at one end.
And at the far end of the spectrum away from grids,
we can have totally non-geometric
graphs that only capture which parts of the space are connected.
Such graphs may not capture distances or angles.
But really, if we have a set of states and edges,
that guarantee that you can get from one state to the other.
Then the nice thing about these graphs is they
don't get more complex as we add more dimensions,
like orientation, to the state space.
If we're using these kinds of graphs and as we go from 2D to 3D and at orientation,
we're not going to necessarily incur any additional computational complexity.
Furthermore, a single edge in a non-metric graph can be arbitrarily long,
unlike grids where the length scale of the plan and
the total distances involved really affect the complexity of the search.
If you have a plan that's one edge long and that edge is arbitrarily long,
then that's going to be a very easy planning problem to solve.
And furthermore, with a graph,
the computational complexity of the search process is independent of scale.
The downside to graphs is that you're at
the mercy of how well you chose the nodes or way points.
If you pick way points badly,
and no path through the graph actually gets you from the start to the goal,
then you'll never find a plan even if a feasible plan exists.
So, that's a problem in terms of completeness.
And even if we guarantee completeness,
somehow it might be the case that any path
through the graph is arbitrarily far from the optimal plan.
There are intermediate graph representations that
actually capture distances and locations,
and these typically tend to be the most useful ones in
that a search through a metric graph can be computationally efficient,
but also contain properties that correspond to optimality and completeness.
Then we're going to look at a couple of these next.