One of the most well-known techniques for extracting a graph that is
kind of like a roadmap through an environment is what's known as the Voronoi diagram.
In its most basic form,
the Voronoi diagram is a graph that breaks up a space into regions around a set of
seed points so that all the points in
a given region are closer to the same seed point than any other seed.
That might seem pretty esoteric,
but let's imagine that we have a set of points that represent the location of obstacles.
The Voronoi diagram then partitions the space into regions or
Voronoi cells where all the locations within
a given cell are closest to exactly one seed or one obstacle.
In other words, in this case,
where each seed point represents an obstacle,
then the Voronoi cell around each obstacle would contain
all locations that are closest to it. Let's draw this out once.
If these points represent my obstacles,
then I partition the space to look like this.
All locations in this region here are closest to this obstacle.
Similarly, all locations in this region here are closest to this obstacle.
The useful thing for us is actually the boundaries of the Voronoi cells.
The boundaries constitute lines that are equidistant from a pair of obstacles.
You can imagine using the Voronoi graph for planning where
the cell boundaries constitute edges in the graph that you can travel along.
And where these edges meet are the nodes
or waypoints that the vehicle could be traveling to.
And you could now perform search through this Voronoi graph in order to find
a collision-free path from some start location to a goal location.
What's really compelling about Voronoi graphs for things like
flying cars is that these edges represent,
in some sense, the safest path,
the one that is maximally far from obstacles.
But, one of the challenges of using Voronoi graphs
in the real world is that we don't have point obstacles.
We have polygons or polyhedra.
And so, the exact construction of a Voronoi graph around obstacles is non-trivial.
Although the Voronoi diagram is easy to understand but hard to compute,
it's a specific form of a more general idea called the medial axis,
which is actually easier for us to compute given
the kinds of maps that we typically have for navigation.
The medial axis method uses the same intuition that a good graph for
navigation is one where the middle of the quarter
between obstacles is a good place to put edges.
With the medial axis transform,
you'll get something that looks basically like a Voronoi graph and
then naturally encodes safety in the construction of the graph.
Here's a scenario where I have an environment including some obstacles.
And I'll start again with a grid-based discretization that
encodes each cell as being feasible or infeasible.
The way the medial access transform works is that you
start in the free space adjacent to obstacles and
iteratively step away from the obstacles until you
find cells that are equidistant from two different obstacles.
Once you have explored the entire grid,
you've identified all cells that lie along the medial axis between obstacles.
Then, using present hand or another tracing method,
you can condense the list of cells representing
the medial axis into a graph of waypoints and edges.
Both the Voronoi graph and the medial access
transform our classic algorithms with a wide range of applications.
In the next set of exercises,
you'll get a chance to construct Voronoi graphs and perform a medial axis transform.