Welcome back. In this lesson,
we're going to analyze a longitudinal motion of fixed-wing vehicles.
We're going to start by using the equations we developed in the last lesson,
to write down the non-linear equations of motion
for the longitudinal motion of a fixed-wing vehicle.
These non-linear equations will be really
useful when we're trying to simulate fixed-wing flight,
but not as useful for actually analyzing an aircraft's actual motion.
To do useful mathematical analysis of fixed-wing flight,
we'll need to first linearize the equations of motion around a trim state.
Once we have a linear model,
we'll use some of the tools of linear algebra to answer
some important questions about the motion and stability of fixed-wing vehicles.