We begin this lesson by looking at
the nonlinear equations of motion for the longitudinal dynamics of a fixed-wing vehicle,
and we use these equations to simulate the state of a vehicle forward in time.
When the aircraft is in initial state that's close
to but not exactly equal to a trim state,
you saw that its motion does some surprising things.
We wanted to know where this weird behavior came from,
but realized we couldn't really do much to analyze the nonlinear equations of motion.
So, we linearized the dynamics around the trim state and
found that the eigenvalues told us a lot about the motion of the vehicle.
In particular, we found
four interesting eigenvalues which came as two complex conjugate pairs.
Both of these pairs had negative real parts which meant that they were stable,
but their non-zero imaginary parts meant that they were also oscillatory.
These motion modes are well-known phenomena.
We call the faster mode the short-period response,
and the slower mode is called phugoid.
Trying to fight these natural modes of motion can be tricky,
and you'll learn more about fixed-wing control and autopilots after the next lesson.
In the next lesson, we'll analyze a lateral directional dynamics of
a fixed-wing vehicle using a similar approach to what we used here.