The first step in building our nonlinear longitudinal model,
is to identify what quantities we need to track.
For now, we're going to take this to be our state vector.
Here, we have the x and z coordinates of the vehicle, in the inertial frame.
Note that, for this lesson,
z is positive upwards to make the math a bit more consistent with some other references.
Theta is the pitch angle.
U and W give the x,
z velocity in the body frame,
and Q is the pitch rate in the body frame.
This is the same Q from the PQ and R body rates you've worked with earlier.
Now, I'd like to quickly derive the equations of motion for the vehicle in two steps.
First, we'll consider motion with no forces,
and then we'll consider motion with forces.
Defining the equations of motion means,
figuring out how all the state variables change with time.
The x and z derivatives give the velocity in the initial frame. They look like this.
They are just the velocity in the body frame,
rotated by the pitch angle.
Theta dot is just the pitch rate Q.
The last three derivatives look like this.
Q dot is zero,
because there are no moments on the vehicle for now.
Since there are no forces,
you might expect U and W dot to be zero.
But if the vehicle is moving in the inertial frame with some velocity as it rotates,
then the body frame velocities will not be the same from time-step to time-step.