We have these equations of motion for force-free motion.
Now, we can incorporate the forces and the pitching moment from the previous lesson.
Since forces and moments influence accelerations and rotational accelerations,
these first three equations will not be changed.
Of these last three equations,
q-dot is the easiest.
It will just be equal to the pitching moment divided by
the moment of inertia about the y-axis.
We're going to handle u-dot and w-dot similarly.
Remember that these give the x and z acceleration of the vehicle in the body frame.
What we're going to do is write the accelerations like this.
We've just added the contributions from Fx and Fz,
which represent the total force on the vehicle in its body frame.
To figure out what these forces are,
we can imagine a vehicle with some pitch angle,
Theta, and angle of attack, Alpha.
Thrust is aligned to the body frame,
weight points down in the inertial frame,
which means it's rotated from the body frame by Theta,
and the aerodynamic forces of lift and drag are aligned to the stability frame.
So, they're rotated by Alpha.
If we look at the x component of these forces,
we find that Fx looks like this.
If we look at the z component of these forces,
we find that Fz looks like this.
The lift and drag forces, L and D,
and the pitching moment, M,
are all exactly as we define them in the last lesson.
Remember, we have two longitudinal control terms for the elevator deflection and thrust.
You don't see them in these equations because their effect
is buried in the specific equations for L,
D, and M. Remember that lift goes away when we exceed the stall angle of attack.
These equations all assume we have laminar flow over the wing.
In the next exercise,
we'll provide you with a longitudinal model
for a vehicle that we've implemented in Python.
You'll play around with this model by forward simulating
the state of the vehicle when it starts near trim state.
The behavior you see might surprise you.
Take some time to make sure you're comfortable with
these equations before moving on to the next exercise.