In the previous exercise,
you simulated the longitudinal motion of a vehicle,
with an initial state that's very close to a trim state.
When you plotted the pitch rate of that vehicle versus time,
you saw a graph that looked like this.
This graph seems pretty strange,
and you might have some questions about it.
After all, if we are near an equilibrium state,
where the pitching moment is zero,
why are we seeing this strange oscillation?
If we were to build the aircraft that we modeled and actually fly it,
would we see this behavior?
Or, maybe what we're seeing is an artifact of
the discretization that we had to do to simulate this motion on a computer.
Or, if this oscillation is real,
then we'd like to know more about it.
For example, will these oscillations go away?
If so, how long will it take?
Can we design our vehicle in a way that minimizes these oscillations?
We'd like to answer all of these questions.
Unfortunately, with the equations written as they are,
we just don't have the mathematical tools necessary to analyze this motion rigorously.
It's hard to get the non-linear equations underlying
the dynamics of this vehicle to explain what is going on.
So, as you've seen a few times in this nanodegree program,
we're going to want to turn our non-linear model into a linear model,
so we can actually analyze these dynamics and answer these questions.