By the end of this lesson,
you'll be able to use a linear model of
the longitudinal dynamics of a vehicle to actually answer the questions we just asked.
The analytical techniques you're going to use are pretty
straightforward but the math underlying them is not so simple.
For the next part of this lesson,
I want to give you some intuitive sense for
how that math works without going too deep into the details.
Let me sketch out the plan for the rest of this lesson.
First, I'm going to show you
a linearized version of the equations of motion you saw earlier.
This linearized version will represent the dynamics of the system near
a trim state as x dot equals AX plus BU.
This might look similar to
the state-transition function you saw when learning about common filters.
Next, we're going to focus on this square A matrix,
which is called the stability matrix,
and I'm going to explain how we can decompose
this matrix into eigenvalues and eigenvectors.
This decomposition will allow us to identify modes in the motion.
These modes will have a term that looks something like E raised to
the A plus BI times T. This A plus BI is called a complex number.
After that, you'll see how the exponential of a complex number actually leads to motion,
which is a combination of oscillation with exponential growth or decay.
Finally, we'll put this altogether and
actually answer some of the questions we just asked.