The nonlinear equations that we came up with earlier looked like this.
If we want to write them more succinctly,
we can gather all of these variables into a vector called x-dot,
and write x-dot equals some function of the state vector x and the control input u.
We want the linearize model around some trim state,
I'm going to call this state x-star.
The controls necessary to maintain this state, I'll call u-star.
Then, we can define deviations from equilibrium as x-bar and u-bar.
So, x-bar is just the actual state x minus the trim state x-star.
U-bar is the actual controls minus the controls of trim.
This means we can define the equations of motion around trim by finding x-bar-dot,
which is just x-dot minus x-star-dot.
When you go through the math of linearizing this system,
which will present in text below this video,
you'll find that x-bar-dot is approximated by
Jacobian times the deviation of the state from equilibrium,
plus another Jacobian times the deviation of the controls.
You might remember doing exactly this in building
the process model for the extended Kalman filter in the estimation module.
These Jacobians are just matrices,
which means we can write the dynamics model as
a linear system around the trim state and trim controls,
where x-bar-dot equals A times x-bar plus B times u-bar.
We call this A matrix the stability matrix,
and we call B the control effect matrix.
Now, remember what x-bar and u-bar represent?
They are the deviation of state from trim and the deviation of the controls from trim.
When you saw the strange plots earlier in the lesson,
we weren't changing the controls from their trim values at all.
So, the deviation would have been zero.
This whole B times u term wouldn't have contributed to the dynamics at all.
So, the dynamics are even simpler.
We just have the stability matrix times the deviation of the state from trim.
We found this matrix by taking the partial derivatives of
the six state transition functions with respect to the six state variables.
So, it's a six by six square matrix.
This square matrix is really what we need to analyze in order
to understand the strange plots we saw earlier.