We need to analyze the square stability matrix to understand the motion near trim.
To do this analysis,
we're going to need to remind ourselves of what eigenvectors and eigenvalues are.
Any square matrix can be represented as a product of three matrices like this.
This uppercase Lambda is a diagonal matrix with
numbers along the diagonal and zeros everywhere else.
This V matrix is a matrix of column vectors,
where each column can be associated with one of the numbers in Lambda.
We label each of the numbers in this uppercase Lambda matrix with a lowercase Lambda.
So we have Lambda one, Lambda two,
and so on, and these Lambdas are the eigenvalues of our original matrix.
If we have some eigenvalue Lambda i,
the corresponding column vector Vi is called an eigenvector.
These eigenvalues and eigenvectors have interesting properties.
For example, if the initial state of the system is some eigenvector Vi,
then A times V i will be equal to Lambda i times vi,
and the motion as a function of time will be given by x of t is equal
to e to Lambda i times t times the eigenvector Vi.
It isn't essential that you understand all the math behind this equation.
The important thing to note is that we now have
an actual equation for the state as a function of time.
This means that if we know the initial state of the system,
we can actually predict the state of the system at
any time in the future using just this equation in a single step.
That was something we couldn't do with the nonlinear equations.
With those equations, we had to actually simulate the dynamics at each time step.
So, let's look at this equation and focus on this e to the Lambda t term.
One thing I didn't mention about
these eigenvalues is that they are actually complex numbers.
A complex number can be written as a plus bi.
This i is the imaginary number defined as the square root of minus one.
You might also see it written as j.
So when we take e to the Lambda times t,
we are really taking e to the a plus bi times t,
and this complex exponential has some interesting properties that you'll explore now.