The eigenvectors of the stability matrix describe the "modes" of the system.
So, if the initial state of the system has some eigenvector Vi,
then the motion will be along the line spanned by Vi,
and the motion as a function of time looks like this.
The Lambda i in this equation is just the eigenvalue associated with the eigenvector Vi.
When we analyze this stability matrix,
we're often analyzing these eigenvalues since
this complex exponential e to
the Lambda it actually tells us a lot about the motion of the vehicle.
As you just saw, this Lambda will,
in general, be a complex number,
a plus b times i.
This a is referred to as the real part of the eigenvalue and the b is the imaginary part.
A complex exponential describes motion that is some combination of
oscillation along with exponential growth or decay.
When the real part of the eigenvalue is negative,
the motion for the corresponding mode will be stable.
Which means that when the system is perturbed from the trim state,
it will eventually return to the trim state.
When the real part of the eigenvalue is positive,
the motion for the corresponding mode is unstable.
Which means that small deviations from trim will tend to grow with time.
So, when the real parts of all of the eigenvalues are negative,
the system will be stable overall.
For a flying vehicle,
this means that the aircraft will always
want to return to trim after it's been disturbed.
For example, by a gust of wind.