At this point, we can actually explain
the strange motion that we saw earlier in this lesson.
The graph we saw for pitch rate versus time looks something like this.
And remember, we generated this graph by putting the vehicle into a near trim state,
and then simulating the motion using unknown linear dynamics model.
We can explain this motion as the combination of
two decaying exponentials with oscillations.
One has a long period,
it decays somewhat slowly,
and the other has a much shorter period and decays much more quickly.
In fact, this behavior is a real thing and well-known in fixed-wing aircraft design.
When you take the eigenvalues of the stability matrix for a realistic aircraft,
you will get six eigenvalues.
Two of them will be equal to zero,
these just correspond to horizontal and vertical displacement of the aircraft.
The remaining four eigenvalues comes two conjugate pairs of complex numbers.
One pair of eigenvalues corresponds to
this short period motion and is typically called a short period response.
It's a transient oscillation and very quickly
dies out as the aircraft returns to the trim state.
The other pair of eigenvalues corresponds to this slower and longer term oscillation,
this motion is called phugoid.
On aircraft that carry passengers,
this phugoid can feel like a gentle rolling motion.
Ideally, the aircraft will be designed to minimize the amplitude of phugoid,
but it can occur when moving from trim state to trim state.
When working with real aircraft,
it's important to recognize phugoid and understand what's happening.
For example, adding control inputs to counteract the phugoid motion directly can
sometimes make things worse in a process known as pilot induced oscillation.