In most of our planning so far,
we have assumed that the map is
a perfect model of the environment the vehicle is flying in.
But of course, we said a few times that that is
a risky assumption not suitable for real-world applications.
The obstacles in the environment can change for any number of reasons.
Buildings get put up or taken down all the time,
trees grow, there may be things moving around like other flying cars.
Assuming that you have some sensor onboard to
measure the position of obstacles in the local 3D environment,
this could be a lidar,
or depth camera for example,
one thing you could do is continually update
the local map in your receding horizon planner and replan with each update.
But replaning can take some time,
and full replanning may not always be necessary.
Nearly always, even with unexpected obstacles,
the original plan is close to correct.
The appearance of an unexpected obstacle may
require just a local perturbation to the original plan,
to dodge around the unexpected tree or flying car.
There is an efficient way to think about obstacles,
that makes it easy to dodge around them without having to
incur the full cost of replanning.
Let's assume, we have our original plan as a set of waypoints.
You can then think of the next waypoint as
the potential field exerting an attractive force on the vehicle,
essentially pulling the vehicle downhill toward it.
Let's set that potential to be a quadratic function of the distance to the goal,
so that the attractive potential is some factor
alpha times one half times the distance to the goal squared.
That defines a quadratic potential surface like the one shown here.
And whenever we think about moving around in a potential,
what that potential does is exert a force which is the derivative of the potential.
Which in this case, is the derivative of alpha times one half,
times the distance squared,
or simply alpha times the distance to the goal.
The alpha term is just some constant we can choose to
control how strong the pull of the goal is.
We can also think of each obstacle point as
exerting a repulsive force in the flight vehicle,
pushing the vehicle away from the obstacle.
In order to make this a repulsive potential,
we'll have it depend on the inverse of the distance to the obstacle,
and we'll define a distance Q_max beyond which will set the obstacle potential to zero.
Meaning that if you steer well clear of obstacles,
you don't feel the potential.
Again, the force exerted by obstacles is just the derivative of the potential,
and now beta is a constant you can use to set the strength of the obstacle potential.
If you now add up the attractive and repulsive forces,
you get a net force vector that always
pushes the vehicle towards the goal and away from obstacles.
Remember, this isn't a true force like wind or gravity.
But if you tell the autopilot to steer toward the direction of this force vector,
the vehicle will make progress toward the goal while dodging obstacles.
If you think of the vehicles eventual path
as the integral of the forces at each time instant,
then you'll recognize that the forces are a source of potential energy and,
this technique is known as potential field motion planning.
It's a really old idea,
but was originally invented for cruise missiles traveling at high speed
that needed to plan motions to avoid obstacles very quickly.
It's a great way for any fast-moving flight vehicle to
efficiently plan to dodge obstacles. There is one wrinkle.
Like any energy potential field,
the motion planning potential field can have local minimum.
Places, where the notional force vectors all cancel each other out,
leaving the vehicle motionless.
In these cases, there's nothing the vehicle can do except stop forward motion,
and do a full replan. So part of
potential field planning is being careful to check for local minimum.
In the next exercise,
you'll get a chance to try this out for yourself,
when you implement your own potential field motion planner.