What you've seen over the course of the last few lessons is that really,
there could be as many as three stages of planning.
There is a proximate global planning that takes into account
the full length scale of where the vehicle needs to go in order to complete its mission.
This stage will include some approximate model of the obstacles and
free space which could be a 2D or 3D or even two and a half D map.
A good global planning strategy might feature a global plan in 2D,
but along the way,
you can have a receding horizon 3D planner or second planner.
With this second planner, you're attempting to follow
the rough outline of the global plan but at the same time,
avoiding local obstacles and responding to the unexpected.
Beyond that, you can implement the third potential field planner for
local obstacle void at high speed
including known obstacles and things that are not already in the map.
By combining all three of these planning layers,
you'll have the ability to implement different kinds of planners all working together
with each one offering different trade-offs in terms of planning efficiency,
response time, complexity, and how much information is available ahead of
time which will give your vehicle maximum flexibility and maximum reliability.