With the exercises you've completed in the previous lessons,
you're ready to tackle the final 3D motion planning project.
If you're ready to dive in and complete the project,
just go ahead and skip to
the next lesson where you will find instructions for getting started.
In this lesson, I'll present
some more advanced methods to take your project implementation above and beyond.
But feel free to skip ahead or just come back to it later when you have some time.
Okay, you're still here I see.
Well then, let's get right into it.
In most of the lessons so far,
we have assumed an idealized version of reality in physics.
We have assumed the vehicle knows exactly where it is in the world.
We have assumed the vehicle knows exactly where
every obstacle is in the world ahead of time,
and we've assumed that the vehicle was able
to follow a trajectory through the world perfectly.
We've also assumed that as long as a path exists through
free space that we can command the vehicle to follow that path.
In the real world,
all of these assumptions break down.
The information available in a map ahead of time is usually imperfect.
And we've talked a little bit about what to do when obstacles
appear or are missing from the map at the time of flight.
Sensor measurements like GPS have inherent errors.
We talked about what to do when
environmental conditions can make following a trajectory challenging.
A final issue is that all vehicles have constraints on
how they can move and you need to include those constraints in your planning solution.
So, in this lesson, we'll touch on a couple
more of these elements of real world planning so that
you have the tools you need to take
your project implementation to the next level and deploy it on real hardware.