Restrictions on the states that a vehicle can
physically be in are called kinematic constraints.
In other words, these are constraints on motion that aren't a result of force or mass.
Kinematic constraints are generally,
a function of geometry and for flying cars,
they arise primarily as a result of the distribution of obstacles in the environment.
You can think of the kinematic constraints as defining the boundary
between the feasible and infeasible parts of your configuration space.
Any feasible motion plan must satisfy the kinematic constraints.
There are, however, other constraints on motion that can arise from
how a vehicle can move through space or what maneuvers it can perform.
A quadrotor is a pretty amazing vehicle in that it can
more or less move in any direction, regardless of orientation.
A car on the other hand does have a set of constraints on allowable motion.
Still ignoring properties such as mass or the forces acting on the vehicles,
cars or at least most cars,
cannot move in arbitrary directions.
Cars are restricted to forward and backwards motion along
a line or an arc defined by the steering angle of the wheels.
The constraints induced by your car steering mechanism
restrict the allowable changes to the state in configuration space.
So, for example, just because your car is sitting next to an open parking spot,
doesn't mean the parking problem is easy.
If you don't consider restrictions on steering,
then your motion planner might think that an action to the right like
this is perfectly feasible in terms of the kinematic constraints of the environment.
But in this case,
it's the constraints on what your car can do in terms of
the allowable motion that makes this problem hard.
It's really about restrictions on how the vehicle is allowed to change its state.
These restrictions are called differential constraints,
and as the name suggests,
these are constraints on the derivative of the state.
So far, we have ignored differential constraints in our planning algorithms.
We assumed that as long as a straight line exists
between two states through the free part of the configuration space,
that it's feasible to include a motion between those states as part of the plan.
It turns out that's actually a pretty reasonable assumption for a slow moving quadrotor.
A vehicle of no differential constraints of any kind is called a holonomic vehicle.
The fact that all vehicles have mass,
implies that there is always a constraint on how
fast a vehicle can accelerate or decelerate.
But for vehicles like quadrotors,
we can often ignore these kinds of constraints.
Vehicles that seem to have
no different constraints like quadrotors are called quasi-holonomic.
And for these types of vehicles,
solving the planning problem is often quite easy.
But for vehicles that aren't Quasi-Holonomic,
you need to think about allowable motions as part of the planning problem.
When your quadrotor is moving at a significant velocity,
you can no longer treat it as a Quasi-Holonomic vehicle.
And next, we'll look at how to include its dynamics in your planning solution.