In solving the planning problem,
we've ignored the mass of the vehicle,
and force is acting on it like gravity.
But when you include forces and mass in your planning problem,
even when there aren't a lot of obstacles
around with complicated passages to fly through,
you still need to think about issues like planning to fly slowly enough,
that you have sufficient room to stop when you get close to an obstacle or waypoint.
Remember, that the attitude of the vehicle directs the thrust vector.
And so, you have to think about how quickly you can rotate
the vehicle to accelerate or decelerate.
The constraints on a vehicle's motion that result from
the vehicle's mass and forces acting on it are known as dynamic constraints.
And dynamic constraints generally,
show up as a form of differential constraint.
While there may be other differential constraints related to how the vehicle moves,
like the steering mechanism on a car for example, in this lesson,
we're going to look at how to find plans for
vehicles that have differential constraints of all kinds.
The first thing you need to work out is how to specify differential constraints.
In some cases, it's easy.
For example, imagine a vehicle flying in
a strong prevailing wind blowing in the positive x direction.
If your constraint is that you must be able to tolerate any crosswind velocity,
but you can never fly upwind,
then this constraint can be written as a derivative on x is greater than zero.
Now, for a flying car,
you might also have acceleration constraints,
which are constraints on how quickly you can accelerate or decelerate.
Acceleration constraints are a function of the second derivative of the state.
A common form of differential constraint is what's called the vehicle model.
The vehicle model addresses questions like,
"What motion is the vehicle capable of given its current state?
How do you specify the possible trajectories
the vehicle can take from its current state?"
This is usually written as a differential equation or set of equations.
For instance, suppose you have a vehicle that is
constrained to fly in a counterclockwise motion in a circle.
We can write a model for this as x-dot is equal to minus y and y-dot is equal to x.
In this case, the vehicle is constrained to fly in
a circle of unit radius centered at the origin.
This model says that the vehicle motion has to always be tangent to the circle.
These sorts of equations are often how we specify how a flight vehicle is able to move.
A challenge with specifying the motion of the vehicle this way is that you can no
longer do simple line drawing to check
whether a path between two states is in free space.
You have to integrate the model forward to know what the path is going to look like.
Integration can be complicated,
especially for nonlinear dynamics models like this.
If you're lucky, you can solve
the differential equations explicitly for the state at any time t,
but if not, you have to use a numerical integration scheme.
The simplest integration scheme is to assume a linear approximation,
so that you can write this dynamics model as a set of difference equations,
such as xt plus one is equal to xt plus yt, delta-t.
In this case, you have to pick some value of delta-t.
The larger the value you pick for delta-t,
the worse your linear approximation is going to be for nonlinear systems.
So, for this model constraining the vehicle to fly in a circle,
the linear approximation would look like a series of straight line segments like this.
Similarly, yt is equal to yt plus xt
times delta-t. Small values of delta-t are going to be a better approximation again,
but more computationally demanding.
Large values of delta-t are easier to simulate,
but a worse approximation.
To apply this approximation,
you would need to iterate on xt and yt from say,
zero to some point in the future.
In the next exercise, you'll get a chance to implement
an integration scheme for a dynamics model using the linear approximation.