The dynamics models that we've talked about so far
have constraints that involve just the current state.
But remember, we have an autopilot that
allows us to control the motion of the vehicle so it
also makes sense to incorporate the control into the differential constraints as well.
Very common dynamics model is what's known as
the Dubin's car has a state X, Y, and theta.
And it has the following dynamics model which is that
X_dot is equal to the cosine of the current orientation,
Y_dot is the sine of the current orientation.
And we also assume that we have the ability to
steer the vehicle so we have a steering angle.
U_phi, and we're going to use U in
general to denote controls that we're giving to the vehicle.
So we say U_phi to specify that as the steering angle phi of the wheels.
The change in orientation of the vehicle is the tangent of the steering angle.
And presumably, we also have a constraint on the control.
Let's say the steering angle is limited to be
in the range minus pi over two to pi over two.
So, minus 90 to 90 degrees.
Implicit in this is an assumption that the vehicle is moving at
a fixed velocity of one meter per second in a forward direction.
This dynamics model is what's called the Dubin's car and there are different variants of
the model that allow the forward velocity to vary or allow backwards motion as well.
The Dubin's car is particularly relevant in the flying car domain,
because it's a pretty good model for fixed wing aircraft.
There's an easy way to convert the steering angle in the model into
a flight path angle and bank angle commands that you
would normally give to a fixed wing autopilot.
For our purposes in the upcoming project,
the Dubin's car model is not a particularly great representation of
true quadrotor dynamics to exactly follow a curve trajectory.
The autopilot for quadrotor,
unlike a fixed wing aircraft,
would have to constantly adjust the thrust vector through the curve.
Unlike a fixed wing vehicle,
there isn't a single setting of the controls that will make
the quadrotor follow a curved path described by a specific steering angle.
That being said, unless the quadrotor stops at each waypoint,
the inertia of the vehicle is going to cause it to follow
some curved path as it changes direction and moves through a waypoint.
If the plan looks like this,
the quadrotor is not actually going to follow this exact trajectory,
unless it stops at that waypoint.
As the vehicle adjusts the thrust of individual motors in
order to change the thrust vector from heading in this direction,
to heading in this direction,
what's actually going to happen is that
the quadrotor is going to either follow a curved path,
it looks like that, or maybe it starts adjusting it's heading
direction earlier and it will follow a curve path that looks more like that.
This is just a function of the inertia.
While the Dubin's car model isn't really the ideal model for quadrotor motion,
physics tells us that a vehicle with inertia
is going to follow a curve path of some form.
Let's just assume for now that our quadrotor autopilot gives us the ability to follow
a specific curve path and thus the Dubin's car model
can serve as a reasonable vehicle model that we can incorporate into our plan.