In the last exercise,
you wrote a method called simulate that allows you to
predict where the vehicle will end up given an initial state,
and some controls, steering angle, and velocity.
The next thing to do is to actually incorporate this into your planner.
As you moved from 2D to 3D,
you saw that a discrete grid would be unwieldy,
and we switched to graph-based methods,
like the probabilistic roadmap.
The way the probabilistic roadmap worked is that we assumed that we
could get from any state to any other state along a straight line,
so long as obstacles weren't in the way.
That is, given sample states X1 and X2,
we can draw an edge, and decide that the edge
is valid if no kinematic constraint is violated.
In doing this, we ignored orientation, velocity,
inertia, and even what the controls needed to be in order to make that edge happen.
Now, because we have more complicated differential constraints,
to see if you can add an edge between two states,
you need to know what controls can get you from X1 to X2.
Or in other words, you need to know
what setting of the velocity and steering angle you need.
So, let's say that the curve trajectory you want to follow looks like this.
Not only do you need to know what controls will get you from X1 to X2,
but also whether any obstacles,
any kinematic constraints are violated along that trajectory.
How do we solve for the controls?
Given a pair of states X1 and X2,
solving for the control that gives the solution to get from X1 to X2 is, in general,
a two-point boundary value problem in differential equations,
and can be very difficult to solve for a lot of real systems.
There may even be multiple solutions,
some of which are collision-free, and some of which are not.
Instead of trying to solve the boundary value problem,
which can be as hard as the original planning problem itself,
let's do what seems like a crazy thing and just guess at a set of controls,
and see how close we get to X2.
We'll call this process of guessing
a control sequence to get from X1 to X2, the steer function.
Given X1 and some X2,
we'll guess U_s and U_phi and see where we end up.