You now have a steer function that,
given some start state X1 and some destination state X2,
allows you to randomly guess a set of controls that will try to make progress towards X2.
I use the word "try" loosely. How do we use this?
Well, you're trying to answer the question of,
"Does there exist a set of controls that will get us from X1 to X2?"
And the steer function puts you at some point, for example, here.
If you're actually randomly sampling controls,
most of the time you'll end up with controls that will
not give you an edge from X1 all the way to X2,
but you will find an edge from X1 to some sample state that I'll call "X_new",
and you determine X_new by using
the simulate function to propagate the controls U-s and U-phi from X1.
To build a graph with this method,
rather than worrying about actually arriving at X2,
let's just throw away X2 and keep X_new.
Now you actually have a pair of states with an edge
between them and are labeled with the control.
So great, you have an edge in your graph.
The way that the probabilistic road map algorithm worked was by
sampling all the states first and then drawing edges between them.
In this case, you're not actually going to be able
to build a graph in two separate steps like that,
so let's do this iteratively.
Let's combine both the state sampling and edge creation.
The algorithm looks like this: sample state,
try to generate controls that'll steer towards that state,
simulate your X_new, and then add X_new to the graph along with
U_s and U_phi and discard the original sample state, then iterate.
This algorithm is what's known as the Rapidly-Exploring Random Tree or RRT.
The reason it's a tree,
as opposed to a graph,
is that it's not always the case that these edges are reversible.
If you're at X1 and you can get to X_new,
that does not necessarily mean that you know how to get from X_new back to X1.
Differential constraints may mean that those edges are not reversible.
It is very much a tree.
In the next exercise,
you'll get a chance to implement RRT and
generate a tree representation of your state-space.