At this point, you may have noticed that your steer function is really rather naive,
just randomly sampling controls,
and then this has a significant impact on how
well your tree makes progress from the start to the goal.
Again, in general, solving for the controls that will allow
you to find an edge between any pair of states is a hard problem.
But for this specific dynamics model,
it turns out you can be a fair bit smarter about
how you choose controls to get from X1 to X2.
You can use geometry to see if the sample point X2 is within
the reachable half circle from the nearest point in the current tree, X_near.
You can solve for these three angles exactly.
This is not quite a half circle,
but all of the points in this area form the set of
feasible points reachable by the Dubin's car model,
with our max horizon t as a function of the maximum velocity,
and the horizon t. Any point that lies inside this region here,
is reachable with a single setting of controls.
And we can solve for those.
If X2 is not in the reachable half circle,
we can choose the max.
The point that's either going to lie on this side,
so that X2 lines up over here, or on this side.
Then we want to set the steering angle in this direction,
so it lies over here,
or set the steering angle in this direction,
so we make progress towards here.
And we can actually modify our steer function to
return a maximum value for the steering angle,
to make progress towards this half plane or this half plane.
In the next exercise,
you'll implement this modification to your steer function.