The last thing you need to do is put
kinematic constraints and obstacles back into the planning problem.
In the last few exercises,
you've just been worrying about looking for control sequences that
satisfy the differential constraints of the Duban's car model,
but you also need to look for control sequences that don't hit things.
You can incorporate obstacles in two places.
Given a graph or tree of possible curves that your vehicle might be following,
first, when you sample new state X2,
you can check for kinematic feasibility.
And then, more importantly, secondly,
when you're attempting to steer to this point using the steer function,
you can actually modify the simulate function to check at
each step along the way whether you're in collision on your way to X_new.
What you're really doing inside simulate is walking along this curve here.
And just as in the problematic road map,
you can test for kinematic feasibility at each step along its edge.
What if you hit something? Do you
throw the edge away if you're going to have a collision?
No. In fact, if there is an obstacle here that you would hit,
then you simply stop and put X_new right there,
and you start propagating all the way horizonty and keep X_new,
the last state that was feasible.
And with that, you've extended your RT implementation,
where you started with randomly sampled states,
growing the graph, trying to steer towards the samples without collision.
Now it's your turn to implement.