There are a couple of more key ideas that we need to
consider about the vehicle representation in order to get to planning.
You now know that you can represent the location of
your vehicle as a reference point in some coordinate frame.
For the most part, we'll be considering the local ECEF frame for planning and you
can represent your vehicles orientation in that local ECEF frame as a reference vector.
So, you have your vehicle in a local ECEF coordinate frame,
it's got some reference location point, it's got some orientation.
And next, you can think about actual motion of the vehicle
as basically just changes to the reference point in your coordinate system.
So for instance, if the vehicle is at
some location 'x' sub 'b' and is going to move to some new location,
let's call it 'x' sub 'b' prime then we can think of the new location of
the vehicle is equal to the previous location plus this transformation vector.
If you want your vehicle to not only translate to a new location,
but also to rotate to some new orientation then
you'll construct a corresponding quaternion 'q' sub theta
and you can now think of your new orientation as equal to
'q' sub theta times the original orientation times 'q' sub theta prime.
And so it's as simple as that.
Every time your vehicle goes through
a transformation of position and orientation during planning,
you're just applying a translation to
the reference points and a rotation to the reference orientation.
You can sequence these changes together over time to create a plan.