At this point, we've covered some really useful ideas
when it comes to representing your vehicle for solving the planning problem.
We've looked at different coordinate frames and how you can represent
your vehicles position and orientation within those coordinate frames.
But real robots are not just points and orientation vectors,
they have some physical size.
And the real world is not
just some big empty coordinate frame, but it has obstacles in it.
So, now I'm going to talk about how to represent
your vehicle within what is called your configuration space,
which is a way of taking into account the physical size of
the vehicle as well as the location of obstacles in the environment.
Let's start with a simple example where I've got
this square-shaped robot that is free to move about in a 2D plane.
I can then also introduce an obstacle into the environment like this.
This obstacle now represents locations where the robot cannot go.
So, we refer to those points as infeasible locations for the robot.
So, now I have a robot with a physical size and the world has obstacles.
But for computational purposes,
I would still like to represent my vehicle or,
in this case, my little square robot as simply a point in an orientation vector.
So, suppose I choose this point as the origin in the body frame of my robot.
I'd now like to know what regions of space are feasible and infeasible for that point.
To see how that works, I can simply move the robot around
the obstacle and see what kind of shape is mapped out.
Okay, so now the set of infeasible points for our chosen origin point looks like this.
I didn't have to choose that particular origin point.
I could have chosen any point in the body frame of the vehicle.
And for each different point,
the infeasible area would take on a slightly different shape.
So, what about orientation?
Well, I can change the orientation of my robot and see that it
traces out a new area of infeasible locations.
And as I continue to change the orientation,
each new orientation traces out a new area of infeasible points in space.
In this way, I can map out what the infeasible area looks like for
my chosen point of origin in the body frame at all possible orientations of the vehicle.
This new map of the environment is three-dimensional and is referred to
as my configuration space with free points and infeasible points.
In general, your configuration space will have
a dimensionality equal to the number of degrees of freedom of your robot.
So, in this case, our robot has
two translational degrees of freedom and one rotational degree of freedom.
So, three total.
Flying robots typically have six degrees of freedom,
three translational and three rotational.
Your configuration space for a flying car will be six-dimensional.
The most exciting and useful thing about configuration space is that within this space,
your robot becomes a single point.
Obstacles take on more complex shapes.
So, for example, on the case,
we just looked at my 2D obstacle now takes on a three-dimensional shape because it
looks different to the robot as a function of the robot's orientation.
Even though the obstacles have more complex shapes now,
it's much easier to plan a path because we can represent the robot
as a single point in this three-dimensional space.
To consider one more example,
we can look at a different 2D robot and multiple obstacles.
In 2D space, you might think of the robot as
sweeping out some area as it travels through the environment,
but in configuration space,
the robot moves through three-dimensional obstacles as a single point.
Going into higher dimensional configuration spaces,
it gets harder to visualize things,
but that's not a problem because in fact,
we're not actually going to compute these complex obstacle shapes explicitly.
And rather than defining
a six-dimensional configuration space for your quadrotor and simulation,
you'll create a simplified 3D configuration space by simply adding
a margin of infeasible space around each of the physical obstacles before planning.