In this lesson, I've covered the basics of
vehicle representation which is a key concept in robotics applications of all kinds.
But in particular, for flying cars,
where you'll need to plan a path from
one place to another while avoiding obstacles along the way.
We started out by looking at
the coordinate systems that you'll be dealing with in this program.
These include the geodetic frame,
which is a spherical latitude and
longitude frame covering the entire surface of the earth.
Then, your local Earth-Center Earth-Fixed or ECEF frame,
which is a more convenient Cartesian frame for
representimg motion within your local environment.
And finally, the body frame,
which allows you to define where things are
with respect to one another on the body of your vehicle.
Next, we looked at vehicle orientations and how you
can describe changes in orientation using Euler angles,
and rotation matrices, or quaternions.
In this program, you'll be converting back and forth between Euler angles and
quaternions to take advantage of the mathematical simplicity of quaternions,
and the intuitive nature of Euler angles.
With position and orientation defined,
we looked at how you can describe the motion of
your vehicle using transformations of position and orientation.
And finally, we explored how
the physical shape of your vehicle can be taken into consideration to
define a configuration space which is the parameter space
that allows you to treat your vehicle as a simple point.