Up to this point, you've been considering how you can find
a path from a start state to a goal state by connecting cells in a grid.
In the real world, however,
you need to take into account the fact that your vehicle has
physical size that occupies space in the world,
and not only that, it has an orientation which for
some kinds of vehicles can limit how and where it can move.
A big part of solving the planning problem is finding a way to represent the vehicle.
And for different kinds of representations,
particular algorithms can operate more or less efficiently.
So in this lesson, we'll take a look at how to
represent your vehicle's position and orientation within the world.
And then, how to incorporate
that information into your search space for solving the planning problem.
We'll start out by investigating
three different coordinate frames that come in
handy for representing your vehicle's position,
namely: the geodetic or global frame,
your local Cartesian coordinate frame,
and the body frame which is a coordinate frame attached to the vehicle itself.
After that, I'll show you how you can express
your vehicle's orientation using Euler angles and
rotation matrices and how life gets
so much simpler when you switch to using quaternions. What are those?
We'll find out. We'll combine these representations of position and orientation to
describe the motion through the physical world
as transformations of position and orientation.
And finally, we'll explore
the so-called configuration space of your planning problem which is
the parameter space where you incorporate
your vehicle's physical size and shape into your description of the environment.