In our investigation of the planning problems so far,
we've talked about the fact that different choices of
representation can make the problem easier or harder to solve.
In this context, one of the most basic questions to consider is,
how do you represent the vehicle?
The way that you represent location in the world is typically using a coordinate frame.
For flying cars, we're actually going to have
to keep track of a few different coordinate frames.
The first frame you're going to have to keep track
of is the one that you're probably most familiar
with which is latitude and longitude for specifying a location on the earth.
This will be a lot easier to explain if I actually had a globe
to show you. Thanks, globe fairy.
Latitude and longitude on the globe,
they define what's known as the geodetic frame.
Of course, for flying cars,
we need to keep track of altitude as well.
The geodetic frame is just a spherical coordinate system where
the typical coordinates are theta and phi are represented by altitude,
longitude, and latitude respectively.
Altitude, of course, is your height above the earth's surface.
And so unlike a typical spherical coordinate system with r equals to zero at the origin,
we set altitude to be zero at the surface of the earth.
Latitude and longitude then specify
your position on that spherical surface and they can be given in degrees,
minutes, seconds, or degrees decimals.
So, its important to know the units you're working with.
It's also important to know the order in which you're being given latitude and longitude.
A spherical coordinate system can be a little bit difficult for actually doing
motion planning because it's hard to compute distances using angular quantities.
So next, we'll convert to a more convenient local frame.