From geodetic coordinates, the first thing you usually want to
do is convert to a linearized Cartesian coordinate frame,
the so-called Earth-centered Earth-fixed or ECEF frame.
The key idea with the ECEF frame is that every point in
space is represented as x, y, and z.
What is really most useful is a coordinate system that
actually has its origin somewhere on the surface of the earth.
That could be your takeoff point
or maybe it's home-based or some other convenient location.
In this frame, the z coordinate is the height above the surface of the earth
while x and y basically tell you how far you are laterally from the origin of the frame.
And with that, you have a local ECEF frame.
So, next comes the choice of how to represent
this frame with respect to the geodetic frame.
The x and y axes now define a plane that's
tangent to the surface of the earth, and in principle,
I could choose to have those axes point at any direction where
the most common representation using aeronautics
is having x point north, then y point east.
Wait a second, that's not east, that's east.
That means, z has to point down.
It might seem counter-intuitive to have z point
down instead of up to indicate altitude above the earth,
but in this case, that would leave you with
a left-handed coordinate system which is not standard for aeronautics.
So instead, we let z be positive downward and we have
the so-called North East Down or NED coordinate frame.
This is the most common local frame used in aeronautics and is what
we'll be using as our local ECEF frame throughout this program.