One last coordinate frame that we're going to keep track of is the body frame.
The origin of the body frame is going to be some point on the vehicle.
Could be for example,
the center of mass, or it could be some other location.
All of the other points in the body frame are defined relative to that origin.
If the vehicle moves,
the body frame moves with it.
There are two main reasons we need a body frame.
One is that the body frame is a really useful and convenient way of keeping track of
the relative distances between different elements of the vehicle like the sensors.
So, I might have a camera on the front of the vehicle,
I might have an IMU at the tail,
I might have air sensors on the wings and so on.
Knowing where all of these sensors are relative to one
another in the body frame is very important
for fusing all the sensor measurements together
into a consistent estimate of where the vehicle is.
The second reason the body frame is important is that this is often
the best coordinate frame for representing
control inputs such as velocities and accelerations.
For example, for a fixed-wing vehicle,
it's easiest to think of the throttle just changing the magnitude of
the thrust vector that is fixed along the x axis in the body frame.
As the vehicle is moving and rotating that thrust vector changes,
which way it points in the external world,
but it's going to stay constant in the body frame.
It's a lot harder to think of the throttle as a three-dimensional control input.