The most common representation for
three dimensional orientation is through what are called Euler angles,
named after the famous 18th century mathematician Leonhard Euler.
Euler angles are usually given as roll, pitch, and yaw.
And they specify the attitude or orientation of a vehicle,
or any other rigid body for that matter,
as a sequence of rotations about the axes of the body-frame coordinate system.
So, here I have a vehicle and my body-frame coordinate system looks like this,
with positive x toward the front of the vehicle,
positive y out the right hand side,
and positive z pointing down.
In the body frame, you can think of roll as
the counterclockwise rotation about the positive x-axis.
So I tell you that the vehicle rolled positive 30 degrees.
I mean that looking down from above the positive x direction,
this maneuver appears as a counterclockwise rotation of the vehicle.
Also, it's really important that we all agree that
rotations are always counterclockwise around the axis.
You can think of this as a right handed rule.
If your right handed thumb points along the axis of rotation,
positive rotations are in the directions that your fingers curl.
The same convention applies for the other two Euler angles.
Namely, pitch is defined as a counterclockwise rotation about
the positive y-axis and yaw as a counterclockwise rotation about the positive z-axis,
keeping in mind that the z-axis points down.
Notice that the body frame resembles our ECEF local frame,
where x points north,
y to the east, and z down. And that's no mistake.
With this choice of body frame when the vehicle is level and pointing north,
the axes of the body frame are aligned with the local north, east,
down ECEF frame and yaw angles correspond to heading angles on a compass.
This convention derives from way back when ships were first sailing on the oceans.
We didn't have to do things this way,
but generally it makes things more intuitive and these are
the most common choice of local and body-frame coordinate systems for aeronautics.
There is no common standard for the orders specifying Euler angles.
Whether it's roll first then pitch then yaw,
or pitch then yaw then roll.
You just have to agree on the ordering with
everybody you're developing your software with.
And stick to it, because when I give you a triplet of numbers,
it doesn't uniquely specify the orientation unless you already know the order of things.
This is actually a source of many real world bugs in robotics,
so watch out for this.
In this program, we'll go with a convention of roll first,
then pitch, then yaw, in that order.
Euler angles are easy to understand,
but they have some problems.
One of which is, as I just said,
that the order which the rotations are applied matters.
So, if I'm going to say that the vehicle is
rolled and pitched to get some new orientation,
I need to know whether the roll is applied first,
and then the pitch, or the other way around.
Again, it's a matter of convention.
But, if you get the convention wrong,
then the orientation you calculate will also be wrong.
But that's not all. There's also the problem of gimbal lock,
which is what we'll look at next.