As I said before, Euler angles are intuitive,
but they suffer from a problem known as gimbal lock.
So, first off, what the heck is a gimbal anyway?
Well, gimbal is just a support with a pivot point
that allows an object to be rotated about one axis.
To allow more degrees of freedom, we can add more gimbals.
To be able to rotate about three axes and simulate the behavior of Euler angle rotations,
we'll need three gimbals, like this.
So, for Euler rotations,
you can imagine your vehicle attached to these gimbals,
and you send it commands to roll,
pitch, and yaw about the axes in the gimbals.
What you'll notice very quickly in this configuration is that order matters.
To demonstrate gimbal lock in this configuration,
I can see that if I start a series of
rotations by first pitching the vehicle up to 90 degrees,
then what will happen is that the red and blue gimbals will line up.
Suddenly roll and yaw actually have the same effect.
What that means is that the vehicle can no longer yaw.
Or rather, it will be as if a yaw maneuver actually affects the roll of the vehicle.
This was a real problem for the Apollo astronauts.
They were using a mechanical set of gimbals to compute the attitude of their vehicle,
and they needed the flight computer to warn them if they were close to gimbal lock,
and they would have to be careful to steer the ship away from falling into gimbal lock,
if they wanted to know which way was up.
This was so annoying that Michael Collins asked
mission control for an extra gimbal for Christmas.
A redundant fourth gimbal makes gimbal lock go away.
Why didn't the Apollo units have a fourth gimbal?
Well, it seems that at MIT we didn't think
the weight and cost is worth it. Sorry about that Mike.
So, does this mean the vehicle can't physically yaw?
Well, if it were bolted to
a gimbal apparatus like this that's exactly what it would mean.
But of course our vehicle is not bolted down and is free to physically yaw,
but by describing orientation through the use of Euler angles,
we've effectively bolted it down with mathematics
because the order of rotations can cause exactly the same effect.
So, gimbal lock is both a mathematical property of using Euler angles to
represent the vehicle's attitude and is a physical property of real gimbals.
If you have a device that stabilized using three separate mechanical gimbals,
the ordering of how they are arranged matters,
just like the order in which you apply Euler rotations matters.