Now, let's take a closer look at the mathematical gimbal lock property of Euler angles.
Given a coordinate system,
I can represent the orientation of some point in space by an actual rotation matrix.
So, I have my vehicle which is at some location in a particular frame,
let's say it's the local ECF frame,
and I can represent the orientation of the vehicle as
corresponding to a rotation in that frame driven by rotation matrix.
Here are the three different rotation matrices
corresponding to a roll rotation about the x-axis,
a pitch rotation about the y-axis,
and yaw rotation about the z-axis.
With these matrices, I can represent any attitude of the vehicle as a sequence of roll,
pitch, and yaw rotations.
And to move the vehicle to a new orientation,
I then multiply these matrices together to get my new representation.
The order in which I apply these rotations matters, as we said a few times.
Then under certain conditions, I'll run into gimbal lock.
But another concern is that this is now
an over parameterized system ready to
carry around nine numbers in order to represent my orientation,
which does have some modest storage implications.
Despite these drawbacks, Euler angles are still used in
many aeronautics applications because they are intuitive and useful,
for example, in communication with a human pilot.
In this program, to run your calculations,
you'll be converting your Euler angles into quaternions,
which are a much more elegant representation
that will simplify your life and your computation.