In 1843 in Dublin,
William Rowan Hamilton had an epiphany so
profound he felt compelled to scroll it into the Broome bridge.
I squared equals J squared equals K squared equals IJK equals minus one.
So what the heck does that even mean?
Well, for starters we're talking about quaternions here and I,
J and K are all imaginary numbers,
which means that they do strange things like squared to negative one.
A single quaternion basically accomplishes the same thing mathematically as a series
of rotation matrix multiplications but in a much more compact form.
I can represent a quaternion as a scalar quantity A and then three numbers B C and D,
which when those three are taken together are the vector component of the quaternion.
You can think of the vector component as representing the magnitude in each of the I,
J and K directions.
So this is just mathematical notation and is not very intuitive,
but this compact representation is equivalent to a composition of
three rotation matrices and can be used just
as well to describe the orientation of your vehicle.
And when it comes to changes in orientation,
the interesting thing about quaternions is that if I have a unit quaternion,
which is to say the square root of the sum of
the squares of the scalar and the vector component is equal to one,
then my quaternion Q corresponds to a unique rotation in
three dimensional space and that means I can use
quaternions to represent changes in the orientation of my vehicle as well.
To perform a rotation, you'll need a unit quaternion and it's inverse.
The inverse of a unit quaternion is pretty simple.
Just write the same thing with minus signs where the plus signs were.
And now for example,
if I have some point on the body frame of the vehicle and I
pre and post multiply by the quaternion and its inverse,
then I get out some new point which is a result of
rotating by whatever rotation is encoded in that quaternion.
I can also multiply quaternions together to compose multiple rotations,
and I can convert from Euler angles to quaternions and back again.
For computation, the quaternion representation
is better than both the Euler angles and rotation matrices in
that it avoids some of the problems associated with
these other representations such as substantial over parameterization and gimbal lock.
Still, it's often useful to convert back to
Euler angles to be able to present a more human readable version of what's going on.
So here are the quaternion representations of roll,
pitch and yaw, and these equations
here show how to convert from quaternions back to Euler angles.
Similarly, you can recover rotation matrices from A,
B and C like this.
For the most part, this will all be going on under the hood in
your code and you don't need to worry too much about these equations,
but it's just worth keeping in mind the conversion between
quaternions and the more familiar Euler angles is pretty easy.