Hello. My name is Sebastian Thrun.
I'm founder of Udacity and I'm one of the instructors in
our new Nanodegree that we called Flying Cars.
Flying cars is a bit of a misnomer.
This is about drones, about anything flying.
But there's a nascent new industry here in
Silicon Valley and around the world that looks into
flight as a transportation medium for goods and people on a daily basis.
Now, we have the chance here at Udacity in Silicon Valley,
to be at the heart of innovation.
And we see things that others don't quite see yet.
Ten years ago, we saw that self-driving cars would become a big topic, and guess what?
It's become the biggest topic in Silicon Valley today.
I predict in five years time,
flying vehicles will be the biggest topic in Silicon Valley innovation.
And the reason I believe is this,
transportation is a huge industry,
really important for people,
but the ground is very limited in transportation.
If we could build vehicles,
it would easy to go off vertically,
fly us to where we want to go, and land.
You could go faster, of course.
We could be safer because of fewer things to hit in the sky than on the ground.
And we will be environmentally more friendly and use less energy.
And the last thing is a bit of a surprise but if you look at the modern aircraft,
when a modern aircraft loses its power,
it glides down at a glide ratio of about one-to-15 or so,.
which means, the energy consumption used for lift for keeping a flying vehicle in the air
is only a 15th of the energy used to combat the air, which is what we call drag.
Now, we've built this Nanodegree to be the first in the world to teach flying cars.
There's no other place I can
imagine that would teach that material that we're teaching here.
And once students graduate from this class,
easily find a job, and can tell you,
former company Kitty Hawk,
they are desperately looking for people to hire.
And we put together a skill set and set of instructors who are world class.
This new industry is small today.
It's going to be big tomorrow.
Amazon, Google, and others will use drone-based systems.
Others will follow. Your pizza will fly in.
It sounds all like science fiction but the chance you get in this Nanodegree
is to really become part of that science fiction and make the future.