Hello and welcome to the Flying Car Nanodegree Program.
We'll get you coding up self-flying drones and flying car fleets in no time.
But before diving in, we want to say hello and give a quick program overview.
So, to start, hi.
I'm Jake and I'm the product lead for the Flying Car Nanodegree Program.
Before joining Udacity, I was a computer science PhD candidate at Stanford University,
where I specialized in AI, robotics, and perception.
As product lead, I make sure everything from classroom content,
to your career prospects,
to the curriculum are top notch.
And speaking of curriculum-
Hi. I'm Andy and I'm the program curriculum lead.
I studied physics at MIT,
and I've been involved at Udacity since basically day one.
I've worked on everything from psychology,
to physics, to self-driving cars.
And as curriculum lead for this program,
I work directly with our instructors to make sure
you get the best educational experience possible.
Great.
Now that you've met Sebastian, Andy, and myself,
in the rest of this lesson,
you'll meet our other amazing instructors,
learn about how the program works,
and wrap up with a little fun.
We're thrilled to be working with you and welcome to the program.