It is my really great pleasure to introduce the three instructors in this course.
Angela, from Germany originally but at Toronto now.
Angela heads the Dynamic Systems Lab at the Institute for Aerospace Studies at
the University of Toronto and she's also
the Associate Director of the Center for Aerobotics Research and Education.
I had to cheat because the title is longer than
any other title I've seen in my life. So, what does it mean? What do you do?
So, I'm leading a team conducting research at the interface of robotics,
controls, and machine learning.
And what this means is,
we built robotic systems that can learn from experience and from each other,
and the goal is that they, through that,
can do tasks better,
operate more safely and are generally more independent.
That's exciting because even if you got 10,000 Amazon drones in the sky,
if this one learn something about the world,
all the 9,999 others will learn the same thing.
That would be one of the ideas.
That's great. Nick, Nick Roy,
we've known each other for a long time because we've
worked together at Carnegie Mellon University
but he's now Professor of Aeronautics and Astronauts at MIT,
and he leads a group of researchers in CSAIL,
MIT's Artificial Intelligence Lab. What do you do?
Well, to first-order, I'm
very lucky to have a great group of students and
post-docs and I do PR and fundraising for them.
But more specifically, what we do is
we look at a lot of related issues to what Angela was mentioning.
Issues of vehicles, how they navigate in complicated,
cluttered environments where you don't have external infrastructure like GPS, et cetera.
We look at the issues of how these vehicles understand what's
happening around them especially in a human-centered environment.
They need to be able to interpret what's happening around them,
understand what people want,
and make safe and reliable decisions.
Now, together, we're building the Nanodegree program on
flying cars and flying cars is a bit of a misnomer.
It's not going to look like cars with bumpers,
but the field of flying
vehicles is becoming incredibly hot in Silicon Valley and around the world,
and I'm super delighted we could attract
two super stellar professors to teach this business program with us.
So, we came here together because we are building this joint Nanodegree,
it's the world's first educational program on flying cars and hopefully,
in a good Udacity fashion,
we will teach more students
these technologies and all universities in the world combined.
Let's find out. But I wanted to ask both of you a bit
about what you're actually teaching and about the interesting problems
are for students. Maybe start with Nick?
Okay.
So for me, the flying car is a great aspirational goal.
We've got a long way to go.
The real content that I want students
to get from this is addressing the challenges of making these vehicles smarter.
So, one of the dirty little secrets of any unmanned system,
whether it's on air, on the ground,
is the total labor,
human labor required to operate that unmanned system.
These vehicles are fundamentally really dumb.
All they do is get from point A to point B.
They can't react to the unexpected and in the ways that people can.
They can't adjust what they're doing.
That kind of intelligence,
that kind of reasoning, that kind of autonomy,
is core to what we're trying to teach for enabling flying cars.
Great.
So, what I'm really excited about in this Nanodegree is that we really teach
the fundamentals on how the physics of
these vehicles were both fixed-wing and multi-rotor.
But then, take it all the way to a real implementation
either in a high-fidelity simulator or the real drone itself.
And I think, both skills really are needed to bring the field forward in the future.
And I'm so excited that both of you are such great instructors in our Nanodegree program.
And for you who are watching,
if you're interested in becoming a student, enroll or apply,
and I guess, I'll see you in class.