We have a vision for the future.
In that flying cars,
and flight is going to be a part of
the transportation network to an even greater degree than it is already,
and there are technical challenges,
and there's a need for people trained in specific foundational concepts,
and future-looking, forward-facing concepts that people still need to know now,
in order to develop that technology.
The flying car nanodegree is Udacity's sense of what
the concepts are the people need to know in order to make flying cars a reality.
A lot of the development will be in the context
of a smaller scale drone because of what people have right now,
the issues are same really at every level at every size of a vehicle.
This program is unique because it includes
the fundamentals about the vehicle dynamics both multirotor and fixed-wing,
but then carries this through to real practical implementation.
So you will implement your own controller as the major and mission planner.
The students are going to develop a variety of skills.
We're going to begin very simply with just giving students
a project that shows how you command a simple drone.
How does a vehicle know where it is?
How does it execute a flight plan,
and how does it decide what that flight plan should be?
And so, the very first skill is just like,
what are the mechanics of actually getting an air vehicle under control?
Even if it's only in simulation,
everybody will have gone through the experience of connecting
to a UAV or a drone of some kind,
and putting it through its paces.
We're sort of setting it up as just like a little flight in your backyard.
In fact, we're calling the project, the backyard flight.
The second project the students will be looking at is 3D motion planning.
How do you generate a plan that is ideally suited for
staying as far away from buildings and other obstacles as possible?
And also, how do you set up the planning problem so
the vehicle for replanned as quickly as possible, if necessary.
So we really want students to be thinking about
all these different tradeoffs as they build towards that first project.
So in the controls project,
students will learn to implement a flight controller from scratch,
that will stabilize the vehicle,
and allow the vehicle to follow a path.
Then we'll start to drill down a little bit more
into how the vehicle is actually executing those flight plans.
How does the vehicle know where it is?
How does the vehicle take in sensor data,
GPS, and other kinds of data,
and then construct a consistent estimate of where it is,
and what its attitude is in space?
For robots to understand the world, it needs sensors,
and state estimation is the field that describes how different sensor information,
and sources of information can be best combined to make sense of the world.
So in the state estimation project,
students will design an algorithm that uses sensor data from GPS
and IMU to estimate the position and orientation of our flying robot.
In term two, we're going to dramatically expand the scope
of technical challenges that the students are going to be thinking about.
We are going to really make sure that the students
understand some of the low-level and foundational concepts.
We're going to move away from the very simple drone quadrotor model.
Look at the challenges of modeling the dynamics of a fixed-wing aircraft,
and a hybrid aircraft that can either go into full aerodynamic flight,
or go into hover, and so on and so forth.
Later on in the course,
we will also study how we can coordinate a whole fleet of
drones to achieve a task together such as delivering packages to customers.
To people who want to get a start in robotics,
or aerial robotics, frankly,
there's no better way than sitting down and starting to just implement simple things.
Having that comfort with just implementing things and trying things,
is a great foundation for coming into the Udacity Course.
There's really a tremendous amount of autonomy
and intelligence required to get us from one
off prototype demonstrations to the kind of reliability
that is going to allow a scalable, reliable, operable service.
My prediction for the future is that 80 percent of
all transportation of people and goods can be autonomous in the next 30 years.