When you enroll in Udacity Nanodegree Program,
you become part of a global community.
You can connect instantly with thousands of
amazing people in our Flying Car Slack Community.
So, be sure to keep in touch on Slack and you never know,
you might even find a study group to collaborate with in your hometown.
And in addition to that student community,
Udacity has dedicated resources set up for you to succeed.
For one, whenever you submit your projects,
they will be reviewed by real human experts not just some bots.
And whenever you have additional flying car questions,
well, we have a team for that too.
Hi, I'm Tucker, I'm Aurina, and I'm Lisbeth.
And we're the student experience team.
We'll always be monitoring Slack and ready to answer any questions you have.
And know that there are
so many more Udacity team members ready to help you on everything from exercises,
to meet-ups, to careers, and beyond.
So on behalf of all of us, welcome to Udacity.