So, we're getting to the end of the course.
We want to share some content with you.
It is not required for the final project,
but it's important when you build actual physical systems.
It has to do with the fact that so far we have a very strong reliance on GPS.
Or else it will just not work without GPS,
because if you don't know where you are,
you could start drifting at a certain speed and never figure that out.
The only way to prevent a flyaway scenario is using GPS.
Sometimes, GPS is not available.
This might be because you are next to tall buildings or
it might be because someone has a GPS Gema,
that's actually exist and GPS is not able.
So, now we're going to give you some information on how to make
a drone fly without GPS and we're going to replace
GPS using a downward facing camera as a way to track your position on the ground.