If we assume that our prior distribution is
given according to a distribution we can sample from,
then we can use Monte Carlo sampling to actually propagate
that prior distribution according to the vehicle dynamics.
Remember that the vehicle dynamics are given according to a model,
say x sub t plus one is equal to g of x sub t,
plus W sub t. Where w sub t is noise sampled according to some normal distribution.
Basically the status propagated according to some function g,
perturbed by some noise.
Let's say that we start with a set of samples;
x sub t, and we apply the function g to each of those samples.
Then the result will be samples drawn from g of
x sub t. We see here that we have samples drawn from this initial distribution,
which is a Gaussian, with some mean, and some co-variance,
and if we propagate each of the samples according to g of x sub t,
then we might get something that looks like that.
Now this isn't quite what we should get because we also have to add a noise.
If we draw a set of noise samples, w sub t,
drawn according to a normal with some noise co-variance,
and add a noise sample to each of the propagated state samples,
we get a new set of samples,
X sub t plus one,
which is equal to g of x sub t plus W sub t. Now,
this example here is a really simple 2D example,
but implicit in this is orientation.
Let's assume the state vector is composed of x, y, and Theta.
We propagate x, y and Theta according to G, which is X sub t,
plus cosine Theta sub t,
y sub t plus sine Theta sub t,
and Theta sub t plus some noise.
This 2D plot doesn't show orientation,
but we assume that our prior distribution has x and y centered at the origin,
with orientation also centered at a mean of Theta equal to zero,
with some variance around there.
If we propagate all those samples,
according to this constant velocity model,
we see that the samples basically get propagated to the right.
If we modify the prior,
so the orientation is sampled uniformly from minus pi to pi,
and we then propagate the samples,
we see all the samples generally move away from the origin.
Remember, that there are no controls here,
this is a very simple constant velocity dynamics model,
but what you see is that in both of these cases,
these are posterior distributions that will be very,
very hard to express in a Kalman filter setting.
The sampling approach gives us a way to actually
capture these very different kinds of distributions.