We've handled the motion propagation.
But if we want to do the same thing to incorporate the sensor model,
it gets more complicated.
The distribution we want to sample from,
given a sensor measurement is p of x sub t given
z sub t. It's not at all obvious how to sample from this distribution directly.
What is interesting however is that we can often evaluate distributions.
That is; given a specific measurement z sub t,
we can evaluate the likelihood of a given state
x sub t. Given the ability to evaluate a distribution,
can we sample from it?
The answer is yes, we can do that using a process known as important sampling.
Let's assume that we have some distribution p of x that we want to sample from,
we don't know how but we have a way to evaluate it.
That is, given some value x we can at least compute p of x.
We'll call this distribution, the target distribution.
Let's assume that we have some other distribution q of x that we can sample from.
We'll call this the proposal distribution,
it can be anything at all.
Let's draw some samples,
xi from q of x.
Each of these vertical lines is a sample.
Now, let's imagine that we want to sample from this bimodal Gaussian distribution here.
So, that's our p of x, our target.
Mathematically p of x looks like this
with some weights to make sure everything is properly normalized.
Unfortunately, we can't always sample directly from multi-modal Gaussians,
but what we can do is we can sample from
a proposal distribution which in this case might be the uniform distribution.
Given the ability to sample from this uniform distribution,
how do we turn these samples into samples that actually match the bimodal Gaussian?
Let's give each sample a weight
which we can represent by the height of the vertical line.
That weight is going to be equal to the ratio between
the target p of x of i and the proposal q of x of i.
We can now treat the weighted samples as if
they were drawn from the target distribution itself.
For instance, we can compute the mean of the target,
x^ as the sum of the weighted samples and that will give us the correct mean.
Furthermore, if we draw a fresh set of samples
x_star of y from the samples according to the weights,
samples with higher weight are more likely than lower weight samples,
which means that the new samples will be
distributed as if they were drawn from the target itself.
This is exactly what we wanted,
samples distributed according to some arbitrary distribution p of x.
To recap what we just did,
we started with some target distribution
p of x that we wanted to sample from but couldn't.
Then, we generated a uniform proposal distribution q of x from which we could sample.
Then, we sample from that proposal distribution and assign weights to
each sample according to the ratio of p of x over q of x.
Finally, we resample those particles according to the weights,
which left us with equally weighted particles distributed according to p of x.
This approach will work generally for any proposal and any target.
But let's plug in the values for the specific estimator that we want.
We started with samples drawn from our prior p of x sub t,
and we want to generate samples drawn from p of x sub t,
given z sub t. That means that our target is p of x sub t
given z sub t and our proposal is p of x sub t. Notice,
that if we use Bayes' rule we can rewrite our target as some normalizer
alpha times p of z sub t given x sub t times p of x sub t. Then,
the p of x sub t terms cancel and all of a sudden our weights become p of
z sub t given x sub t. We can safely ignore the normalizer alpha,
because we're going to resample from the weighted samples
anyhow and the normalizer will have no effect on that process.
This results should make sense intuitively.
The weights now are just proportional to the likelihood of the samples.