Evaluating p of Z sub t,
given X sub t, will of course depend on your specific sensor.
Let's take a look at using a range sensor in a 2D map.
A range sensor emits a pulse of energy along
some bearing and that energy is reflected off the closest obstacle.
And, based on the return properties of that energy,
either the time of flight or the phase,
we get a measurement of distance.
Errors in the measured range are typically normally
distributed around the true range and that distribution can be
parameterized with a mean given by the true range of
the obstacle and some variance that depends on the sensors which can be measured.
But, there's also some probability of getting N inappropriately short range,
and some probability of never getting any reflected energy at all.
Which we'd interpret as a measurement of some maximum range.
All of these probabilities of these specific events depend
on the sensor and can be measured from real data.
What we need is the probability of a particular measured range,
given the vehicle is in some position.
But we don't really believe that the behavior of the sensor changes with the position.
What actually changes with the position is the distance to the obstacle.
The probability of a given range at a given position
is actually a function of the obstacles on the map.
This means we can write the sensor model,
p of Z sub t given X of t and m,
where m is a map.
If the sensor distribution really depends on
the realest position of the vehicle in the map,
we can say that the probability of the measurements Z sub t given X sub t and m,
is actually equal to the probability of the measurement,
given some function of the state and the map.
That function is just the Euclidean distance between the state and the nearest obstacle.
Here, lambda is the position of the nearest obstacle along the bearing of the sensor.
After all of this,
we have a sensor model that looks something like this.
As you'd expect, there's a peak here,
where the distance is equal to the actual Euclidean distance.
There's some variance around that peak which depends on the sensor and then there's
also some probability of measuring a maximum range or a short range.
And it's this curve here that characterizes
the probability distribution of all possible measurements given that,
this is where the obstacle actually is.
And it's this funny shape that's no longer Gaussian that's really
hard to capture inside Kalman filter type distributions.