One thing to note is that any sensor on a flying car
or any autonomous vehicle is going to be a digital device,
and can only return a discrete set of range values.
We could therefore collect a big dataset of laser range measurements
and simply count how many times we get each possible range value.
Since the probability depends on the range to the actual object being sensed,
we would need to put the sensor at
all possible distances to obstacles and then collect our data.
But we could do that and we could count up
how many times we get each range value for each distance.
This would give us a nice lookup table which would let us
convert an expected distance x sub t minus Lambda,
into a measurement probability distribution.
Now, how do we find Lambda the position of the nearest obstacle along
the bearing in order to compute the expected distance x sub t minus Lambda?
We've actually done this before in a grid map.
Remember the Bresenham ray tracing algorithm from planning?
We can use that exact same algorithm again here.
What we do is we put the vehicle on the map wherever a sample is,
and along the bearing that the sensor is measuring,
we basically walk through the grid cells until we actually get to an obstacle cell.
Of course, we are tracing between two points but from the sensor in a given direction.
We can get the Bresenham effect of a second point by
finding a point P2 at the edge of the map,
along the bearing of the sensor and then ray tracing from x sub t to
P2 and stopping when we hit our first obstacle cell in the map.
If we're working with a planar lidar that
spins and makes range measurements once every degree,
then that means that z sub t will be a 360 dimensional vector.
We can probably assume independent measurements,
which means that P of z sub t given x sub t is
just the product of the 360 individual measurements.
That means the weight of each sample will be the product of all these likelihoods.
Since we're doing this for every measurement,
for every sample x sub t,
i the computation can really add up.
That's why we like efficient ray tracing algorithms like the Bresenham algorithm.