Okay. We just looked at two different Monte-Carlo sampling techniques.
First for sampling a posterior or the vehicle dynamics given a control and the
second for sampling a posterior over
the state given sensor measurements and doing sensor fusion.
You can now put these together to get
an estimation algorithm known as the particle filter.
The first step is just like in the Kalman filter.
We start with an initial estimate of where the vehicle might be.
This might be a normal distribution with some mean, and some covariance.
Then we sample that distribution to get a set of
samples or particles that will be densest around that mean,
and with fewer samples as we go further from the mean.
You can think of each of these particles as a vehicle that we're modeling.
The hope is that if we do this right,
then our cloud of particles will have a mean that's equal to our vehicles actual mean.
Once we have our prior distribution of samples/particles,
we can take some control action.
Let say U knot,
and use it along with some noise to
propagate those samples according to the vehicle dynamics,
and this leaves us with a new distribution of samples.
This is analogous to the prediction step of a Kalman filter.
Then when a measurement comes in,
we can compute the weight for each sample
as the likelihood of the measurement for each sample.
Basically, we're comparing the vehicles actual observation of
the world to what each of the particles would see if we we're making the observations.
When those are similar,
the likelihood for that particle is high.
Let's say that we sense a landmark nearby in the environment.
Well, the samples that have expected measurements of
that landmark that are closest to the actual measurement of the landmark
are going to have the highest weights and the samples that have expected measurements to
the landmark that are furthest from
the actual measurement to the landmark are going to have the lowest weights.
Then, when we resample from those weighted samples according to those weights,
will end up with many more samples around the location of the actual vehicle
and very few samples far from
location of the vehicle based on that measurement to the landmark.
Unlike the Kalman filter where our initial estimate is
always a gaussian given by a mean and a covariance,
and a posterior is always a mean and a covariance,
our initial estimate here can be given by any initial distribution.
We can sample from the uniform distribution for example,
which allows us to localize the vehicle given prior information that's
very vague when it's not at all clear where the vehicle is.