What are the pros and cons of a particle filter?
Well, the pros are that we can obviously express many more distributions than before.
We can also capture more complex distributions of
our state estimate such as multi-modal distributions.
Unlike the Kalman filter where our initial estimate is always a Gaussian,
given by a mean and a co-variance,
our initial estimate can be given by any initial distribution that we can evaluate,
in order to sample from it.
For example, we've already discussed using the uniform distribution to allow us to
represent the idea that the vehicle is somewhere in the general environment,
but we're not really sure where.
This doesn't happen very often,
but it is a nice thing to know about as an error recovery mechanism if for instance,
estimation fails in some dramatic way.
What are the cons? Well, multi-modal distributions can cause problems for
the control system in that we have to decide
what state to give the controller as our best estimate.
Naively taking the mean of a multi-modal distribution
and using it as a state estimate is obviously the wrong thing to do.
As an example, imagine you had some bi-modal distribution,
then the mean is somewhere in the middle and that's actually
a very unlikely state and the controller could have failures.
Another problem with particle filters is that they tend to be computationally costly.
There's no way to know ahead of time how many particles you need which
is operationally a problem but even worse is that empirically,
the number of particles needed to get a good state estimate seems
to grow exponentially with the number of variables in the state vector.
For a state estimate with 12,16, or 20 variables,
which is often the case for things like flying cars,
particle filtering can be prohibitive.
One way to address this problem is to use
a particle filter over a subset of the state variables.
For example, just over the position of the vehicle,
and then you can incorporate the particle filters position estimate as
an effective measurement inside a Kalman Filter which runs over the entire state vector.
That particular approach is what was used for
state estimation in this airplane flying in a parking garage at MIT.
The sensor is a laser range finder and we wanted to use
a particle filter to handle the badly non-linear laser range finder measurements,
but we didn't want to pay the computational cost of running a full particle filter.
So, the particle filter ran over the position variables,
and the Kalman filter incorporated the output as a measurement,
along with the IMU,
to get a consistent and accurate state estimate in flight.