Over the last few lessons,
you've seen how crucial state estimation is for autonomous flight.
To perform good state estimation we need a few things.
First, we need a good understanding of
our vehicles dynamics which we capture an emotion model for the vehicle.
Next, we need good sensors and a measurement model that allows us to
probabilistically update our state estimate
when we get new information from those sensors.
Finally, we need an algorithm that can
effectively stitch all of these components together.
In the projects you've completed up until now,
we've taken the vehicle state for granted, for example,
when you implemented a controller you were given the exact state of the vehicle.
In the final project for this module you'll implement an estimator to
estimate the state of a quadrotor which moves in three-dimensions. Good luck!