In this final lesson,
we're going to look at a couple of different challenges in estimation.
The first challenge is, how can we incorporate camera images into our estimator?
We could easily spend multiple lessons on how to use
images to estimate our position and velocity,
how to estimate the position of obstacles around
us and how to track other things moving around us.
We're not going to have time to look at all of those questions.
But a lot of vehicles,
including ones you might already own like the Crazyflie use a very simple approach with
a downward facing camera to estimate
the velocity vector using a technique called optical flow.
We'll show you how you can use optical flow to get
a reasonable state estimate for your vehicle even when you don't have GPS.
It's not perfect, but it's a useful thing to know about and
something you could try for indoor flight on your own quadrotor.
The second thing we're going to look at,
is an alternative technique to Kalman Filter called The Particle Filter.
The Particle Filter does a much better job of handling range sensors,
being used to estimate the position of the vehicle in a map.
Remember that the Kalman filter has
strong assumptions of Gaussian noise and linear models.
The EKF and UK let us relax the linearity assumption somewhat,
but The Particle Filter lets us handle non-linear and non-gaussian systems even better.
Notice that both of these topics are designed to give you an estimate without
GPS and GPS to night navigation is really important for flying cars.
When your vehicle is operating in an urban environment close to the ground,
our vehicle is in a regime where GPS is very unreliable.
Being able to use additional sensors to compensate for
GPS errors or manage temporary GPS outages,
is crucial to the reliable operation of your vehicle.