Let's dive into Optical Flow.
The goal here is to use a downward facing camera to
obtain an estimate of the vehicles x and y velocity.
We're going to do this by looking at what's called the
optical flow of the scene from frame to frame.
At the highest level,
this velocity estimation happens in two steps.
First, optical flow analysis.
We need to analyze the data for my camera to obtain
the optical flow vector which describes the x and y velocity of pixels in the scene.
Note that these velocities are measured in something like pixels per frame.
The second step is converting the velocity in pixels per
frame to a vehicle velocity measured in meters per second.
As you can imagine, this step involves a lot of geometry.
The vehicles altitude above the ground,
it's role and it's pitch,
and it's body rates all affect the pixel velocities that the camera sees.
But once you've done this geometry correctly,
you'll be left with a good estimate of the vehicles x and y velocity.