The first thing we need to do to get a velocity estimate for the vehicle,
is to recover the uv velocity vector from the image that the camera sees.
Let's start by looking at how we estimate
the motion of a vehicle from a downward-facing camera.
If we have two images taken from two positions of the camera,
then we can see how much the scene appears to have moved from image to image,
which tells us how much the camera must have moved.
Now, there's many ways to do this,
and it's by no means a solved problem.
The simplest way you can frame the problem is just
to work out the relative velocity of the camera.
But you can take the problem all the way to working out
the exact position of the camera at each point in
time and the entire geometry of the scene.
That process is called visual simultaneous localization and mapping or visual slam.
Regardless of how complicated we make the problem,
the first step is being able to reliably
recognize the same part of the scene from image to image.
Such points we call, features.
There are lots of ways to find good features,
but the basic idea is that good features or points in the image are
ones that we can easily localize by looking through a small window of the image.
Shifting the window in any direction,
should give a large change in pixel intensities of the window.
Which makes the location precisely defined.
If we look at this figure,
we see that we have a small window over this flat grey plane portion of the image,
and if we perturb the window on the image,
what we see through the window hasn't changed at all.
That means that this location is a bad place to put a feature.
We'll have a really hard time figuring out where exactly the feature is in future images.
Now, if we move our window to this part of the image,
you can see that if you move the window left and right,
what you would see is that the image changes quite a bit.
But if you move the window up and down,
then the image isn't going to change it all along that line.
This means at this particular location is a better place
for feature than the gray flat field, but still not great.
On the other hand,
if we put a feature right here and we move the window up and down or left and right,
the image is going to change quite a bit.
We see here at this location,
there's a significant change in all directions.
That means that this is a good place to put a feature,
and it also means the local image at
this location is going to be easy to recognize in future frames.
In your next exercise,
you're going to take advantage of a toolkit that provides
a method to extract features which are called Good Features to Track.
By Shi and Tomasi. And the Shi and
Tomasi Good Features to Track are called good features,
because they are easy to recognize from image to image.