Now that we have good features that we can recognize from image to image,
we need to know how to use them.
Optical flow is the apparent motion of objects, surfaces,
or edges in an image based on the relative motion of the camera.
Let's consider the motion of a single pixel first,
before considering more of the image.
We'll define an image I and a given pixel at x y in the image at time t is
I of x y t. Let's assume that the pixel moves from xy time t to x plus u,
y plus V at time t plus one,
where u and v is the apparent motion induced by the camera moving.
The question is, how do we estimate the motion of a pixel from I of xyt to I of x plus u,
y plus v, t plus one?
We basically need to solve what's called a pixel correspondence problem.
Given a pixel intensity,
I of x y t we'll look for nearby pixels of the same color intensity at I of x prime,
y prime t plus one.
To solve the pixel correspondence problem,
we're going to make two assumptions.
The first is that, the motion is not very large,
u and v are small,
and we don't have to look very far to find the corresponding pixel on the next timestamp.
The second assumption is that,
the pixel appearance itself doesn't change; which means that,
whatever object is being imaged by this pixel, at time t,
is going to look exactly the same at some other pixel at time t plus one.
We can say that, I of x y t is equal to I of x plus u,
y plus v, t plus one.
This is known as the brightness constancy constraint.
Now, this equation here is not very helpful but if we use
a Taylor series expansion on the right hand side of the brightness constancy constraint,
dropping the time index temporarily,
we can see that I of x plus u,
y plus v is roughly equal to I of x y plus
the spatial gradient in the x direction times the velocity in
x direction plus the spatial gradient to the image in the y direction,
times the v velocity.
If we plug that into
the brightness constancy constraint and reorganize terms a little, we get the following.
And here I'm using a subscript to denote derivative.
So, for example, I sub t is the derivative of the image with respect to time.
This equation basically says that any change in the appearance of a pixel x y over
time has to be explained by spatial motion induced by the camera movement.