Okay. We have this equation which relates the optical flow vector,
u and v, to the change in the image from t to t plus one.
But there's a problem here, because this is a single equation with two unknowns.
We don't know u or v,
and this isn't just an abstract mathematical problem,
it's an operational problem called the aperture problem.
The fact that we have one equation with two unknowns means that there
could be motion in the image that we can't necessarily explain.
For example, if I have a pixel on a line,
and the camera moves,
I can't disambiguate any motion parallel to
the image gradient that is parallel to that one.
How do we solve this ill-posed problem?
Remember, up until now we've been looking at individual pixels.
There are a few things we might be tempted to do.
For example, we might want to make u and v consistent everywhere in the image.
But that doesn't actually work because the projective geometry of camera imaging
causes pixel motion to have
variable velocity depending on where in the frame of pixel is.
Instead, what we do is try to make the motion of some group of local pixels consistent.
This is known as a Lucas-Kanade optical flow algorithm.
Let's assume that the pixel neighbors have the same u,v velocity vector.
If we use a five-by-five window,
that gives us 25 equations per pixel,
and you see the 25 equations here.
This equation should look very familiar.
This is essentially a least squares problem that we're trying to solve for u and
v. This can be solved in closed form by noticing that it's in the form,
minus b plus a times x equals zero.
As you learned in the first estimation lesson,
this can be solved as a least squares estimator where x is given by
A transpose A to the power minus one times A transpose again times b.
The x this gives us will be the best estimate for u and v. It's important to notice that
the particular matrix elements in A transpose A tells us
a lot about where we will get a good velocity estimates.
The eigenvalues of A transpose A are essentially the local image gradient.
When the eigenvalues are small,
we will not have much image gradient in any direction,
and the least square solution will be affected
by small variations of the image intensities.
If we look at a five-by-five patch here in this particular image,
the spatial gradient is very low,
and we will not get much optical flow there.
When the ratio of eigenvalues are large,
we'll have a strong image gradient in one direction, but not another.
Imagine that we have a strong spatial gradient in the x direction,
but a very low spatial gradient in the y direction which typically happens along an edge.
The least squares solution will be affected by
small variations in the image intensity along the edge.
When the eigenvalues are large and the ratio of the eigenvalues are small,
we have a strong image gradient in both directions
which usually happens for highly textured regions,
and we'll be able to accurately recover the relative motion of these pixels.
Though Shi-Tomasi features we were looking at
a few minutes ago are designed exactly for this idea.
Finding features where the smallest eigenvalue is still large.
You can also try other features for optical flow such as
the Harris corner detector which is specifically designed to
keep the ratio of the eigenvalues small as well.
But given the ability to extract features from an image,
you can now solve the least squares problem and
determine the motion of those features in subsequent images.
That's exactly what you're going to do using
a Lucas-Kanade optical flow algorithm in your next exercise.