We've assumed throughout the estimation module
that all our noise distributions are Gaussian,
and we've mostly assume that our models are linear,
and when they weren't linear then the Taylor series or
unscented transform were reasonable approximations.
But, there are many ways things can become non-Gaussian.
For example, our measurement model can be
non-Gaussian or our state estimate might be non-Gaussian.
We might believe we're either here or there,
in which case we'd call that a multi-model belief.
These situations show up especially often in
a GPS to night navigation because a lot of the sensors that we use,
especially ranging sensors like LIDAR,
are really non-linear and really non-Gaussian.
Why is that the case? Well, if a range sensor is pointing at a wall like this,
the range will depend on the cosine of Theta,
the bearing of the sensor which is clearly non-linear.
But why is it non-Gaussian?
For it just pointing at this wall and
the distribution on the range measure really would be Gaussian.
But imagine this wall has a corner like this,
and the sensor is pointing at that corner.
Now, a slight perturbation in the bearing will
cause the sensor to go all the way out to some maximum value,
missing the corner and that distribution between hitting the obstacle right there on
the corner and getting a max range measurement
from missing the corner, that's really non-Gaussian.
This makes range sensors really hard to deal with in the
Kalman filter setting. What about the state estimate?
Well, if we don't have GPS and we're relying on maps and
landmarks to estimate our location in some grid of city blocks for example,
then the vehicle may not know whether its actually in
this intersection or in that intersection since they might look very similar.
You could represent that as a mixture of Gaussians
where the vehicle knows it's in one of a couple of different locations,
but doesn't know exactly which one.
This is another example that's really hard to deal with in
the conventional Kalman filter typesetting.
Fortunately, there are methods of state estimation that
are better suited to these highly non-linear and non-Gaussian situations.
The approach we're going to discuss here is something called particle filter.
The main idea behind particle filter is that instead of
maintaining a single belief with an associated uncertainty,
we're going to keep track of many,
maybe hundreds or thousands of particles.
Each of these particles will occupy some position in the state space.
You can almost think of each particle as a simulated quadrotor.
Then, we can mimic the prediction and measurement update
steps that you saw with the common filter.
With a particle filter, prediction involves using the controls commanded to
the actual vehicle to advance each particle
forward in time according to the appropriate dynamics.
The measurement update in turn involves comparing the drone's real sensor measurements,
so the measurements we'd expect each particle to see.
When a real measurement is close to what we'd expect,
that particle has its particle weight increased.
When a measurement is different from what we'd expect,
then that particle has its weight decreased.
When we actually need a consistent state estimate,
we can use a weighted average of all the particle states.
So, this is a very high level explanation of a particle filter.
Let's dive into how this all actually works.