The first thing we need to do is figure out how to
represent a distribution with samples instead of parameters.
A Gaussian can be neatly described with a mean and a covariance.
But now we're going to represent the distribution as a set of discrete samples x_i.
The estimators job is to create a set of samples that capture the distribution.
What's interesting about using samples,
is that you can often use the samples
directly in place of the parametric form of the distribution.
For example, let's say I need to give the control system
the mean of the distribution and I have a set of samples like this x_i,
if those samples are drawn from the distribution,
than they are naturally going to be denser around the mean,
and sparser further away from the mean.
Once I have the set of samples,
then I can compute the mean simply using x hat is equal to the sum of the samples.
Perhaps with some weights and we'll see where those weights come from shortly.
But the important thing is that I can use the samples to compute the mean exactly,
and I can do the same thing for the variance.
Okay, we can use samples and set of parameters to represent our distribution.
But where do these samples come from?
How do we sample from a known distribution?
One way is the computer.
Python gives us ways to sample from some kinds of known distributions.
Num pi in particular is a variety of distributions that we can sample from.
When you look at the num pi documentation,
you see binomial, normal the poisson distribution et cetera.
We can simple directly from these,
but often our distributions are a mixture of components or other kinds of
distributions that we might be able to evaluate that is for a given event or outcome,
we can evaluate the density of that point,
but we can't necessarily sample directly from that distribution.
So, what do we do in that situation?
In particular, how do we propagate our samples using
our knowledge of the commanded controls and the vehicle dynamics?