Estimation is something that you and I do every waking moment.
For example, right now, I'm getting sound waves in your ear with my voice,
and somewhere in your brain,
you form a belief as to what words I just uttered.
Okay, this is called estimation.
Robots have the same estimation problem,
they need to know where they are X, Y,
and Z and possibly fetch for the pitches for the rotors.
So now, we're going to focus on estimation.
Estimation at its core is a temporal process,
so you integrate things over time,
and it's a process of managing uncertainty.
You can never be 100% certain what I've said or whatever it is.
We're going to use Bayes rule as a method to integrate data over time.
Bayes rule is a method to take multiple sources of information,
and coming up with the distribution that is
the best reflection of what the state might be.
And your goal is going to be to make a very tight distribution,
so as to fights certain ways.