Now, we've assumed so far that our random variables are scalars,
but what if they are actually vectors.
The vehicle position isn't going to be given by a single variable x,
It's going to be given by x, y and z.
Presumably, we could fold attitude in there as well.
Which would make x, a six dimensional vector.
And we'd like to have a distribution over those variables.
If we treat each variable separately,
then we're making some strong assumptions about
independence that we'll talk about in a little bit.
But, we can actually define vector value functions over the vector value inputs.
And the same concepts that we saw for scalar values existence before.
The integral still has to come to one.
In this case, the normalization constant that makes this
come to one would be the integral of f(x),
dx1, dx2 up to dxn.
The mean it's given by the same set of integrals,
but it's the integral of x times f(x).
Instead of a variance,
we have a co-variance,
which is going to be given in this case by upper case
Sigma and that's going to be equal to the integral of x minus mu,
times x minus mu transpose, times the density.
This co-variance is going to be a matrix,
because the outer product is going to result in a matrix as well.
The co-variance is going to be a symmetric matrix and positive semi-definite.
If you remember your linear algebra,
positive semi-definite means that there are no negative eigenvalues.
Now, we can define a multivariate Gaussian.
We have to again take care to do the vector math correctly,
but the functional form is not that different.
We're no longer taking square root of two pi,
it's n over two for a vector x of length n.
This term here is the determinant to the co-variance
and then we have the vector value multiplication.
The estimate of the parameters is almost the same as before,
taking care to do the vector math correctly.
And we see here an example of a two dimensional co-variance.
And an important property of the co-variance, is that the eigenvalues and eigenvectors of the co-variance,
describe the amount and direction of uncertainty.
Here, we have an overhead view and
that location at the center of the ellipse would be the mean.
If we take the co-variance and extract the eigenvalues and eigenvectors,
this would be the first eigenvector and this will be the second eigenvector.
If I draw an ellipse at one eigenvalue away from the mean along each vector,
then this one eigenvalue ellipse is going to define
a confidence region which in this case is an ellipsoid.
Just as one standard deviation distance away from the mean and
the scalar case defined the 68 percent confidence interval for x,
the ellipse in 2D defines the confidence interval.
The total probability inside the ellipse at
one standard deviation is not 68 percent in this case.
The total probability for a given length of
axis actually depends on the number of variables in the random vector.
But in 2D, 95 percent probability is captured by axis with length,
roughly five times the eigenvalues.