Now, I made reference earlier to the fact that if we have a multivariate distribution,
we can't just assume that we have
a probability distribution around each variable or field in the vector,
and operate with those separate probability distributions.
The reason for that is that a lot of the time,
knowing the value of one field in your vector tells you something about the other fields.
So for instance, if you have a vehicle that has a distribution over a state x, y, z,
knowing the altitude of the vehicle may tell you
something about the lateral position of the vehicle or vice versa.
You can't treat those probabilities separately and differently.
What that means is that we often have joint distributions,
where if our vector value is x,
then p of x is actually equal to the p of x1 and x2.
If x is equal to the vector x1 and x2.
This function p of x is a probability distribution over
these two variables that takes the vector as an input and outputs a scalar density.
But what if we only want to worry about the probability over x1?
Can we still use that joint distribution? The answer is yes.
We can compute what's called the marginal simply
by integrating x2 out of the density function.
If we have many variables in our vector,
we can just integrate out all the variables we don't want to get a
marginal over any subset of variables we do want.
Now, it might be the case that the system that
you're estimating has many more than two variables.
Your flying vehicle may have variables for x, y,
z, roll, pitch, yaw, that's six.
You may also have variables for the derivatives which takes it to 12.
You might also have variables that track what's happening in the environment.
So, if you're tracking other vehicles in the air,
then your joint estimator would be all of your 12 degrees of freedom,
plus the 12 variables,
the six degrees of freedom and the derivatives for all the other vehicles,
and that distribution is going to get unwieldy very very quickly.
But only some of the variables may actually have information about each other.
It might be the case that some of the random variables in the vector are independent.
Independence is the property that the joint probability density function is
really the product of individual densities of the component variables.
We can see the effect for a 2D Gaussian where,
if I have x1 and x2,
and if x1 and x2 are correlated,
then I may have a distribution which is kind of tilted up like so,
and you can see that if you have a positive x1,
then you're very likely to have a positive x2.
If you have a negative x1 you're very likely to have a negative x2.
On the other hand, if I have a spherical Gaussian like this,
then knowing where I am on the x1 axis,
tells me very little about where I might be on the x2 axis.
Really, this idea of independence is that knowing the value
of one variable has no effect on the other random variable,
and knowing the value of x1,
tells us nothing about x2.