So, how do we know if two variables are independent?
How can we tell if a random variable
such as whether the vehicle is working is independent
of whether the payload is working?
If the data are discrete and you have
a probability mass function also known as having categorical data,
then a chi-square test is a type of
statistical test that can be used to determine the degree to
which the differences between variables are due to
chance or if they're actually correlated in some way.
For flying cars, we're going to be dealing with continuous data more often.
And if the data are continuous we can examine what's known as the correlation.
Intuitively, correlation gives us some measure of how related two variables are.
Let's say we have two variables x_1 and x_2.
Now let's say we sample some distribution over these variables and plot those points.
In this case we would say the correlation between x_1 and x_2 is positive.
Since a large x_1 means x_2 is likely to be large as well.
Here, the correlation will be negative,
and here, the correlation would be zero.
This is knowledge of x_1 doesn't really say anything about x_2.
Now, that's fine for a qualitative understanding of whether the correlation is positive, negative, or zero.
But to precisely quantify the correlation,
we need a correlation function.
There are many different choices for correlation functions.
One common choice is the Pearson Product-Moment Correlation.
Which is equal to the covariance of x_1 and x_2,
divided by the standard deviations of x_1 and x_2,
and this gives the correlation between x_1 and x_2.
Now we can show that if the data are independent,
then the correlation is going to be equal to zero.
If we look at the co-variance of x_1 and x_2,
it's going to be equal to the expectation of x_1 minus mu x_1 times x_2 minus mu x_2.
It turns out that we can rewrite this as the expectation of x_1 times x_2,
minus the expectation of x_1 times the expectation of x_2.
If we know that x_1 and x_2 are independent,
then this is equal to the expectation of x_1 times the expectation of x_2,
minus the expectation of x_1 times expectation of x_2 again,
and that's going to be equal to zero.
As a result the correlation is going to be zero
divided by whatever the standard deviations are.
That's good. If the data are truly independent,
then the correlation will be zero.
That's a good test but we have to be very careful,
because uncorrelated does not always imply independence.
For example imagine that we had
two random variables y_1 and y_2 and they're constructed in
this funny way where they're actually functions of some other
random variable that itself is distributed from zero to two pi.
These variables are clearly not independent.
If you know one with high probability, you know the other.
It's easy to show the expected value of all these terms is equal to zero,
and the co-variance is equal to zero.
Which means that y_1 and y_2 are uncorrelated,
but they're clearly not independent.
So, why am I even describing correlation?
The answer is because for jointly Gaussian random variables x_1 and x_2,
we can show that if the correlation is zero then the variables are indeed independent.
It's a useful test just for this particular setting.
You've got to be careful though because x_1 and x_2 have to be jointly Gaussian.
It's also easy to construct an example where if
the marginal x_1 and the marginal x_2 are each Gaussian,
the co-variance will be zero even though they're clearly not independent.