Another useful property of
joint random variables is that it's often of extreme interest to find a density of one of
the unknown random variables given specific knowledge of other random variables.
For instance, is a vehicle moving given the current state of the propulsion system?
Written this way we have the Joint distribution p of x and y.
But we often want to know what's p of x given y?
And that is a conditional distribution.
A very useful rule and probability is that
p of x given y is equal to the joint divided by the
marginal of the conditioning variable that is p of x
given y is p of x and y divided by p of y.
This rule is called the chain rule.
A really useful application is
sometimes we want to reverse our conditional probabilities.
Recall our thought experiment of the autonomous UAV receiving GPS measurements.
Let's call the GPS measurements y,
and these measurements are noisy.
We could estimate our position x as a conditional probability using p of x given y.
And remember this can be read as the probability of position x,
given GPS measurements y.
If we've acquired a model of
the position probability density function
given a measurement then we have everything we need,
but it's often much easier to obtain
a model of the measurement distribution given a position,
p of y given x.
We can apply the chain rule twice to derive
an expression for p of x given y for p of y given x.
This is what is known as Bayes rule.
And Bayes rule in Bayesian estimation is
a foundational concept in estimations of statistics in general.
Bayesian techniques have enabled a huge amount of autonomy in a variety of ways.