So, how can we use Bayes' rule? Let's take a look.
For example, imagine that we don't know where our vehicle is,
but we have some knowledge about roughly where it is.
We'll call this a prior, maybe it's a Gaussian.
We know the vehicle position is distributed with some mean and some variance.
That variance can capture how well we think we know where the vehicle is.
Imagine that the position of our flying car is measured with GPS,
but the GPS is corrupted by guessing errors or noise.
We'll say that the measurement y equals x plus v,
where x is the true position of the vehicle,
v is the air added during measurement,
and y is the received measured value.
We can assume that the position is independent of the measurement noise,
which means x is independent of v. Can we
compute the distribution over the position given the measurement?
That is, can we find p of x given y?
Well, we can show from the chain rule the y is going to take this form,
and y given x is going to take that form,
but we don't want p of y or p of y given x,
we want to know p of x given y.
We can use Bayes rule to find it.
P of x given y,
is going to be equal to p of y given x times p of x divided by p of y,
and if I plug in normal distributions into this equation, I'm left with this.
This is the product of two normal distributions,
divided by a third normal distribution,
and with some algebra,
we can show that the product and division actually results in another Gaussian.
In fact, whenever we multiply a normal distribution by a different normal distribution,
the result is also a normal distribution.
In this case, the resulting normal distribution
has a new mean and variance which look like this,
and there's some interesting properties that result from this multiplication.
Notice that we're taking the measurement and essentially applying it as a correction to
the initial estimate mu of x. If sigma v is small compared to sigma x,
that means we have more trust in our measurement than in our initial estimate,
and that results in a new estimate which is centered very close to the measurement.
On the other hand, if we trust our prior a lot sigma x is small compared to sigma v,
then we wind up trusting our prior more than our new measurement,
and the updated position estimate only gets moved
slightly in the direction of the measurement.
And so sigma x and sigma v are
basically trading off how much we trust one quantity versus another.
That's a concept that we're going to see a lot throughout this estimation module.