For the rest of this lesson,
I want to introduce you to three approaches to estimation.
All three of these approaches will, in some sense,
solve the same problem,
but each will do so in a slightly different way.
The goal of estimation is to come up with an estimate for some unknown state.
We'll denote this unknown state by the vector x,
and for the estimate of the state, we'll use x^.
Note that these are both vectors.
For 2D quadrator moving in the vertical plane,
this would be y, and z,
and the roll angle phi, and the corresponding derivatives.
In the exercises is you see in this lesson,
these state vectors will be smaller,
and the examples we use won't necessarily relate directly to quadrotors.
Because for now, we want to focus on the math that
underlies the three approaches to estimation that we'll discuss.
So, how will we come up with this estimate x^?
What information will we have access to?
In each of these three approaches,
we'll have three things.
First, we'll have some measurement model,
H. A measurement model projects a state into measurement space.
Let's say we had our 2D quadrotor with some true state vector x.
It's at some vertical position z,
and it has a laser range finder pointing downwards.
If this were a perfect sensor,
it would measure a distance to the ground that's
equal to z divided by the cosine of phi.
In this case, the state's space was y and z of phi in the derivatives.
The measurement space, one dimensional,
and H is the function that maps a state to a measurement.
Next, we're going to get some measurements.
We represent a measurement with y.
And in each of these examples,
we'll consider making m measurements of the true state x,
where each measurement would be given by y equals H times x.
If these were perfect measurements. But they aren't.
Instead, each measurement will actually be y equals H times y plus v.
The v here is the measurement noise and that brings
us to the last thing we need to provide to our estimator.
Since the measurements are imperfect,
we need some model of this measurement noise v. Note that this
doesn't mean we'll know exactly how much noise gets added to each individual measurement,
that will still be unknown.
Rather, it means that we know the distribution from which this noise is sampled.
Generally, we're going to model v as a zero mean Gaussian or some co-variance r. So,
where a perfect rangefinder would make some perfect measurement H times x,
a realistic rangefinder would also add some zero mean Gaussian noise to each measurement.
The three approaches we'll discuss in the rest of this lesson are called,
least squares estimation, recursive estimation,
and non-linear least squares.
Each of these three approaches makes
slightly different assumptions about
the measurements and the underlying measurement model.
The least squares approach, for example,
requires that the measurements all come in all at once,
and it assumes that the measurement model H is n by m matrix,
which maps a state vector of length n,
to a measurement vector of m individual measurements.
Note that this means the measurement model must be linear,
which wouldn't have worked for example earlier with
the rangefinder since that measure model had a cosine in it.
These are some pretty unrealistic assumptions,
but this will be a useful starting point for discussing estimation.
With the recursive estimator,
measurements will come in one at a time.
The measurement model will still be linear,
but since measurements are coming in one at a time,
H will just be a vector, not a matrix,
and this vector will map a state to a single measurement.
The non-linear least squares estimator is also recursive,
which allows us to handle measurements coming in one at a time.
But in this case,
we'll allow the measurement model to be some arbitrary function of the underlying state.
One last point I'd like to make.
If you were to use any of these approaches to estimate the state of a real vehicle,
you'd have to make one more assumption.
The vehicle would have to be stationary for any of these approaches to work.
In the later lessons,
we'll see how we can use
the common filters and its variants called the extended common filter and the
unscented common filter to incorporate motion into our state estimation process.