If we're doing a thought experiment around estimating the state of a flying car,
the standard least squares approach to
estimation makes some pretty unrealistic assumptions.
It assumes the vehicle isn't moving,
that the measurements come in all at once,
and that the underlying measurement model is noisy but linear.
Remember, that a linear function of x,
which in this case maybe a vehicle position,
is one that can be written as a times x plus b for some known a and b.
Measurements of things like orientation are rarely
linear and we'll see in a bit how to overcome that assumption.
But despite these over-simplifications,
this estimation technique is common for calibration,
finding the transform between two coordinate systems or model fitting.
For now, we're going to consider a purely mathematical example of our thought experiment.
Let's consider a system where we make m measurements y of a constant vector x.
Such that y equals h times x plus v,
where x is the constant unknown state vector
of length n. This is the thing we're trying to estimate.
It's our quantity of interest and y tilde is the specific vector of measurements of
length m. I'm going to use the tilde here to denote the actual measurements I received.
The measurements are a linear function of the state
perturbed by some noise and that noise is not known.
It's the unknown error vector.
I'm going to assume the noise is drawn from
a Gaussian distribution with a zero mean and some covariance r,
which perhaps we can assume is some known variance times the identity matrix.
H is then the measurement matrix.
It's assumed to be constant and known
and it projects the state into the measurement space.
Now, if we knew what the error's viewer,
we could subtract them out and then that would just
leave y tilde minus v equals H times x,
and we could solve for x.
Or if we knew x,
we can solve for the errors.
Well, we don't know either of these,
that's what makes this an estimation problem.
What we're going to do is use a maximum likelihood estimation approach.
Intuitively, what we're going to do is look at our measurements and ask
what vehicle state is the most likely to yield this particular set of measurements.