We have our measurements and we want to know what vehicle state in
our thought experiment is most consistent with those measurements. How do we do that?
Mathematically, we're going to select our estimate x-hat to be
the value of x that maximizes the probability of our actual measurements y-tilde.
There are two steps to this process.
First, we're going to figure out what is the PDF,
the probability density function of p of y given x.
Remember, this function tells us the likelihood of the measurement y when the state is x.
We're next going to select our estimate x-hat to be the value that yields
a maximum likelihood of the actual measurements y-tilde given that estimate x-hat.
These two steps, let's look at them in turn.
First, we have to figure out what is the PDF,
the probability density function of p of y given x in this model.
We're going to assume that this distribution is Gaussian.
That means we need an expression for the parameters,
that is, the mean and the covariance.
Since y equals Hx plus v,
it's easy to show that the expected value,
the mean, y-bar is equal to H times x.
Given the properties or a noise model it's also easy to show that
the covariance y minus y-bar times y minus y-bar transpose
is going to be equal to the covariance of just the noise and that's equal to
R. We now actually know the parameters of this distribution p of y
given x for any x it's going to be
a normal distribution with a mean of H times x and covariance
R. We just need to find a value of x-hat that
maximizes the likelihood of the actual measurements y-tilde given x-hat.
How do we do this? Let's look at the full formula for this Gaussian.
Here, I've just written out the formula of the Gaussian.
Plugging in effect the mean is H times x and the covariance is R. We can
see this consists of a normalizer term here which does not depend on x at all.
For the likelihood of the received measurements of y-tilde given x,
the specific choice of x has no impact on this normalizer and we can ignore it.
If we want to maximize this overall function,
then what we actually care about is maximizing the term that's in the exponent here.
Which means we just need to maximize the function in the exponent.
A standard way to solve for the maximum of a function like
this is taking the derivative and finding where it is zero.
If we take the derivative of the exponent,
set it equal to zero, and then solve for x,
we get this term right here;
x-hat is equal to H transpose times h to
the power minus one times H transpose again times y-tilde.
And so, this is a solution to
the least squares estimation problem given some measurements
y-tilde that are linearly related to
some unknown quantity x by this matrix H that we assume that we know.
Using that, we can solve for the most likely estimate, x-hat.