We now have this equation for the maximum likelihood estimator x hat.
Which is x hat equals,
h transpose h to the power minus one,
times h transpose again times y tilde.
It's nice to see that the best estimate is purely a function of our measurement model h,
and the actual measurements y tilde.
Let's look at how this works in practice,
in this example we're going to fit some noisy data to a straight line,
and we can assume that we have the parameters of some line that we don't know,
which should be drawn like that.
The axes I'm going to call t since we're already using x for the state and y.
Which means that the true equation of this line is
y equals a times t plus b for sum a and sum b.
Let's assume that our data is sampled from the line with some added noise.
Well, what we're actually looking for the properties of this line,
what we actually want are a and our b,
a and b together are unknown state vector x.
We assume that our measurements y sub one, y sub two etc,
are drawn according to a linear function of y sub i,
which is equal to a times t sub i,
plus b plus v sub i.
It's this unknown v sub i that's perturbing the measurements from the line.
The measurements are in the form of y tilde equals h times x
plus v. We have all these measured values,
y tilde sub one up to y tilde sub m,
and we have our state vector x equals a and b.
In order to get the first vector to match up with the second vector,
we need an h that looks like this.
The first row is t sub one and one,
then the second row is t sub two and one all the way up to the last row t sub m and one.
Now the problem is solved,
we have our measurements, we have our h,
now we just need to apply our equation for
the maximum likelihood estimate and we'll find our best estimate for x.
An important thing to note is that once you have the measurements y tilde,
the least squares estimation problem boils down to
figuring out exactly what this measurement model h looks like.
Figuring out how to form h for any estimation problem is often the tricky bit.
Once you have that,
it's just a matter of carrying out the math to get the best estimate.