At this point, we figured out how we can take
a set of measurements that are linear function of
the unknown quantity to be estimated the state and solve it as a least squares problem,
but we had to make some assumptions.
Let's see if we can relax one of those assumptions.
Let's go back to our third experiment of a flying car
receiving measurements that are linear function of the state.
We're going to still assume that the vehicle is not moving and we're
going to assume the measurements are noisy but linear function of the position.
But now, let's allow the measurements to actually be received one at a time.
So, instead of coming up with an estimate all once,
we're going to think about maintaining an estimate,
and allowing new measurements to update that estimate.
Once again, we'll make m measurements y of our constant vector x,
such that y is equal to H times x plus v. In this equation,
x is again the constant unknown state vector of length n,
the thing we want to estimate,
y tilde is the vector of actual measurements received.
V is the unknown error vector and H is again
the measurement matrix assumed to be constant and known.
Let's assume that we now have a prior estimate of the vehicle position,
we're going to assume that it's given as
a Gaussian and it's going to have an initial estimate x naught,
with some co-variance Q naught.
I am going to use the subscript naught to denote the estimate before any measurement is
received and subscript one to denote the estimate after one measurement is received,
and will increment from there.
How can we actually use this prior in our estimation process?
We're going to do a very similar approach to
the two steps we did before maximum likelihood estimation.
Remember that with maximum likelihood estimation,
we first found the probability density function p of y given x,
and then we selected the x to be the value
that yielded the maximum likelihood of the measurements,
y tilde given that x hat.
The difference is that now we have a prior,
we can find the posterior estimate p of x, given y tilde.
The two steps of this new process are, one,
can we find the probability density function p of x given y?
Two, can we select x hat to be the value that
yields the maximum p of x hat, given y tilde?
The output of this recursive estimate is usually referred
to as the maximum A posteriori or MAP estimate.
We're taking our prior and turning it into a posterior using
new information from the new measurement. How do we do this?
Well, the first step is to find the PDF of p of x given y.
Remember, from Bayes rule applied to Gaussians that we can turn p of x given
y into p of y given x times p of x over p of y.
That's equal to some normalizer alpha times a normal distribution with
mean H times x and variance R. This is p of y given x,
we worked that out in the previous concepts.
We then multiply that by p of x which is our prior,
which remember is given to us as a normal distribution
with mean x hat naught and co-variance Q naught.
We can ignore the normalizer alpha just as we did in the maximum likelihood estimate,
the normalizer is not going to have any impact on the maximum.
The next thing is, we select x hat to be the value that
yields a maximum likelihood of p of x hat given y tilde.
If we look at the full formula for the product Gaussian,
we have two of the normalizers from the Gaussian here,
and then we actually have the product of the two exponents,
which when you take the product of exponents becomes the exponent of the sum.
Just as before, we see this expression consists of a normalizer term up front
which does not depend on x and an exponent that does depend on x.
We do the same thing that we did before which is,
we take the maximum of the function in
the exponent by taking the derivative and finding where it's zero.
The result for this maximum A posteriori estimate still a Gaussian,
but the Gaussian hasn't updated mean and covariance.
We first do a covariance update to get Q1,
and notice that it does depend on R even if we define
R to be a variance times the identity matrix,
and then we do an update to the mean based on this new covariance.
You can think of the maximum A posteriori estimate as a weighted average
between the prior x hat naught and what the new measurement says about x.
The weights come from the relative magnitude of the prior covariance, Q naught,
and the measurement covariance R. The more we trust the prior estimate,
the smaller the prior covariance and the less the measurements will affect the estimate.
The more we trust our measurements,
the smaller the measurement covariance and the more the
new measurements will change our current estimate.
As I've said once before and we'll say a few more times for this module,
that balance between prior information and
new information is the heart of the estimation process.