Welcome back.
At this point, you've learned how to plan paths for a flying vehicle,
and how to control a flying vehicle so it can actually fly along those paths.
That's right, but up until now,
we've made an assumption that we can't
make when we're working with a real flying vehicle.
We've assumed that we always know what the state of the vehicles is.
Exactly. For example, the controller you just
implemented was somehow able to use the vehicle state variables like X,
Y, and Z, in its control logic.
In reality, we never know the vehicle state with certainty.
It's something that has to be estimated.
So, in this lesson and the lessons that follow,
you'll learn how we can estimate the state of a flying vehicle.
And in the project that follows,
you'll implement your own estimator for a quadrotor.