Now, let's go back one more time to our thought experiment of a flying car in operation.
We want to infer the location of the vehicle from position measurements.
Say, some sort of GPS system.
We're going to still assume that the vehicle is still not moving.
The measurements are received one at a time,
we saw how to handle that in the previous concepts,
but now the measurements are noisy and nonlinear function of the position.
Maybe the measurements tell us something about the orientation.
Once again, we have a system where we make M measurements y of a constant vector x.
But now, y equals some function and h of x plus some additive noise.
Where x is the constant unknown state vector of length n,
again our quantity of interest.
y tilde is the vector of actually received measurements,
v is the unknown error vector,
the noise with zero mean and non-covariance.
Remember before we had a linear function which meant we
could write down the function as a matrix h times x,
but now we're going to say that h is
any measurement function with no constraints on it at all.
Beyond the fact that we know what the function is,
and that is not changing over time.
h is now problem,
you might not have realized it but in recursive estimation we were actually
projecting the measurement distribution into the same state space as the estimate.
We had our estimate x and p of x.
We had some distribution of measurements y and p of y.
And the mean of that distribution was given by h of x,
and the covariance was r. We could use
the linear matrix h to project
Gaussian distributions in the measurement space into the state space,
and the fact that the measurements were related by a linear function given
by h. Ensure that the projected distribution stayed Gaussian.
That meant that the weighted average posterior distribution was Gaussian as well.
But if h is an arbitrary function,
we have no guarantees at all that the projected distribution of y will stay Gaussian,
which makes it a lot harder to take a weighted average between
the prior x hat naught and what the new measurements are telling us.
So, we're left with a bit of a problem if
we want to preserve this Gaussian to Gaussian mapping,
we're going to need to find a way to make the measurement model linear.