So, what can we do?
A common thing to do when linear arising a nonlinear function,
is to take the Taylor series approximation.
The Taylor series approximation of H around
the estimate is approximately equal to h of x hat naught,
plus this matrix capital H,
evaluated at h naught times x minus x hat naught,
where capital Hx hat naught,
is the first derivative of h evaluated at x hat naught.
This should look similar to some of
the linearization you did in the previous module on controls.
Now if x and y are scalars,
then the first derivative is a scalar itself.
Hx naught is just a derivative,
but if x and y are vectors of length n and m respectively,
then you might remember from linear algebra that
the first derivative is a matrix called the jacobian.
Hx hat naught is equal to a matrix with
the individual partial derivative components in the various locations in the matrix.
Since we know both x hat naught and h,
we can compute that jacobian and the function evaluated at the prior mean,
which lets us rewrite all of this in a linear form A times x plus b,
which is the form we need for a cursive estimation to work.
As a result the maximum a posteriori algorithm is basically unchanged,
with just an extra step of linearization,
that is constructing the jacobian.
Our three steps are now: One,
construct the jacobian to get a linear approximation of h around the estimated state.
Two, compute the posterior covariance.
Three, compute the posterior mean estimate.
You now have the ability to take in a series of measurements of an unknown quantity,
where the measurements are non-linear function of the unknown quantity.
Assuming that you have gaussian noise being
injected into the system to perturb the measurements,
you can still recover a reasonable estimate.
This is exactly the process that's being used
inside your phone to figure out which orientation it's in.
Its exactly the process being used inside a drone to figure out altitude and position.
This non-linear least square estimation is
another idea that is very much core to the estimation process.
The one thing you might be seeing as well,
we made an assumption the vehicle is not moving.
In the next couple of lessons,
we're going to look at how specific sensors can plug into this formulation,
and we'll look at how to relax that last assumption
about the vehicle moving using something called the common filter.