In this module, we're going to look at the question of estimation.
There are several forms of the estimation question,
but the most basic is where is the vehicle,
what's its attitude and how fast is it going?
Answering these questions is often referred to as navigation or localization,
but there are other questions you could ask such as what is around the vehicle?
Estimation shows up in techniques called mapping
and slam which you may have seen in other courses.
Another question you might ask is,
well there are other vehicles in the sky, where are they?
How fast are they going? That is often referred to as tracking.
The same mathematical tools that tell us where a vehicle is,
what its altitude is and how fast it's going
can also be used to answer all of these questions as well.
You might say, well we have GPS and we've got sensors so why does this matter?
Why is it the slightest bit interesting?
And first of all GPS is a great tool for knowing where vehicles are,
but estimation is actually what makes GPS work and GPS itself is not perfect.
The other day, I was flying into Boston's Logan Airport and
the in-flight GPS suddenly put the plane
over the Atlantic and then quickly brought it back again.
That's really unlikely and a good estimator would know that it's probably
an erroneous GPS measurement and discard it or do something sensible with it.
Estimation underlies a huge number of technologies: flying
vehicles of all kinds from tiny drones to large aircraft rely on estimation.
The Apollo spacecraft for example,
was a huge success in terms of estimation,
and estimation also underpins a lot of
how your phone works in terms of
knowing how to orient the screen when you turn your phone.
What is at the core of the estimation question is really uncertainty.
The real world is fundamentally uncertain,
and it's uncertain in a couple of important ways,
one is that the world is stochastic.
The effect of actions can have uncertain outcomes,
the vehicle could be traveling a path you might
intend for the vehicle to follow this nominal path,
but it might get hit by a gust of wind and blown to one side or the other,
or the vehicle could be flying on some nominal path and suddenly stopped working.
That change in state is a source of uncertainty,
you never know when it's going to happen.
The second thing is there are things we might be uncertain
about in terms of the current state of the world: where is the vehicle?
What's behind that building over there?
We can't know where everything is in the world and the
way we describe this is to say that the world is partially observable.
Historically, there are lots of ways to quantify uncertainty.
Probability is generally the most common and the most powerful.
People have looked at using other things like
confidence scores or you may have heard of fuzzy logic,
but at the end of the day we're going to stick with probability.
That's because there's good sound theorems for example,
the Dutch Book theorem which says that probability is
the only rational way of representing uncertainty in making decisions.
Either, you are implicitly using the axioms of probability or
you're actually going to make a bad decision in terms
of estimating what the state of the world is.
We're going to talk about probabilities as the relative frequency of outcomes.
Let's dig in and remind ourselves of how probability works.