To begin talking about probability,
let's define some terms.
Let's say that there's a space of possible things that might happen.
For now, we're going to describe a discrete set of possible outcomes.
Before we dig into position estimation,
let's start very simply and just think
about whether the vehicle is working or not working.
Each of these we call an event or outcome,
and together they form our sample space.
We're going to assign to each one of these
some probability or relative likelihood of that outcome.
Let's say, we have a highly reliable vehicle with 0.9
probability of it working and 0.1 probability of it not working.
These numbers with the outcomes define a probability distribution.
To be a properly normalized probability distribution
the sum of these probabilities has to equal one.
We can in fact write this distribution as
a function that maps from the outcomes to numbers.
All probability function maps to numbers between zero and
one where zero probability means an event is guaranteed to not happen.
At a probability of one means an event is certain to happen.
When we have discrete outcomes we can call this function a probability mass function.
And if we have relative frequencies of things,
they may not be in the range zero to one,
but we can make the relative frequency sum to one by normalizing,
taking the sum and dividing.
Once we have a probability mass function
we can use it to answer a couple of questions such as,
what is the probability of some event or
outcome given that some other event or outcome occurred.
This is called conditional probability.
We can also sample from the space of possible outcomes,
and for some distributions we can ask what is the most likely event?
However, this particular representation where we write
down the names of the different outcomes is not as helpful as it might be.
If before working out the probabilities we first have a function that maps
each outcome to a number then we can ask and answer more questions.
So, let's say we have a set of outcomes, say,
working, not working, and let's add mostly working.
We can map them to the integer numbers zero, one, and two.
So, now we have this mapping of outcomes to integers and then the probabilities say,
0.9, 0.05 and 0.05.
This map of integers to relative frequencies or
probabilities is what's called a random variable.
We're going to use as notation the letter X to represent the random variable
which in this case, is this entire table of integer numbers.
X of I represents one entry in the table,
P of X represents the column of probabilities in
this table and then P of X of I would represent one entry in that column.
Now, that we have a random variable that maps events to
numbers we can perform computations over the events.