One calculation, we can perform with a random variable is called the expected value.
I can define this expected value here,
which you can see is a function of the components of the random variable.
It's the integer value of the random variable,
times the likelihood of each of those outcomes all summed together.
Now, the expected value of a random variable,
where the underlying events are
truly non-numeric quantities such as working or not working,
they may not be all that useful.
Let's say that we had working is zero, not working is one,
and mostly working is two,
the probabilities are 0.9, 0.05, 0.05.
If I compute the expected value of that variable x,
it's going to be equal to 0.15.
What that means is really unclear.
But imagine our sample spaces actually a numeric quantity,
such as the number of GPS satellites that a flying car can detect.
Our random variable looks like this,
with the number of satellites and probability.
If we compute the expected value over this random variable,
then you have the expected value of x is equal to the sum of p of x of i,
times x of i, which is going to be equal to 0.1 times one,
plus 0.1 times two, and so on.
That's going to be equal to three point 3.5,
and it tells us something about the number of satellites that we might
expect to see at any given time.