You can, in fact, compute lots of different functions of random variables,
but the expected value is one of
two very useful functions of random variables that we'll see a lot.
The expected value is often referred to as expectation, the mean,
the average, the first moment,
and it is exactly the quantity we had a second ago.
When we drop the i indices,
that quantity is the sum over all the outcomes of x times p of x.
I'm going to use x bar to represent the expected value of this random variable x.
Another useful quantity we'll compute a lot is the variance,
which is the sum of x minus x bar all squared times p of x.
The expected value is,
on any given draw from the distribution,
what is the value we expect to get?
Not the most likely, but the average value that we'd expect to
get if we were to continue drawing from this distribution over and over again.
The variance, sigma squared,
tells us how spread out these samples will be around the mean of x.
People sometimes use the variance as a measure of how well we know the mean,
something like a confidence.
It's important to understand it isn't that,
but it will tell us how much the samples vary.
You might also have heard of a quantity called the standard deviation,
where the standard deviation is a square root of the variance.