So far, we've discussed discrete events such as the number of visible GPS satellites,
or the state of the vehicle being working or not working.
What about continuous samples spaces,
such as the real value position of a satellite?
Random variables become extremely powerful in this case.
Using real numbers to index the members of a continuous set, it's fairly intuitive.
Let's first begin by defining a specific function called
the cumulative distribution function F sub x of u.
This function F sub x of u with a capital F,
describes the probability that the random variable x is less than or equal
to u. F will be monotonically increasing.
The limit as u goes to negative infinity is zero,
and the limit as u goes to a positive infinity is one.
This is the cumulative distribution function.
It's important to understand that the index to the function is u,
but its sub-scripted by x to indicate which random variable we're characterizing by
the probability that the value of that random variable is less than u or not.
Now, we can define lowercase f sub x of u,
which is equal to the derivative with respect to u of uppercase F sub x of u.
This is what we call a probability density function.
Since we are dealing with a continuous sample space,
we can no longer say anything about the probability
that our vehicle is at some specific or exact location,
because for a continuous sample space,
the probability of any particular value will always be zero.
We can only give the probability that our vehicle is in some region.
Consider this uniform probability density function for the position x of a vehicle.
As you can see, it has the value one half between x equals zero and two,
and zero everywhere else.
I could calculate the probability that the vehicles in this region between zero and one,
by calculating the area under this curve,
which would be one times one half.
In fact, the probability that a random variable will take a value between x1 and x2,
is just given by the integral of the probability density function from x1 to x2.
This lowercase f of x isn't the probability,
and it can easily be greater than one.
But we do often write this density function as p of x.
This changes our notion of what it means to be a proper distribution.
To be a proper density,
lowercase f sub x of u has to be greater than or equal to zero,
and the integral under the distribution has to be equal to one.
Normalization implies finding a constant multiplier in
front of this density function to make it integrate to one.