The uniform distribution that you just saw,
was parameterized by the parameters A and B.
In general, a probability distribution will typically be
parameterized by some small number of parameters.
We will use theta to collectively refer to all of
the parameters that describe a particular distribution.
One thing to emphasize is that P of X given theta is not
the same thing as saying the function that
describes the density of X is parameterized by theta.
This particular condition here P of X given theta,
implies theta is a random variable itself.
What can be the parameters of a density function?
Well, two common distributions are the Uniform,
and the Gaussian, or the normal.
The uniform has a couple different ways to parameterized it.
There is the A and B bounds you just saw,
or we could say that we have say a mean,
and we have a width, and this is mu minus w, mu plus w,
and the height of this distribution is one over two w,
the mean of this distribution is that mu,
and the standard deviation winds up being w over root three,
which makes the variance equal to w squared over three.
This distribution says all possible outcomes are equally likely,
and sometimes this is the only thing we can do when we have
no idea what the parametric family p of x actually is.
The other distribution that we'll see most of the time in this module is the Gaussian.
It's the familiar bell shaped curve,
centered at some mu,
with some width given by sigma.
The density function is given by p of x equals one,
divided by the square root of two pi,
sigma squared times e to the negative x minus mu all square over two sigma squared.
The Gaussian has a few interesting properties.
First, it's symmetric around the mean mu.
Second, the probability that x is within plus or minus one,
standard deviation of mu is 68 percent,
and the probability that it's within plus or minus three sigma is 99.7 percent.
Notice how sigma describes how wide the distribution is.
When sigma's small, that will make the peak narrow and sharp,
and this implies that we have a high confidence of
predicting what a sample drawn from x will be.
When sigma is large the Gaussian,
the normal distribution is very wide and flat,
and that means we have poor knowledge of what exactly
any given sample from this distribution is going to look like.
So, you can see that a continuous distribution like a Gaussian,
can actually be fully described by two parameters mu and sigma squared,
and taking together, these parameters are the theta for this distribution,
that I referenced earlier.
Solving estimation problems often boils down to using data often from sensors,
to come up with estimates for the values of these parameters.