One situation where we want to do
parameter estimation has been coming up with a model for a sensor.
Take a laser rangefinder.
If you mount a laser rangefinder exactly one meter from a wall,
and use it to measure the distance,
you probably won't get a measure distance of exactly one meter.
It will likely be slightly above, or slightly below.
But if you repeat this measurement many times,
you'll likely find that on average the sensor does
measure the correct distance plus or minus some error.
That error is also called sensor noise,
and it's often best modeled as a Gaussian random variable with some mean ideally zero,
and some standard deviation.
In order to use that sensor most effectively,
we need an accurate estimate of what the parameters of that distribution are.
We can't know the exact values of the parameters of a distribution given some data,
but we can compute estimates of the parameters in a variety of ways.
For example, a Gaussian is parameterized, as
we said a minute ago, by mu and sigma squared.
We'll write the estimates of these parameters as x_hat, and sigma_hat squared.
Now, let's imagine that I have some Gaussian that's generating samples from x,
and this is p of x, and we don't know mu, or sigma.
We repeatedly draw from this distribution to collect samples of data.
And you can see we'll likely get more data here near the mean,
and fewer samples out on the tails.
Using a technique called the method of moments,
it's easy to show that if we have samples x_1,
x_2 up to x_n,
then x_hat is equal to one over n,
sum from i equals one to n of x of i.
And sigma_hat squared is equal to one over n,
sum from i equals one to n of x_sub_i,
minus x_hat all squared.
It's quite convenient that the mean of the distribution matches the expected value,
and the variance of the distribution matches that variance.