So, now just to make your life a little bit messier,
we are going to go to a real drone,
and the real drone will have a seven dimensional state-space to load,
and the robot will now navigate in a 3D space, okay.
So, what this does to you is makes these matrices,
the [inaudible] matrices much, much more messy.
We're going to do Kalman filters, extended Kalman filter,
and then there's a technique called unscented Kalman filter,
which is my favorite technique. Why unscented?
Many years ago in Sydney, in Professor Durant Whyte's lab,
there were students that hated the unscented Kalman filter.
It's so hard to implement,
and it's smallest amount of error [inaudible] estimator.
This filter stinks.
They came up with a technique that's easier to
implement and works much better in practice,
and called it the unscented Kalman filter.
That's why it's called unscented.