Now that we've got prediction figured out,
we can move on to the measurement update step.
And this is going to require defining a measurement model h,
and then finding the jacobian h prime for each of our sensors.
So, let's go through our sensors.
We can start with GPS.
We get position and velocity from the GPS.
So, this z_t is the measurement you'd get.
And since we're directly measuring all of these state variables,
the measurement model is really straightforward,
and this means the jacobian looks like this.
The other sensor is the magnetometer.
And this gives us a measurement of the yaw angle psi.
Again the observation model is straightforward.
We just measure psi directly.
And the jacobian looks like this.
And these two sensors are all that you'll need to handle in the final project.
And since it turns out that everything is linear for these sensors,
the update step is especially straightforward.
But not all drones have GPS.
Some drones like the crazyfly for example,
use a camera and something called optical flow to measure the velocity of the vehicle.
The math for optical flow involves a lot of geometry,
but Nick is going to teach you more about that in the last lesson.
At this point you should have everything you need to
implement the update step for the 3D EKF.