Now that we know how to implement state estimation in 3D,
let's move on to the second part of this lesson where I will
introduce you to another variant of the Kalman Filter,
called the unscented Kalman filter before I do that,
let's do a quick recap of Kalman filters.
A Kalman filter is an optimal estimation algorithm that can be
used to estimate the state of a system that cannot be measured directly.
A Kalman filter is defined for a linear system with a linear state transition model,
and a linear measurement model.
But this is a very specific situation.
In general both the state-transition function
and the measurement function could be non-linear.
I want to demonstrate this difference with a picture.
The Kalman filter assumes a Gaussian distribution.
When the state transition function or the measurement function is linear,
and we pass the state into the transition function,
the distribution stays Gaussian,
even though the mean and covariance will have changed.
But when the transition function is non-linear,
the resulting distribution will not be Gaussian.
The extended Kalman filter handles this by first
linearizing the system around the mean of the current estimate,
then the EKF uses linear approximations of
the state transition and measurement functions to update its estimate.
So, this works well when the G or
H function can be well approximated by a linear function,
but there are some drawbacks to EKFs.
Consider what happens when the state transition function looks like this.
In this region, the function is not well represented by a linear approximation at all.
This is one situation where unscented Kalman filters are really useful