The Unscented Kalman Filter, or UKF,
doesn't try to have a linear approximation for the g or h function.
Instead, it approximates the probability distribution itself.
So, if this is our distribution,
a UKF would select a small set of weighted sample points such that the mean and
covariance of these weighted points is
equal to the mean and covariance of the distribution.
These special points are called sigma points.
The UKF propagates the small set of
weighted points through the non-linear g or h function.
Then we can calculate the mean and covariance of the transformed sigma points
and just use these empirical values as the mean and covariance of the new state estimate.
But, where do these special sigma points come from?
Naively, we might just say,
more points must be better,
and select as many points as we possibly can.
This brute force approach could work,
but it could be computationally prohibitive pretty quickly.
The real magic behind the UKF is what's called the Unscented Transform,
and the first step of the Unscented Transform is getting these special sigma points.