So, how do we get these special Sigma points?
We can't just symmetrically sample any points around the mean.
In order for the math underlying the UKF to work out,
we need to choose the right points.
In fact, if we have an N dimensional state space,
we're going to need to generate two times N plus one Sigma points.
The first Sigma point is just going to come from the mean.
If I were doing this in one dimension,
that would mean my first Sigma point is here.
Then my remaining two points might be at the mean plus
the standard deviation and the mean minus the standard deviation.
To calculate Sigma points in higher dimensions,
I first need to calculate S,
which is the square root of the covariance matrix.
Remember, this will be an N by N matrix.
So, this S matrix will have N rows.
I'm going to refer to row number I as S_i.
You can think of this like
a multidimensional version of a standard deviation in one dimension.
Now that I have S with rows given by S_i.
I'm going to get my Sigma points according to this math here.
This just says, I should take my first point to be
the mean and then I should sample N points like this,
where each point is sampled by stepping some distance away from the mean.
The size of that step is set by Gamma and
the direction is given by row I of the S matrix.
Of course, I also have to do something similar
in the opposite direction to make the sampling symmetric.
Eventually, we're going to use all of these Sigmas to try to recover the mean
and covariance of the samples once we
pass them through the measurement and transition models.
When we perform that averaging,
we aren't going to count all of the Sigma points equally.
Each one will have a weight we use for the mean calculation given by these equations.
Note here, the superscript N to denote that this weight is used for
the mean calculation and each Sigma point will
also have a separate weight associated with the covariance calculation.
We'll explain more about the details of
this math and some other parameters in the text below this video.