Just like all the other base filters,
the UKF has a predict and an update stop.
We're not going to do the full derivation of the UKF predict and update stops,
but it's worth walking through the steps at a high level.
Let's start with predict.
This is really just a couple of lines of pseudocode.
First, we convert the mean and covariance into
a set of sigma points which we're calling X of t minus one,
then we propagate each of these Sigma points forward in
time using our state-transition function g. Which leaves
us with transformed sigma points X_t
and these sigma points are what we return from the predict step.
Zooming out, it's helpful to just look at the inputs and outputs of the step.
As was the case with the KF and the EKF,
the UKF predict step takes as input a mean,
a covariance, and a controller input.
But unlike the KF and the EKF,
the UKF does not return an updated mean and covariance.
Instead, it returns this set of Sigma points.
Later during the measurement update,
will be able to convert these Sigma points into an updated mean and covariance.
The equation we use to recover the mean from the Sigma points looks like this,
and this is just a weighted average of each of the points.
The W_i is the weight of point i,
X_i is the actual point.
To get the updated covariance,
we'll use this equation.
This X minus mean times X minus mean transpose,
that's just how you calculate the sample covariance,
and that's going to be weighted by each samples weight.