The UKF update is a little more involved,
but let me just walk through the algorithm at a high level.
So, first note that the update function takes the sigma points as input,
along with the new measurement as we'd expect.
And the first thing we do is recover
the updated mean and the co-variance from these weighted sigma points.
Next, we take the sigma points and pass them through the observation function.
So, just like we pass the sigma points through the state transition function earlier,
now we pass them through the observation function and this gives us new sigma points.
And this basically gives us
an expected observation that's represented as the Z sub t sigma points.
Then, we can compute a mu_Z and sigma
Z of the sigma points that we passed through the observation function.
And we do this using the same technique that we use
to compute the mu bar and sigma bar before.
We just take the weighted sample mean and sample co-variance of the Z sigma points.
And we need one more thing,
which is the cross co-variance between
the state sigma points and the observation sigma points,
and this tells us how they vary with respect to each other.
And then we use this to calculate the Kalman gain.
And once we have the Kalman gain,
it is just like with a common filter.
We just use the mean that we got from
our predicted sigma points and then we add some correction in the direction of
the measurement and that correction is just the common gain
times our measurement Z sub t minus our predicted observation,
which is represented as the mean of those sigma points.
Then, we do something similar here to get the new updated co-variance,
and finally we can return our new mean and co-variance,
and then we just rinse and repeat,
and as with any other base filter,
we just alternate back and forth between
prediction and measurement, prediction and measurement.
Now, I want to talk about the trade offs between EKF's and UKF's.
For the EKF's, we had to take all these derivatives to compute the jacobian matrix.
For the UKF, no derivatives.
For this reason, the UKF is substantially easier to implement.
All we need is a G and an H function.
Not only is the UKF easier,
but the UKF almost always gives a better state estimate than the EKF,
and it does so in a comparable runtime.
So, given a choice,
you should almost always use a UKF if the system is at all gaussian.
Given that that's true,
why did we spent all that time covering EKFs?
And why are we asking you to implement an EKF for the final project?
The answer is that EKF's are the standard tool in
the field and you will certainly encounter them in your work.
So, we wanted to make sure you understood them completely,
but we're also aware of the UKF advantages over the EKF.