For the final project of this course,
you'll be implementing a 3D state estimation algorithm in C++.
In the first part of this lesson,
we discussed some of the decisions we made around how that 3D estimation will take place.
In particular we discussed how we would maintain
an estimate of all the vehicles 12 state variables,
and the decision we decided to use involved two filters.
One filter is called a complimentary filter,
and it uses direct measurements of pitch and
roll from the IMU to estimate the vehicles attitude.
This worked by balancing
the long-term liability of the accelerometers attitude measurement,
with the more responsive but drift-prone measurements
that come from the IMU's Rate Gyros.
The majority of the state estimation was handled by an extended Kalman filter.
This EKF was conceptually very similar to any other EKF,
though the Jacobians did get larger and more complicated.
In the second half of this lesson,
you learned about the unscented Kalman filter,
and you saw how the UKF handles non-linear g and h functions,
not by linearizing the frictions,
but instead by approximating the Gaussian distribution,
which represented the vehicle state.
The UKF makes this approximation by selecting
special samples from the distribution called "sigma points".
Once we had the sigma points,
we could do prediction for instance,
by simply passing these sigma points through the state transition function g. Then,
when we wanted to turn these predicted sigmas back into a Gaussian,
we simply calculated the mean and covariance of these sample points.
One thing I hope you take away from this lesson,
is that there are many ways to do state estimation,
and often there isn't a single best way.
In the rest of this course,
you'll learn a bit more about some of
the practical considerations associated with state estimation,
as well as some techniques for estimating state,
when you don't have access to GPS.