Welcome back. This lesson is going to be broken into two parts.
In the first part,
we're going to do a conceptual walk-through of
the 3D state estimator that you're going to implement in C++ for your final project.
As we do this, you'll also be implementing some of the logic in Python.
Once we've gone through 3D state estimation,
there's one more variant of the Kalman filter that I'm
going to show you called the unscented Kalman filter.
The unscented Kalman filter is
an even fancier math trick than the extended Kalman filter,
but it actually winds up being easier to implement than the EKF,
and it works better too.
But we'll get more into the EKF at the end of the lesson.
For now, let's focus on the moment we've all been waiting for,
implementing state estimation in three dimensions on a real drone.