At this point, I want to emphasize that there's more than one way
to do an EKF for a quad in three-dimensions.
Every approach has to make some trade-offs.
Even in the design of this course,
we had a lot of discussion about the best way to do it.
The approach we ultimately chose is one reasonable option,
but it's not the only option and it's also not necessarily the best option.
The option we chose is the result of trade-offs between
implementation complexity, explainability, and functionality.
The two choices I want to explain are our choice of EKF state vector and input.
Almost everything else is a consequence of these two decisions.
So, first our choice of EKF state vector.
What we're going to do is use something called a complimentary filter for attitude,
direct gyro measurements for the body rates and an EKF for position, velocity, and yeah.
So, our EKF state vector is going to look like this.
You could also choose to not put roll and pitch in the complimentary filter,
you could put it as part of the EKF state as well.
Then you could do all your estimation within EKF.
But if you had the full pose in the EKF,
then you would have something like a 15 or 16 dimensional-state vector and then 15 by 15,
or 16 by 16 Jacobians.
People do that, but it's a lot to keep track of and it gets hard to debug.
So, we chose something that's a little simpler for this course.
You won't get quite as good an estimate when you put attitude into a separate filter,
but it will still work for typical flight and it's a very common thing to do as well.