Next, I want to discuss our choice of control input.
Our control input is not going to be
the collective thrust and three moments that you worked with in the controls course.
Instead, we're going to be using the X, Y,
and Z accelerations as well as the R rate psi.
Considering what we chose to use as a state vector,
this makes some sense to use as a control input if we can.
But I want you to really look at this for a
second and think back to the controls course as you do.
Are we allowed to do this?
Can we just say we're going to use the acceleration and the R rate as our control input?
Remember, that the thing we get to control are the rotation rates of the propellers,
and these map directly to one collective thrust and three moments.
Shouldn't those be our control inputs?
The answer is yes we could and usually do
use the real control commands as the control vector in our estimator,
but we certainly don't have to do that.
So, how do we do this?
How do we use the accelerations and psi.
as a control input?
We're actually going to handle this using a weird trick.
These control inputs are actually going to come from the IMU measurements.
The accelerations will come from
the accelerometer on the inertial measurement unit, and psi.
will come from the Rate Gyro.
Now, the right thing to do would be to use the IMU for measurements since well,
it's a sensor, but many sources actually use the IMU as a control input.
One reason this is the case is that for lower cost terms,
the control commands don't always
accurately reflect the controls that actually get executed,
while the measurements made by the IMU actually do reflect reality.
So, because the IMU directly measures these accelerations,
and acceleration is in some sense
what you're controlling when you're moving the drone around,
we can justify using the IMU as our control input.
We could of course use the IMU as a measurement,
and use the commanded controls as the control input.
But the tradeoff is if you use the IMU as a measurement,
you have to put a lot more stuff into the state vector,
and those Jacobians get even bigger.
I encourage you to discuss this decision on the Slack channels,
and if you're feeling ambitious,
you can even try to implement an estimator using a different strategy on your own