As I said before,
we're going to be using something called a complimentary filter for attitude estimation.
So, we might as well get that out of the way first.
For a real quadrotor to fly in three-dimensions,
it's crucial that it have a really accurate estimate of it's attitude.
Small mistakes in roll and pitch estimates especially,
can lead to some really bad behaviour.
The basic idea behind
a complimentary filter is that we're going to use two measurements of attitude.
One, which comes from the accelerometer and a second,
which comes from the rate gyros.
Neither of these measurements alone can provide
a reliable and responsive attitude estimate.
But taken together, the two sensors compliment each other,
and we can get a good estimate of attitude.
The accelerometer measures attitude because it can tell you which way is down,
and that's because of gravity,
which we know always points down.
Then if the drone feels an acceleration vector which is inclined,
there's a good chance,
that means the drone itself isn't level.
We can use this to figure out the roll and the pitch.
Now, there are some caveats here,
but the key idea is that when we average the acceleration over long time scales,
It should point down,
and we can use that reference down to measure attitude.
Unfortunately, any individual accelerometer measurement is pretty noisy.
So, over long time scales,
the accelerometer is good,
but it's not very responsive to sudden changes in attitude.
The rate gyros on the other hand,
give really good measurement of the angular rates,
and these can be integrated to get the attitude.
These measurements aren't very noisy.
But since they get integrated they are susceptible to a drift over time.
So, this means the rate gyros are responsive,
but they aren't useful over long time scales.
So, we have accelerometer measurements that are good over long time scales,
and gyro measurements that are good over short time scales.
We want to combine these measurements intelligently so that we can have
an estimate of attitude that is both accurate and responsive.