Let's walk through the math that underlies the complimentary filter.
We assume the state acts that were tracking is the
vehicles pitch and roll angles: theta and phi.
We also assume that these angles stay close to zero.
The linear complimentary filter that we will implement will
not perform well when these angles stray far from zero,
though it's possible to adapt
a non-linear complimentary filter in a way that allows it to work for any attitude.
So, the measurements come as a measurement of
theta and phi from the accelerometer and a measurement of
theta-dot phi-dot from the gyros and these measurements come
with some frequency and we can denote the time between sensor measurements as T_S.
So, now we want to come up with an estimate for theta and
phi based on this measurement z sub t and the previous estimate at time t minus one.
To do that for theta we use the following algorithm.
Here, tau is a time constant and T_S is the filter sampling period.
Then this equation says that my new estimate is going to be equal to some coefficient,
tau over tau plus T_S and all of that times the old estimate plus theta-dot times T_S.
This multiplication of theta-dot times T_S is just an integration.
So, basically in this first term,
we're taking the old estimate and we're adding the change from the gyros.
And this measurement isn't very noisy,
but since we're performing an integration,
this estimate is susceptible to drift.
Then we have the second term.
And this is just this coefficient T_S over tau plus
T_S times the direct measurement that we get from the accelerometer.
And this is a much noisier estimate but it won't be susceptible to drift.
And the idea is that we're going to put a low-pass filter on
the noisy estimate and a high pass filter on the other estimate,
and this allows us to get the benefits of both approaches by using these two filters.
And note that this coefficient and this coefficient together sum to one.
So, we can tweak the behavior of the estimator by adjusting this time constant tau.
But in general this first coefficient will be big,
maybe 0.95 and this other coefficient will be smaller closer to 0.05.