Now that we have the complimentary filter implemented,
you should be able to estimate the roll and the pitch in the global frame.
So, we're just going to assume that's happening all the time,
and we just know roll and pitch now as a result of that estimation process.
Now, I like to walk through some of the actual EKF implementation details.
We'll be providing you with a document that goes over all of this in detail,
and you may find that more useful than listening to me explain everything,
but let's walk through that document as well.
So, here I am in the section called three dimensional quad.
Now, in the event that we make some changes to this document after I record this,
it's worth noting that some of the details of what you see here may change.
So, things like the section and equation numbers that you see in this video might change.
I also want to mention that there's a lot of math here,
and it's possible that there are some mistakes in the draft I'm recording with here.
If we find mistakes,
we will make sure to update the document that we distribute.
So, if you have any doubts just make sure you consult the document.
With that out of the way, let's dive in.
As I already mentioned,
we're representing the state at time t with these variables,
and the control input at time t with these variables.
This control input will be getting from the IMU which is weird, but it works.
Note the superscript B and all of these variables
which indicates that these are given in the body frame.
Since these are in the body frame,
we need a rotation matrix that converts from the body frame to the world or global frame,
and that should look pretty familiar.