Now, as always, to implement the predict step,
we need a state-transition function.
That G function looks like this,
and this is the portion of the prediction that's based on the previous state.
And here, we have the position updates and here are the velocity updates,
which incorporate the acceleration due to gravity.
Now, over here, we have the portion of the prediction that's based on the control input.
The notation I'm using here is meant to keep things a little cleaner.
So, when I write Rbg 0 colon,
that means that these three missing elements of
this matrix should be replaced with the first row of the rotation matrix.
So, this is just rotating the body-frame accelerations into the world frame.
The important thing to note here is that this
is exactly where our nonlinearities come in.
Because this rotation matrix contains non-linear functions of V, theta, and sin.
So, this one is just here to pluck out
the change in yaw angle given in the control input.
So, that's G. To do prediction,
we will need a G prime as well,
which means we have to take the Jacobian.
When we do that, we get a lot of zeros, which is good,
and we get ones along the diagonal and also some delta Ts.
The only tricky partial derivatives are here in these three elements of the Jacobian.
I want to point out that I didn't even take this derivative, I looked it up.
The math gets pretty messy,
but you wind up getting this matrix,
R prime, and the Jacobian winds up looking like this.
This notation is telling you to take the dot product of
the first row of R prime with the first three elements of the control vector.
So, with that, it should be possible to implement the predict step of the 3D EKF.