Welcome back. When you first get a new drone,
you're going to want to bring it outside and get it flying.
And in this lesson, which we're calling Backyard Flyer,
you will simulate doing exactly that.
Now, to simulate this experience,
you're going to be working with the same simulator
you'll be using throughout this program.
The drone you'll be controlling in this simulator
can actually be controlled with Python code.
And later, you'll be using C++ as well.
Now, the primary learning objective for this lesson is for you to understand at
a high level how this Python drone control code actually interacts with the simulator.
By the end of this lesson, you'll be able to write
code in what's called an event-driven paradigm,
and that code will actually control a drone to fly in whatever flight path you choose.