Now, before we continue,
I'd like to show you what the code you're
eventually going to write is actually going to do.
And here, I have a simulator window open and it's open next to a terminal.
In the actual interface you use it might actually look a little bit different,
but as you can see,
when I do an LS here,
you can see I have this file called backyard_flyer.py,
and that's the one you're going to complete at the end of this lesson.
And this file actually has code which controls this drone.
So let me just run that for you now without showing you what the actual code looks like.
So if I hit Enter, you can see what happens.
So the drone arms,
and it takes off,
goes forward, turns right,
then it goes backwards,
and to complete square,
it slides to the left,
stops in place, and lands.
Now, this square path that
this drone flew is not the interesting thing about this project,
though I do think it's pretty cool to see
the drone actually flying in the square that I programmed.
What's interesting about this project is the code,
and more specifically,
the programming paradigm behind the code that allowed all of this to happen.
And that is exactly what you're going to be learning in the rest of this lesson.