So let me show you one way you can interact with this drone with code.
So, I've already connected to this drone.
And, now, what I want to do is call this take_control method, drone.take_control.
And I'm about to do this,
so as I do pay attention to this little button here that says manual.
As you can see, taking control changes the command mode to guided.
Next, I can call drone.arm,
and before I do, pay attention to these rotors.
Because I called a drone.arm causes them to start spinning.
And, now, we're almost ready to do the really fun stuff,
which involves actually flying the drone.
So, let's take off to an altitude of five meters.
Sure enough, the drone flies up as expected.
I can use this command position method to
actually set a target position and the drone should fly there.
And now, let me fly back to where I started.
All right. This is starting to make commanding the drone look pretty easy.
And in fact, it is pretty easy.
Now remember, the final project for this lesson involves making a drone fly in a square.
Well, given this command position interface,
it seems like it should be pretty easy to do that.
And in fact, I've done it down here.
Here we define the coordinates of a square,
or the coordinates of the corners of a square, I should say.
And if we just loop through those corners then we can just
do a drone.cmd_position star corner.
Let's just run this to see if it works as expected.
Sure enough, it flies right.
Then it flies back. Now we're at 10, 10.
Then it flies left to 0, 10.
And back forwards to where it began at 0, 0.
So, great. Problem solved.
Final project over, onto the next lesson.
Right? Not quite.
Because there's actually a problem with structuring our drone code this way.
And to highlight what that problem really is,
I'm going to run this cell again and as I do,
I want you to now focus over here,
on the actual simulator,
but over here, on the code that's executing.
So let me run this cell. And here you see this asterisk up here,
and this asterisk is Jupyter Notebook's way of
saying this cell is currently executing code.
Now, the reason why I'm calling your attention to the fact that this cell is executing
code is because that means this code is all blocking code.
This drone is going to go in a square trajectory before it does anything else,
which is fine in a nice simulated environment.
But what about in the unpredictable, unknowable real world?
What if, when I execute this cell, shortly after,
another drone flew in the way of ours or something else happened?
The fact is, there's all sorts of unpredictable obstacles that could occur.
And when these things happen,
our drone needs to be able to respond dynamically,
and using this linear sequential style of programming just isn't going to cut it.
We're going to need a different way of thinking about our logic,
and that different way is called event driven program.