To help you understand how to write code within this event-driven paradigm,
I've written a really simple flight plan in a program called upanddown.py,
and I'm going to show you that code in just a second
but first I want to show you what that code does,
and the name I give it away.
But if I run upanddown.py you can see the rotor starts arm,
the drone takes off,
flies back down and then turns off.
Now, this is a very simple flight plan but
let's take a look at the event-driven code that actually caused it to happen.
So here is upanddown.py and as you can see it's just over 100 lines of
code which may seem kind of verbose for
how simple it is but this verbosity actually has a reason.
So let's talk about how this code works.
At the top you can see there's a lot of imports as is often the case with a Python file.
We can ignore those for now.
Likewise with this phases class we don't need to pay too much attention to it just yet,
though we will shortly and then there's this up and down
flyer class and it inherits from this drone super class.
This is Python notation for defining a class and saying what super class
is and this drone class is something that
we're providing for you and it's really pretty powerful.
It's got a lot of high level commands that allow you
to control the position of the drone,
it let's you set different way points and other sorts of high level commands like that.
You'll be using this class throughout the new node
but let's not worry about all that just
yet because for now I really want to focus on this initializer,
the constructor for the class.
And let me just walk through line by line really quick how this initializer works.
So first we call the super class initializer.
This is pretty standard.
Next we've got this boilerplate.
This target position is going to be used by the super class to
navigate to different way points and also there's
some logic checks in
the super class drone that only begin flying if the drone is declared to be in a mission.
So we need to set this to true.
Again I want to ignore this flight face stuff for now and really
focus on what's similar to
that chat barcode you just set which is this callback registration part.
And as you can see this looks almost identical to the chat barcode.
We're calling a function that's called register callback.
It takes a message as first argument and then a callback function as a second argument.
So what this line of code is saying is any time we
get a local position update from the autopilot we want to call
this function local position callback and we've got something similar
going on when we get local velocity updates or state updates.
So from a high level you can see this code is
actually pretty similar to the chat bar since during
initialization we just register
particular callback functions to certain events or messages.
Now I'm going to peek into this local position callback in just a second.
But first I want you to think about when
this function is called and what it's responsible for doing.
Since I'm registering this function to this local position update,
I'm going to be getting local position updates from the autopilot many times
a second and most of the actual way point following logic
is actually handled in the drone super class.
So what this function is responsible for doing is implementing any logic that's
particular to this particular flight plan going up and then going down.
Since going up requires going up until we reach a certain target altitude,
that's what I have to check for in this callback.
So let's see how that's implemented.
And as you can see
this flight face stuff is showing up again and this is probably starting to make
a little more sense now if the flight phase is
the takeoff phase or that's when we're performing this altitude check.
So the first thing that happens is this coordinate conversion and this is a little funny.
What's going on here is there are
two different coordinate systems that are trying to play
nicely together and for one of them the altitude and the z-axis goes up,
for positive and for the other one the z-axis goes down for positive.
So we're just making a little correction there.
And then the interesting logic happens down here where we're
checking to see if the altitude is greater than
95% of the target altitude and if it is we begin this landing transition.
And really this is sort of how we're going to think
about how flight works in this event-driven paradigm.
We've got these callbacks and depending on the state we're in,
we do some logic and then perform state transitions.
So hopefully this event-driven portion of the code is starting to make some sense.
The other thing that's important to understand about this code in which we are going
to be working with shortly is this idea of phases or states.
Once you get a sense for how these phases and these callback functions,
messages and transition functions all interact with each other you'll be able to start
implementing your own flight plans that
play nicely within this whole event-driven framework.
So now I'd like to look a little bit more into this phases class.