So, let's talk about one implementation of the Bayes filter called the Kalman filter.
And we're going to talk about the Kalman filter by using an example of a 1D drone.
And this drone is able to set it's acceleration
which will influence the vertical velocity and the height, z.
Let's start by defining the state variables for this system.
For this 1D drone,
when we ignore yaw,
the state variables are just z dot and z.
Then the control input for this system we can say is just z double dot.
Now, I'm also going to need a state transition function
which we call g. And this function's job is
to advance the state x of t to time t plus
one based on the system dynamics and the given control input.
So, the velocity updates like this,
x of t comma,
z dot is how I'm going to refer to
the z dot component of the state variable at time t. So,
this just says that the new velocity is
the old velocity plus the control input which is the acceleration times delta t.
Then the new position is just the previous position
plus the velocity times delta t. That's one way to write the transition function,
but we could also express this in matrix form like this.
Here, we have one matrix A sub t times
the state vector plus another matrix B sub t times the control input.
And usually, when you see
Kalman filter math you'll see it expressed in this matrix notation.
So, think back to the Bayes filter for a moment.
Remember, we had bel and bel bar that we were passing around.
Any of these beliefs could have been anything.
Now, with the Kalman filter we're insisting that beliefs must be Gaussian.
And that means that all we have to pass around is mu and
sigma where mu is the mean and sigma is the covariance.
Then we can manipulate this mean and
the covariance in the Kalman filters prediction and update steps.