When you look at the Kalman filter pseudo code,
the predict function looks like this.
Now, instead of taking some arbitrary belief,
it just takes the mean and covariance from
t minus one along with the current control input.
And because everything is Gaussian,
the integral from the base filter takes a nice closed form and I can compute
the new Gaussian by taking the old mean and
passing it through the state transition function we just defined.
And that gives us a new mean,
and to update the covariance,
I first have to use this g prime function to get this matrix G sub t. And then I
use this G sub t to transform
the old covariance and then here add what's called the Process noise.
So this Q term is why the new covariance is always going to be bigger after prediction.
Now that I've propagated my mean and covariance,
I can return those from prediction.
Before you try to implement this,
there's one more thing I want to say about this g prime function.
I choose to write the pseudo code this way,
because it makes the pseudo code for
the Kalman filter identical to the extended Kalman filter.
But really this is a bit of overkill when we're just doing Kalman filters.
When we talk about the EKF,
you'll see this g prime is actually what's called
the Jacobian of the state transition function;
which you can think of as the derivative of
the state transition function with respect to the state.
And for a Kalman filter,
where everything is linear,
remember we could break the state transition function
down into this A times x plus B times u.
So the derivative of this function with respect to x is actually
just this A matrix in the case of a Kalman filter.
So g prime will just look like this.
So even though in the pseudo code here says the g prime is a function of u and x,
it turns out that for the linear case,
g prime actually ignores these inputs and just returns that same A matrix every time.
That won't be the case when things become
non-linear and we switch to the extended Kalman Filter.