We can't just predict forever to get
the state estimate because the transition noise is always increasing.
And after each step,
it's going to get bigger and bigger and bigger.
If we had a perfect transition model with no noise,
then this wouldn't happen and we can just predict forever,
and we wouldn't need to make any measurements.
But in fact, there is noise,
so we do need to use measurements.
Just like we defined our state-transition function, g,
for the predict step,
we're going to need it to define a measurement model,
h, for the update step.
And this 1D drone has one sensor which is a range sensor pointing downwards,
which measures the height of the drone above the ground.
So what the measurement model does is it takes a state as
input and returns the measurement we'd expect to see from a perfect sensor.
So if we pass in a state which is z. and z,
then we want the measurement to just pick out the z value,
since that's what our ideal height sensor would do.
And the matrix that does this just looks like this.
And once again, everything is linear so I can write
the h function as this matrix C times x.
So now, we have our measurement model, h. Now,
if we go back to the pseudocode for the Bayes' Filter,
the measurement is incorporated in this update function where I
get my belief after prediction bel bar and I get my measurement z_sub_t.
And then, I use Bayes rule to incorporate the measurement with my predicted state.
For a Kalman filter,
which is just an implementation of a Bayes filter,
the measurement update looks a little different.