For a general Bayes filter,
the measurement update look like this.
But for calming filters,
the measurement update looks like this.
And once again, instead of passing around bel and bel bar,
we just use the mean and co-variance estimates from the predictions step.
What happens is, we use this h prime function to get some h of t matrix.
In the general non-linear case,
this will require taking the Jacobian of the measurement model.
But for now this will just wind up being the C matrix from our linear measurement model.
Then I use this H matrix in the next line to compute what's called the Kalman game.
The Kalman game is going to be used in the next step to dictate
how much we should trust our new measurement compared to our previous belief.
And calculating this Kalman game as a bunch of math,
but what it does is it takes
the old co-variance and transforms it using the measurement model,
and then adds the measurement noise,
R. Then I transform all of this math which
took place in the measurement space back into the state space,
and that gives me this Kalman game.
All of this math is what you get when you derive
the Bayes filter update step and you assume that everything is Gaussian.
It's a long derivation that we won't show here,
but the thing to take away is that this is
the mathematically correct way to get this Kalman game.
Now the next line is where we get our new mean MU or a new status estimate.
The new mean is just the old mean,
plus this Kalman game,
multiplied by the difference between the actual measurement,
and the measurement I would have expected based on my measurement model.
So, you can see this moves my estimate in the direction
of the new measurement by an amount that's dictated by the Kalman game.
Then finally, I compute
a new co-variance using some math that takes into account the Kalman game.
Then I return those update values and
those are my best possible estimate of the state after making a measurement.
So, hopefully from those equations and the measurement model,
you can implement the update stuff for the one D drone we've been discussing.
Once you've implemented predict and update,
you've basically implemented a Kalman filter.
In practice, these predicted update functions might be
callbacks that get called whenever you set a new control input,
or receive a new measurement from a sensor.