The Kalman Filter is the optimal algorithm for estimating the state of the one day drone.
And that's because in that case everything was linear and everything was Gaussian.
But well, we can often justify the Gaussian assumption.
The most interesting estimation problems are usually non-linear,
and the Kalman filter just won't work in those cases.
We need a different algorithm.
The first algorithm we're going to use to solve
non-linear estimation problems is the extended Kalman Filter,
and it turns out that the math can get pretty tricky with EKFs.
So, to try to avoid getting lost in the math,
we're going to be working with a very simple non-linear system,
and the system will be working with is pretty contrived but that's all right.
The drone we'll be working with will be
a two-dimensional drone similar to what you've seen in the controls course,
except this drone will be constrained in the vertical direction,
so it won't be allowed to go up or down.
That means the state of this drone is going to be given by its current role angle phi,
it's horizontal position Y and also Y dot.
And we're going to define a weird control input as well,
know how to simplify the math.
Instead of thinking of forces and moments,
we're just going to have one control input which lets us set phi directly.
So, we command some roll angle and the drone just teleports to that phi.
The thrust we assume is constant and equal to one as is the mass.
So, if we want to accelerate this vehicle to the right,
we set some roll angle that's tilted correctly,
and some portion of that thrust equal to
the sine of phi will cause the vehicle to accelerate.
So, just like we did with the Kalman Filter,
the first thing we need to do is define a transition function for this model.
This is a function that takes as input x of t, u sub of t,
and delta t, and it returns x of t plus 1,
and the transition function for this system looks like this.
The new phi is easy.
It's just whatever we set it to be,
and I'm going to call that u sub of t comma phi,
which means the phi component of the control input.
That might be a bit of overkill since that's the only component of the control input.
But it will make the math easier later if we stay consistent now.
Next, we update the velocity y dot,
and that just means we take the current y dot and we have to
subtract the sin of phi times delta t. And know
I'm not writing phi but x sub t comma phi
to emphasize that phi is part of the state vector x.
Then to update y, well,
that's just the current y plus y dot times delta t. Now,
x sub t is a three vector,
and g takes an x sub t and a u sub t and it also returns a three vector,
the new x sub t after you apply the control input.
Now, this is unlike the one D case.
In the one D case,
we could write g as a linear equation.
We could write it as an a sub t which was constant times x sub t plus b
sub t which was also constant times u sub t. But here we can't do that,
and the reason is because of this sine.
We can't factor this into a and b matrices that don't depend on the state.
And that means that we won't be able to use
a Kalman Filter as our estimation algorithm for this system.
If we want to use a Kalman Filter here,
we're going to have to work with a linear approximation of the system
that's linearized around whenever the current state of the vehicle is.