To perform this linearization,
we're going to have to take what's called the Jacobian of this function
g. And taking the Jacobian of g is like taking the derivative of this g,
which is a three vector with respect to x,
which is also a three vector.
And the result of doing this is going to be
a three by three matrix of partial derivatives.
The Jacobian tells us how each of the components of
g change as we change each of the components of the state vector.
Well, what do I mean by components?
Looking at x, it has a phi component,
a y dot component,
and a y component.
And I'm going to refer to these components as x sub phi,
x sub y dot,
and x sub y. G is similar.
It has a g sub phi,
a g sub y dot,
and a g sub y.
So, now we're going to lay out these components like this.
And this layout is going to tell us how to take
our partial derivatives in our three by three matrix.
So, here we have big brackets that we can
fill with the nine partial derivatives that make up this matrix.
In the top left I need to calculate the partial derivative of the phi component of g,
with respect to the phi component of x.
Then, here I would take the partial derivative of the phi component of g,
with respect to the y dot component of x.
When I got to the second row,
I start taking the derivative of the y dot component of g,
with respect to the state variables.
And the third row will involve taking the partial derivative of the y component of g,
with respect to all of the state variables.
So eventually, the matrix will look like this.
And remember what g and x are.
When you actually take these partial derivatives,
a lot of them will wind up being zero.
Two of them will be one.
This one will just be delta t. And this one,
the partial derivative of the y dot component of
g with respect to the phi component of x,
will actually be more interesting.
The y dot component of g looks like this.
And when I take the partial derivative with respect to phi,
I pretend every other variable is a constant and then I take the derivative.
So this first term,
x sub y dot,
will differentiate to zero.
And then, this minus sine term will differentiate to a minus cosine of
x sub v times delta t. So every time we call this g prime function,
we'll get back a three by three matrix like this.
And unlike with the linear case,
now this matrix changes depending on the state of the vehicle.
More specifically, this particular element of the matrix changes depending on phi.
And this Jacobian represents
the best linear approximation of the state transition function near the state x.
If we go back to the linear 1D example,
remember that we were able to write the transition function as Ax plus Bu,
because this function actually was linear.
In that case taking the derivative of g with
respect to x just leaves us with our A matrix,
and this A matrix doesn't actually depend on the state of the vehicle.
So looking at our pseudocode for the Kalman filter predict function in the 1D case,
this G sub t was constant and just equal to the A matrix.
So calling the g prime function wasn't very
interesting since that function actually ignored the current state of the vehicle.
But with the non-linear case,
we actually have to calculate the Jacobian every time we do this predict step.
And then use that result to propagate the covariance forward.
So, that's the predict step for an extended Kalman filter.