Before we can dive into the measurement update step,
we need to talk about this drones sensor.
So, here is our drone and remember it's only allowed to rotate and move left and right.
Over here we are going to imagine there is
a big vertical wall at some position wall sub y,
and this wall extends infinitely upwards and downwards.
We are going to give this drone a range sensor that
points to the right and measures the distance to this wall.
So, when the drones rule angle phi is equal to zero,
we'd expect this sensor to give us a measured value of wall sub y,
minus the drones y position, x of y.
If we let the drone rule to some angle phi,
then we'd expect the sensor to return some number that's bigger than wall sub y,
minus x sub y.
In fact, we'd expect it to return wall sub y,
minus x sub y,
divided by the cosine of phi,
and this is our measurement model.
This function h takes in a state as input,
and returns an expected value of what the sensor will read.
Keep in mind, this really does just return and expected value.
The sensor is of course noisy.
This measurement model is really useful.
Even though I said it takes the true state as input,
we could also pass it in estimate of the state and then figure out
what we expect the measurement to be based on our current estimate.
Now this h function has a cosine in it.
So, clearly, it's non-linear,
and that means that if we want to use the measurement model in an extended Kalman Filter,
we're going to have to linearise the model around the current state.