Now that we have this non-linear measurement model,
we can derive h prime which is the Jacobian of the measurement model.
Since our measurement model is just a one-by-one matrix,
this will be less involved than the Jacobian for the state transition function.
So the Jacobian will be the derivative of
the measurement model with respect to the state vector,
and that's going to give us a one one three matrix whose elements are,
the partial derivative of H with respect to the phi component of the state vector.
The partial derivative of H with respect to the y.component and the state vector,
and the partial derivative of H with respect to the y component of the state vector,
and when you do the math the Jacobian winds up looking like this.
So how does the measurement model H and its Jacobian h prime,
get used in the update step?
Here in the update function the first thing we do is
use h prime to generate the H sub t matrix.
Then we've got some messy math in the Kalman gain calculations,
and then when we update the mean we compare
the actual measurement Z to the expected measurement H of mu bar,
and this is all just like it was in the linear Kalman filter.
So now that you have H and h prime,
you should be able to implement the update step for this extended Kalman filter.