In this lesson, you will learn how to maintain
an accurate and responsive estimate of a vehicle state using
something called a Kalman Filter for
linear systems or an extended Kalman Filter for non-linear systems.
Both of these algorithms are implementations of
a more general algorithm called the Bayes Filter,
which uses a cycle of motion prediction and
measurement update steps to maintain a belief of a vehicle state.
The thing that made the KF and EKF special was
the assumption that our beliefs were described by Gaussian's.
With that assumption in place,
the mathematics of the base filter just turned into sequences of Matrix operations.
The difference between the KF and the EKF had
to do with the linearity of our motion and sensor models.
So for the one dimensional vertical drone,
our motion model and our sensor model were both linear functions of their inputs,
and because of that we could solve
the estimation problem optimally using a Kalman Filter.
But when we try to use a Kalman Filter on our weird 2D drone we ran into problems.
Both the motion model and the sensor model had non-linear terms in them,
which meant we couldn't write them as matrices.
The extended Kalman Filters solves this problem by calculating the Jacobian
of these models to linearize them around the current estimated state of the vehicle.
These linear approximations have to be made at every time stamp and when we do that,
we can treat this system as if it were linear.
In the next lesson,
we'll take the idea of state estimation into three dimensions,
and also learn about another variant of
the Kalman Filter called the unscented Kalman Filter.