Welcome back, I'd like to introduce you to
your instructor for the next two lessons, Stefanie Tellex.
Thanks, it's great to be here.
And it's great to have you here.
So, should we explain what this lesson is all about?
Yeah, well, so far in this course,
you've learned a lot about making measurements and
incorporating those measurements into your state estimator.
That's right. But up until this point,
we've had to assume that the vehicle wasn't moving,
and state estimation for a stationary vehicle just isn't that useful.
So in this lesson,
you'll learn how we can use something called a Kalman filter, and later,
an extended Kalman filter to incorporate
the controls we command the vehicle into our state estimator.