Think back to the controls course you took before.
In one of those lessons,
you learned about PID control in the context
of a drone moving only in the vertical direction.
The control code you wrote for PController,
for example, looked something like this.
And the thing I want you to notice about this code is what it took as input.
The z_target is something you would get from a trajectory planner,
but the z_actual was just passed in magically.
And in fact, z_actual isn't the best name for this parameter because in the real world,
sensors are noisy and we never really know z_actual.
A better name would be either z_measured,
though really, the best name would be z_estimated.
And earlier in this course,
Nick showed you some state estimation techniques but all
of them relied on the assumption that this vehicle wasn't moving.
And for obvious reasons,
that assumption just won't work for a real flying vehicle.
In this lesson, I'm going to show you how we can
estimate the state of a moving vehicle with
noisy sensor data using a technique called
the Kalman filter and then something called an extended Kalman filter.
We're going to use this example of a 1D drone for the first part of this lesson.
First, you're going to try controlling this drone directly using
the normally distributed measurements from
a noisy range sensor just like the one on this crazy fly.
Then, when the raw measurement data leads to some pretty crazy flight paths,
we're going to try implementing some other estimation techniques
using intuitive techniques and clever manipulation of the sensor data.
But we're going to find out that no matter how clever we are with the sensor data,
we just can't maintain a robust and responsive estimate of our vehicle state,
unless we also tell our estimator about
the controls that we're commanding to the vehicle.
In the second part of the lesson,
we'll talk about the Bayes Filter as a general framework
for thinking about state estimation for a moving vehicle,
and then dive into the Kalman filter as a specific implementation.
At the end of this lesson,
we'll discuss the extended Kalman filter as an improvement to the Kalman filter which can
handle non-linear systems like a drone that moves in two or three dimensions.