As you've seen earlier in this course,
sensors are not perfect.
And we can capture the imperfections in a sensor using something
called a measurement model which tells us p of z given x.
That is, the probability of making some measurement, for example,
with the rain sensor,
given a certain state,
for example, how far the drone really is above the ground.
And often, these measurement models are Gaussian.
The most likely measurement is centered around
the true value of whatever the sensor measures,
but there's some covariance as well.
In the next exercise,
you'll simulate noisy measurements and see what happens when you try to
use those noisy measurements directly to control a 1D drone.