You just saw that using noisy sensor measurements directly is a bad idea.
Even if the vehicle is at a target altitude,
a single noisy measurement might report a height that's way too high or way too low.
This leads to some pretty erratic control.
So, what we're going to do in this lesson, is something magical.
We're going to use these noisy measurements that are wrong,
to somehow get an estimate of the state of
the vehicle that winds up being really close to the truth.
The way we're going to do this is by exploiting two tricks.
The first trick is that we get to read the sensor lots and lots of times,
not just one time.
When we intelligently average lots of measurements,
we'll get a better estimate of our state.
The second trick is that we know what we've told the drone to
do and we can actually predict the effects of our control actions.
So when we tell the drone to accelerate upwards,
we can incorporate our knowledge of the vehicle's dynamics into
our estimate without having to wait for a sensor to give us new measurements.
But before we get to that,
let's just do a quick notation recap.
For now, we're going to think of time discretely and we're going to be using x of t to
represent the drone's true and unknowable state at timestep t. For a one day drone,
that will be the altitude and its rate of change,
and we're going to use z sub t to represent an observation or
the measurement that we get at timestep t. For the one the drone,
that would just be an altitude measurement that comes
from some range sensor that's pointed down at the ground.
To represent our estimate of the state at time t,
we're going to use x hats of t. The simplest thing we can do to get
a reasonable estimate from noisy data is to
just average all of the observations together.
In that case, x hat would just be the sum of all the t sensor measurements divided
by t. But we would like to not have to save all z's of t's.
The first problem with doing that is that our memory grows without
bound because we're going to have to save all the z's of t's.
The second problem is that the time this is going to take it's longer and longer,
the longer the drone has been running.