So, we want to avoid having to save
our entire history of sensor measurements to perform our update.
Luckily that's not so hard.
What we're going to do is transform this into a recursive update,
where we take our old x_hat and our new z_sub_t and use those to get a new x_hat,
and the equation looks like this.
We've replaced the history of t minus
one sensor measurements with a single number, their average.
And then we multiply that by t minus one,
and then add it in the new measurement and then we divide
by t. And this is so much better.
This approach respects something called the "Markov Assumption",
and basically that just means that our updated estimate
only depends on the current observation and the previous estimate.
It doesn't depend on
all the previous observations we used to come up with that previous estimate.
A lot of what we do in estimation,
is trying to get problems into
this Markov form so that we can exploit this computational advantage.
But unfortunately, even though this approach is computationally better,
when we try to use those we're going to run into another problem.
As t gets bigger new measurements are
going to cause the estimate to change less and less.
So this will be really bad for a drone that hovers in place for
a long time and then after a long time decides to move.
The motion will take a long time to get incorporated into the estimate.
We can attempt to address this by implementing an exponential moving average like this.
This would definitely make the vehicle more responsive to new measurements,
but it might suffer the same problems that you saw when using raw measurements.