So, with this exponential moving average,
we have to make this trade-off.
If we make alpha close to one,
then we trust our previous estimate much more than any new observation,
and this leads to an estimate that's pretty
robust against really bad measurements which we like,
and that leads to pretty smooth estimates of state,
which is good if the drone state actually is smooth.
But when the drone starts moving,
this breaks down and the estimate is slow to
respond to new measurements from the drone's new position.
So, large alpha is robust, but not responsive.
So, we can make alpha small and choose to believe our new measurements.
And with this approach,
we will see that changes in the drone state get quickly incorporated in the estimate,
but the estimate is really susceptible to getting tricked by bad measurements.
So, small alpha is responsive, but not robust.
Now, what I want is to have my cake and eat it, too,
I want an estimate that's fast and responsive,
but also still robust against bad sensor measurements.
And the way that we can achieve this is by
using something very general called a Bayes' Filter,
and the basic idea of the Bayes' Filter is that we're going to incorporate control input,
what I told the drone to do,
and sensor input, what I measured about the world.
And we're going to do this in the mathematically correct way
according to how we've defined our model of the system.