So, the idea behind the Bayes' Filter
is that we'll know where the drone is from two different sources.
First, we know what commands we send to the drone,
and we'll use that knowledge to predict the new state.
And of course, when we do that,
there's going to be some error in our prediction,
but we can still do something with that information.
And second, we still get to use the sensor measurements,
and of course, there's error in our sensor values.
But the fancy math trick will let us put these two pieces of information together in
the right way to get the robustness benefits of
averaging but also the responsiveness of fast updating.
The Bayes' Filter is a very general idea with many implementations.
So in this lesson,
we're going to discuss the Bayes' Filter first at a high level,
and then we're going to talk about one implementation called the Kalman Filter,
which is what happens when we represent everything as Gaussians.
And what happens is matrices.
Then, we'll dive into the extended Kalman Filter or EKF which is what
happens when everything is Gaussian but the state or observation models are non-linear.
And then, we can linearize around the state to make things Gaussian again,
and basically, use linearization to make things
Gaussian and then everything works out just like a Kalman Filter.
In the next lesson,
we'll also discuss the Unscented Kalman Filter or UKF.
And this is an even fancier math trick which is actually simpler to implement.
And with a UKF we estimate a non-linear state using special particles which we
can pass through a non-linear system instead
of linearizing the system like we do with the EKF.
In a later lesson,
Nick is actually going to cover another version of
the Bayes' Filter called the Particle Filter,
where we use particles or samples to
estimate a non-linear distribution which is not Gaussian.