So, there are all these different approaches to estimation,
and all of them are implementations of a Bayes filter.
The key idea behind all of these filters is if we know what we told the drone to do,
we can predict where it will be.
Then, we can use measurements from sensors and
incorporate those into our estimate in a way that's mathematically correct.
So, what we'll be doing in a Bayes filter,
any Bayes filter, is alternating between prediction and measurement.
In the prediction step,
I tell the filter what controls I can monitor to the drone
and use that to anticipate where the drone is likely to be.
In the measurement step,
I use actual observations of the world to correct that prediction,
and then I predict and then I update,
and I do this over and over.
If I do it correctly,
I'll be able to maintain a robust,
responsive and accurate estimate of the state of my vehicle.
The way this is going to work is our estimate is not going to be a point estimate.
It's going to have uncertainty.
It's going to be a distribution.
So, after we do the prediction step,
we're going to project where we think we are forward based on the control input.
But, we're going to assume that we don't have a perfect model of the system.
So, the uncertainty is actually going to increase at this step.
So, if we tell the drone to go up,
then the rotors are going to start turning faster and we
can have some idea of where the drone will wind up,
but that prediction will be noisy and will cause or belief to spread out.
Then, when we do the measurement,
we're going to incorporate information from the external world.
Even though this is noisy information,
it's still going to cause our uncertainty to go down.
So, let's look at the base filter algorithm.
Here, we assume we're at some timestamp t,
and we have some belief from the previous timestamp called bel of x_t-1.
The first thing we do is somehow use that previous belief to get a new control value u_t,
then we use that u_t to predict the state of the vehicle at
the next timestamp and then we call that bel-bar of x_t.
Then we get a new measurement z_t from our sensor,
and then we use that measurement along with bel-bar to update our belief.
For this general base filter,
the predict and update functions look like this.
So, in the predict function calculating bel-bar is an integral in general.
But depending on how you present bel and bel-bar,
this integral might take a closed form.
In particular, when the belief is Gaussian,
this takes the form of matrix operations over the mean and covariance matrix.
Then in the update step,
I take the state estimate after prediction and I
compute a new estimate that takes into account the observation.
This step really is just doing Bayes rule to
calculate a new distribution given the observation,
and it does that by multiplying p of z given x times the belief.
Something that's worth noticing is what each of these functions take as inputs.
The predict function only takes my previous belief and my new control,
and my update function only takes a belief and a measurement.
Because of the Markov property,
we don't need to remember all of our previous controls and measurements.
So, this has all been pretty high level.
Let's jump into the first implementation of the Bayes filter
that we're going to discuss and that is the common filter.