Welcome back. To understand how to control a fixed-wing aircraft,
we need a better understanding of
the underlying Physics than we needed when controlling a quadrotor.
If you think back to the controls module from the first term,
you might remember that our model of quadrotor Physics was pretty simple.
The model you used only considered two types of forces,
the weight of the quadrotor,
which I always pointed down in the global frame and the thrust from
each of the four propellers each of which always points up in the body frame.
What about fixed-wing vehicles?
Let's consider a plane flying in straight and level flight at constant speed.
This aircraft will experience a weight force from
gravity which points down in the global frame.
It will also experience a thrust force from
the propulsion system but this points
forward in the body frame of the aircraft instead of upwards.
But the thing that makes fixed-wing dynamics more complex than
quadrotor dynamics are the aerodynamic forces of lift and drag.
Drag is a force that points opposite the direction of motion of the vehicle.
For this plane traveling in straight and level flight,
drag would point directly behind the vehicle.
Lift is generated by the wing as it moves through the air.
For this aircraft, lift would point in this direction.
This lesson is all about understanding and modeling
these two forces but before we can build a model for these forces,
it will help to do a quick review of some of the relevant Physics.