To understand the motion of a fixed-wing vehicle,
we need to understand how it moves and rotates in all three dimensions.
But a complete 3D analysis of the forces can get very complicated very quickly.
To avoid this complexity,
we often split the four or 3-dimensional analysis
into two separate 2-dimensional problems,
the longitudinal motion and the lateral motion.
When we analyze the longitudinal motion,
we typically think of a picture like this where we view the vehicle from the side.
This is the picture we used in the previous quizzes.
It's also the picture we'll be using for the majority of this lesson as well as the next.
When we analyze a lateral motion,
we either look at the plane from above or from behind.
We'll be analyzing lateral dynamics in the lesson after the next lesson.
Each of these pictures is useful for
understanding various aspects of the vehicles motion.
For example, longitudinal analysis helps us understand how
the aircraft pitch changes over time
while lateral analysis helps us understand roll and yaw.