It'd be a lot easier if I had an actual model airplane to show you
some of the concepts I'm going to talk about today. Thanks plane fairy.
In some of the previous quizzes,
you saw a picture of a plane travelling forward at some constant speed,
and this picture is relatively easy to analyze.
Thrust points forwards, drag points backwards,
weight points down, and lift points up.
When I talk about this plane,
I can use words like up, down, forwards,
and backwards unambiguously since the axes of the body frame of
the aircraft point in the same direction as
the axes of the global or inertial frame of reference,
but that's not generally true.
To keep track of the dynamics of a fixed-wing aircraft,
we actually need multiple frames of reference.
When analyzing the longitudinal motion,
there are three frames that we'll discuss.
We can see the need for each of these reference frames by watching a plane as it lands.
Consider this plane as it approaches the runway to land.
Since it's descending, the velocity vector points forwards and downwards.
But, when we're analyzing the forces on a plane,
the velocity of the plane,
relative to the ground,
isn't nearly as important as the velocity of the air relative to the plane.
So, if it's a still day and there's zero wind,
then from the plane's point of view,
the airstream will be coming in the opposite direction, like this.
So, we'll call this V sub air.
Note that the aircraft itself will be generally pitched upwards.
The important thing to note here is that the direction of travel is
not the same as the direction that the nose is pointing.
Now, let's analyze the forces acting on this plane.
We're going to add four more arrows to this diagram.
Keep in mind that this arrow,
V sub air, is not a force.
It's just there to remind us what direction the air is moving relative to the plane.
For the first force, we have weight.
Weight is going to point in this direction since
gravity always points to the center of the Earth.
Next, we have drag.
Drag always points parallel to the relative airflow,
so it's going to point this way.
Next is thrust. The direction of thrust is determined by their propulsion system,
but generally it will be in the same direction that the nose of the plane is pointed in.
So, it might look something like this.
Finally, lift always points perpendicular to incoming airflow,
so it point in this direction.
Note that lift does not point normal to the surface of the wings.
Lift and drag are always at right angles to each other.
Now, hidden in these four force vectors and one velocity vector,
are actually three frames of reference that we need to keep track of
when analyzing the longitudinal dynamics of a fixed-wing vehicle.