So, what are these three hidden frames of reference?
First, we have the inertial frame of reference.
You might also see this referred to as the world or global frame.
This is just the Northeast down frame you've seen before.
The Z-axis of this frame is parallel to the gravity vector.
The X-axis points North and the Y-axis points East,
though we can't see it in this picture.
Next, we have the body frame.
The origin of this frame is at the center of mass of the vehicle.
The X-axis points out of the nose and the Z-axis points down through the fuselage.
As you can see, the thrust vector is aligned to the X-axis of this frame.
Finally, we have what's called the stability frame.
The stability frame is actually determined by the direction of this arrow which,
remember, is the velocity of the air relative to the plane.
In this example, we're imagining zero wind.
So, this vector is just the opposite of the plane's velocity vector,
but you could imagine,
that would change if there were wind.
As you can see, drag points in the negative X direction in the stability frame,
and lift points in the negative Z direction.
In addition to these three frames of reference,
there are three important angles that are used to relate these frames.
If we ignore the forces for a moment,
what we have is a plane pointed in this direction,
relative airflow coming in at this direction,
and that this line is horizontal in the inertial frame.
The angle between the body frame in horizontal in the inertial frame is Theta.
This is the pitch angle of the vehicle.
The angle between the airflow and the
horizontal is the flight path angle and it's labeled Gamma.
Finally, the angle between the airflow and the body frame is called the angle of attack,
and it's usually labeled Alpha.
These three angles are useful when you need to
rotate forces into different frames of reference.