Up until this point, we've been talking about thrust, weight,
lift, and drag, without really discussing where these forces come from.
Thrust and weight are forces that you should be familiar with.
Weight is just the mass of an object times the acceleration due to gravity.
Thrust is what we call the force generated by
a propulsion system like a propeller or a jet engine.
The details of how these propulsion systems work
are something we can safely ignore for our purposes,
so we can continue to take thrust as a given.
But we will need to know a bit more about lift and drag.
These forces are both aerodynamic forces,
which means they come from the relative motion between a body like a plane and the air.
Let's start with lift.
The key concept is what's called "dynamic pressure."
Dynamic pressure is the pressure caused by the motion of
a body like a wing through a fluid, like air.
Note that the body doesn't have to be a wing.
For example, imagine some rectangular block travelling to the left through the air.
As it moves, the air will exert a pressure everywhere on the block.
Now, some of that pressure comes from the fact
that the body is actually pushing on the air.
You felt this pressure if you've ever stuck your hand out of the window of a car,
but this only explains a small portion of how a wing generates lift.
Here, you can see the cross-section of a wing.
As a wing moves through the air,
there is smooth or what's called laminar flow over the top and the bottom of the wing.
Due to the shape of the wing,
the air will tend to flow faster over the top of the wing and slower over the bottom.
This faster flowing air has lower pressure
than the slower moving air on the bottom of the wing.
Since pressure is just a force exerted over an area,
lower pressure means less force.
So, this pressure differential between the top and bottom of
the wing means there's actually a net force that points upwards on the wing.
An important thing to note is that this method of generating lift relies on laminar flow,
but this laminar flow can be disrupted.
In general, it's easy to maintain laminar flow when
the angle of attack is low and when maneuvers are gentle.
But when the angle of attack increases beyond a certain threshold,
the flow can become separated from the wing.
In this case, the airflow over the top of the wing becomes
turbulent and the wings suddenly produces significantly less lift.
This is called "stall."
The mathematical models for lift that we discussed in this module
do not explicitly account for the critical stall angle,
but an autopilot would need to incorporate that angle into its control decisions.