We have a basic conceptual model for lift,
and now would like to know how to calculate lift.
The first thing we need to do is bring in
a concept called the non-dimensional coefficient.
Calculating the lift of a wing is computationally costly
and involves integrating the dynamic pressure over every point on the wing.
When people were designing wings in the 20th century,
it was really expensive to build those models and they needed a way to
avoid having to recreate the model for a wing in different conditions.
What you really want is a single number that could predict the force
produced under a range of conditions like the speed of the vehicle,
the density of air and the size of the wing.
Because you multiply that single number by the relevant dimensions so you get the force,
this number is called the non-dimensional coefficient of lift.
We are going to define the total lift force as L equals
C sub L Qbar S. S is the area of the wing.
That's something that we can calculate based on the geometry of our wing.
Qbar is the dynamic pressure,
and that is going to depend on the air speed and the air density.
Specifically, Q bar is 1.5 rho times V squared.
Rho here is the density of air,
and it's a function of altitude and temperature.
There are good models for air density that we can use to look this up.
V is the speed of the aircraft through the air,
and we can get this either from an air speed sensor or we can
estimate it using state estimation techniques from other sensors.
That just leaves the lift coefficient C sub L,
and this is typically a non-linear function of the angle of attack Alpha,
the pitch rate Q and the elevator deflection
delta E. This non-linear function is hard to model exactly.
So, we'll use a first order tailor series approximation to write
C sub L as C sub L naught plus C sub L
alpha times alpha plus C sub L delta E times delta
E. This first term is the coefficient of lift at zero angle of attack.
This next term is the lift slope and it tells us how lift changes with angle of attack.
This last term is the dimensionless control derivative and
it tells us how lift changes with elevator deflection.
Note that this model assumes low angles of attack,
small elevator deflection and zero pitch rate.
It's important to remember that every part of the aircraft generate some lift.
The fuselage and the horizontal tail generate lift, for example.
For small aircraft, we can generally ignore these contributions,
but for bigger flying car that's actually carrying people,
it would be better to model each of these separately.