The second major aerodynamic force acting on the vehicle is drag.
Drag always points parallel to the direction of airflow relative to the vehicle,
which means it acts to resist forward motion.
There are actually two forms of drag.
The first is called parasitic drag and this is
just the resistance the air puts up against any body moving through it.
The other form of drag is called lift induced drag.
Remember, that when a wing is producing lift
the incoming air flows over the top and bottom of the wing at different speeds.
When these flows are joined,
they tend to get deflected downwards,
this is called downwash.
So for this wing,
we have the relative airflow coming into the wind like this and
the effective relative airflow leaving the wing like this.
Now, we define lift to be
the aerodynamic force that's perpendicular to the relative airflow.
So, the lift in this case has to point like this,
but since the effective airflow that the wing sees
is actually rotated by this downwash angle,
the effective lift will also be rotated by the same amount.
This rotated effective lift vector has a component that points parallel to
the incoming relative airflow and that component is what we call lift induced drag.
So, when we model drag,
we'll model it as some non-dimensional coefficient,
times the dynamic pressure,
times the surface area of the wing.
This coefficient will be the sum of two other coefficients.
The first is the coefficient of parasitic drag
and the second is the coefficient of lift induced drag.
This second coefficient is itself a function of the lift coefficient we saw before.