At this point, we've developed a mathematical model for lift,
drag and pitching moment.
Each of these models has a coefficient associated with it.
It's important to remember that these equations are models of reality,
and these models are not perfect.
When we make models,
we want them to be accurate and simple.
Often, we make assumptions that may make
our model slightly less accurate in order to keep it simple.
For example, in reality,
these forces and moments also depend on a pitch rate of the vehicle,
which we've been representing with Q.
But this contribution is generally small for normal flight,
so we've ignored it in these models.
But what is normal flight for a fixed-wing aircraft?
With a few exceptions,
fixed-wing vehicles usually operate at or very near some sort of trim state.
A trim state is simply an equilibrium state where
the net force and net moment on the vehicle are zero.
One common trim state is straight and level flight.
This is flight where the vehicles flying in
a straight and level flight path at constant speed.
Straight means the vehicle isn't turning,
and level means it stays at constant altitude.
Note that the level in straight and level flight
doesn't refer to the orientation of the vehicle,
but to the fact that its altitude isn't changing.
Now we'd like to use our models to answer some questions about this trim state.
For example, if I want to fly at a certain velocity,
I might want to know how much thrust should the propulsion system provide?
What angle of attack should I try to fly at?
In general, the answer will not be zero.
What elevator deflection angle will I need?
We would like to answer these questions using a model that's
as simple as possible without sacrificing too much accuracy.
Let's consider the forces acting on an aircraft in straight and level flight.
There's the weight, lift, thrust, and drag.
Since this is a trim state,
the forces must balance in a horizontal or vertical direction.
This is fairly straightforward analysis.
The most important thing to remember is that we
need the lift force to match the weight force.
There is a vertical component of thrust that will help match the weight force,
but we won't be pitched by much, so let's ignore that.
For a level flight, that our pitch is the same as our angle of attack,
and that's where lift comes from.
We just need to pitch up enough to make sure our lift matches our weight.
But if we're pitched up, then we'll have a pitching moment too.
That will cause the vehicle to start rotating upwards,
increasing our angle of attack,
creating more lift and causing us to gain altitude.
To avoid that, we need to counteract the pitching moment with the elevator.
It might seem counter intuitive,
but in level flight will deflect the elevator downwards,
just enough to counteract the pitching moment of the positive angle of attack.
The elevator will also contribute to the lift,
but near this trim state the elevator deflection will be really small
and the contribution of this term will be negligible compared to the other terms.
That means, for this example,
we can ignore this terms impact on lift.
We'll walk through some of this math in more detail next.