We started this lesson by defining
the frames of reference for fixed-wing longitudinal motion.
We then looked at the four forces that act on fixed wing vehicles
and identified the relevant reference frame and axis for each force.
Of these four forces,
two of them were familiar: weight and thrust.
But, the two aerodynamic forces: lift and drag were just simple.
We came up with mathematical models for these forces and the pitching moment,
M. You were able to use these forces to solve for
trim states like straight level flight and climbing flight.
These trim states are really important.
At the end of this module,
you'll be asked to implement a controller for fixed-wing flight,
and a big part of that controller's job will be to identify
the appropriate term values for the propulsion system and the control surfaces.
In the next two lessons,
we'll come up with full mathematical models for fixed-wing dynamics.
First for longitudinal motion and then for lateral directional motion.
In the last lesson of this module,
you'll learn how to implement an autopilot for fixed-wing flight.