Welcome back and congratulations on completing the first term of the Nanodegree program.
Up until now, we've been focusing our attention on quadrotors.
A quadrotor is what's known as a rotary wing aircraft.
We call rotary wing because each of the propellers is
actually a wing which spins to the air to generate lift.
But as you know rotary wing vehicles aren't the only aircraft design,
there are also fixed-wing aircrafts,
like the one you see here.
This is footage from the fixed wing simulation environment that you'll be using soon.
As you can see, instead of using a motor to spin the blade,
a fixed wing vehicle uses its own velocity through the air to generate lift.
But there are other vehicle designs besides fixed-wing and rotary wing vehicles.
For example, there are vehicles like Cora.
Cora is made by Kitty Hawk and it's a hybrid fixed wing and rotary wing aircraft.
When we use the term flying car in this Nanodegree program,
we're generally referring to a hybrid vehicle like this.
A flying car like Cora has three important capabilities.
First, it's capable of VTOL or vertical takeoff and landing.
This means it can operate without needing a long runway to take off and land.
Second, it's capable of both rotary wing flight and fixed wing flight,
which comes with some benefits that we'll discuss shortly.
Third, a flying car has to be able to operate autonomously.
It's not practical or safe to ask everyone to become a pilot,
so a realistic flying car needs to be able to fly itself.
Implementing these three capabilities means solving
three main technical challenges on the software side.
One, autonomous flight and rotor craft mode this is something you can already do.
Two, autonomous flight in fixed wing mode.
This is what you'll be learning about in the next few lessons.
Three, how to transition from hover to fixed-wing flight.
This transition period is a very difficult,
and it's an open question on the best way to solve this problem.
We'll be focusing most of this lesson
and the lessons that follow on the second challenge.
How can we make a fixed wing vehicle fly autonomously.
But for now I'd like to talk a bit about some of
the many ways that people have tried to design hybrid vehicles.