In between pure rotary wing aircraft and
pure fixed-wing aircraft is a whole pile of
different hybrid aircraft that have the ability both to hover,
that is, generate lift without forward motion and also fly forward
using fixed-wing surfaces to generate lift aerodynamically from the forward motion.
The variation between these vehicles is almost always in how lift is generated in hover.
Some so-called tilt-wing aircraft rotate their entire wing.
But, this can be complicated and costly.
Other aircraft like the V-22 Osprey are called tiltrotors.
These vehicles keep their wings fixed in
a horizontal configuration and tilt only the rotors.
The Fairchild FZ3 takes an interesting approach.
This vehicle can tilt two-thirds of its wing downward like a flap.
This generates lift by redirecting the horizontal airflow from the propellers downwards.
Other vehicles, like the Harrier Jump Jet,
have what's called vectored thrust,
which allows the engines to direct the thrust downwards instead of backwards.
Other vehicles called tail-sitters take off and land in
a vertical configuration and then use
their control surfaces to pitch forward to go into aerodynamic flight.
The F-35B takes yet another approach.
It has a large fan in the center of
the vehicle which provides vertical thrust during take-off and landing.
Despite all of these different approaches to hybrid vehicle design,
only two hybrid vehicles are still in production,
the F-35B and the V-22 Osprey.
The Harrier is also still in operation,
but hasn't been manufactured for several years.
The main problem with all of these aircraft is that
they can be very difficult to control in transition,
that is, when they go from hover to aerodynamic flight and back again.
We're not going to try to solve this transition problem in this module.
Instead, we're going to focus on autonomous fixed-wing flight.