Before we jump into the details of fixed-wing dynamics and controls,
it's worth understanding the high level trade-offs
associated with fixed-wing versus rotary-wing aircraft design.
The reason why flying cars do use a hybrid design is because they really need to.
If you try to design a useful flying car with
a purely rotary-wing design or purely fixed-wing design,
you'll pretty quickly see some problems that will be hard to deal with.
We can highlight the strengths and weaknesses of
each design by playing around in simulation.
Here, you can see one obvious strength of rotary-wing aircraft vertical takeoff.
Along with vertical takeoff and landing,
a rotary-wing aircraft is much easier to control than a fixed-wing vehicle.
Here you can see it hovering in place,
which is something that a fixed-wing vehicle could never do.
This is really nice for navigation, planning, and safety.
The rotor craft have drawbacks for one thing they are very inefficient.
Even hovering in place requires using a good deal
of power to keep the rotors turning and generating lift.
This inefficiency drastically reduces the payload size,
range, and flight time of rotor craft.
Additionally, these vehicles tend to be pretty slow and quite noisy.
Finally, these vehicles have little to no capability when they lose power.
You can see that when I disarm the rotors,
bad things happen to the vehicle.
That brings us to fixed-wing vehicles.
One of the biggest drawbacks of fixed-wing flight is that
these vehicles need a long runway for takeoff.
Once a fixed wing vehicle gets in the air,
it has a lot of advantages though.
First, you can see that this vehicle is
moving a lot faster than the quad-rotor ever could.
In addition to being faster,
these vehicles are also much more efficient than rotor craft.
That's because instead of using a motor to spin its wings,
a fixed-wing vehicle uses its own motion through
the air to keep air flowing over the wing and generating lift.
This allows fixed-wing vehicles to carry much heavier payloads much longer distances.
This approach to generating lift also has other benefits.
For example, if the motor cuts out while you're flying,
the vehicle doesn't fall out of the sky and in
fact you can still do quite a bit to control it.