let's establish some basic vocabulary,
so we can refer to the pieces of a fixed wing aircraft.
When we worked with the quadrotor in term one,
we didn't spend a lot of time talking about the various pieces of the quadrotor.
It was enough to know that there were four rotors and we
can adjust the speed of each rotor to control the aircraft.
When it comes to fixed-wing aircraft,
there are a lot more mechanical pieces that affect
the dynamics and if you want to
write an autopilot to make the aircraft follow a trajectory.
It's important to know what these pieces are and what they do.
So, let's take a look at a fixed wing aircraft.
The biggest part of most vehicles, is the fuselage.
This is the main body of the aircraft.
Next, are the wings.
The wings have control surfaces in them,
such as ailerons and flaps.
Any movable bidder the aircraft which changes
the aerodynamic properties of the aircraft is called a control surface,
and we'll talk about these more in a little bit.
Then you may have more control surfaces in the back.
You may have a horizontal tail with elevators to control pitch,
and you may have a vertical tail with a rudder for yaw stability.
The horizontal tail and the vertical tail together are called the empennage.
Then we have our propulsion system.
In this case, the propulsion system is a single propeller at the front of the vehicle.
But you might also have multiple propellers,
in which case they would be on the wings.
When we have a single propeller at the front of the vehicle,
we call it attractor and when the propeller is in the back it's called the pusher.
Finally, we have landing gear.
Since this vehicle isn't capable of vertical takeoff and landing,
it needs wheels so it can roll along the ground.
If this were an amphibious aircraft,
then these might be pontoons or some combination of wheels and pontoons.
There are many other pieces of a fixed wing aircraft,
but this is all we really need to know for now.