We've looked at the components of a fixed-wing vehicle overall,
now, let's look more closely at the wing.
The wing is where most of our lift comes from.
So, we need to understand properties of the shape and
size of the wing to understand how much lift we are going to have.
When we discuss the shape of a wing,
we use words like platform, airfoil and camber.
The platform of the wing refers to the entire horizontal shape of the wing.
So, the platform is what we see when we look at the wing from above.
If we look at the cross-sectional shape of the wing,
then we're looking at the airfoil.
The airfoil refers to a slice through the wing at a particular point.
For a low speed ultralight aircraft,
the airfoil might look like this while the airfoil for an airliner might look like this.
We can quantify the shape of the airfoil by its camber.
The camber is essentially the curvature of
the upper surface of the wing relative to the bottom surface.
So, this wing on the top has more camber than the weighing on the bottom.
In addition to shape, we also want to discuss the size of a wing.
The wingspan is the distance from the tip of one wing to the tip of the other and
the semi span is the distance from
the center of the aircraft to the tip of one of the wings.
We typically use the letter B to represent wingspan and the letter S for semi span,
which means that S is equal to B over two.
The length from the leading edge of the wing to the trailing edge is called the chord.
The chord will usually vary in length as you travel along this semi span.
When the chord varies continuously,
it could be hard to do lift calculations.
So, we take an average which is known as the mean aerodynamic chord.
We usually represent the mean aerodynamic chord as C bar.
The aspect ratio is defined as the ratio of the semi span to the mean aerodynamic chord.
So, short wide wing will have a small aspect ratio while a long skinny wing,
will have a large aspect ratio.
There are various pros and cons associated with large versus small aspect ratios.
All of these terms become very important when you get into wing design.
Wing design isn't something we're going to get into in this curriculum,
but it's still important to be familiar with these terms.