If you've ever put your hand out the window while driving on a highway,
you already have some idea for how control surfaces in a fixed-wing vehicle work.
When you angle your hand upwards like this,
you can actually feel a force on your hand which pushes it upwards,
and when you angle your hand downwards,
you can feel a force which pushes it downwards.
Fixed-wing aircraft is typically equipped with three primary types of
control surfaces called the ailerons, elevators, and rudder.
These surfaces can be actuated by a pilot or an autopilot to control the roll,
pitch, and yaw of the vehicle.
If you look at our fixed wing simulator,
you can get a sense for how these work and the vertical tail,
you have the rudder and this controls the yaw of the vehicle.
When the rudder is deflected to the left that introduces
a rotational moment on the vehicle that causes it to yaw to the left.
The horizontal tail, you can see the elevators which control the pitch of the vehicle.
When the elevators are deflected downwards,
that causes the vehicle to pitch downwards as well.
At the end of each wing,
you can see the ailerons which control the roll of the vehicle.
The ailerons act anti symmetrically,
which means that when one ailerons deflects upwards,
the other deflects downwards.
So, to create a positive role,
positive around the body x-axis,
the ailerons on the right-wing deflects
downwards and the ailerons on the left-wing deflects upwards.
In addition to these primary control surfaces,
some aircraft will have additional control surfaces like flaps,
spoilers, slats, and rubrics.
We're not going to discuss these too much in this module,
but you can read more about these additional control surfaces below.