Fixed-wing and rotary wing aircraft each have their own strengths and weaknesses.
Building an effective flying car requires using
a hybrid design that takes advantage of the strengths of each.
Before you can design a hybrid vehicles,
it's important to first understand how purely fixed-wing vehicles work.
In this lesson, you were introduced to the various components of these vehicles.
In particular the wings and the various control surfaces.
In the next lesson, you'll learn about lift and
drag and how these aerodynamic forces influence fixed-wing flights.
In later lessons, you'll learn more about the Physics
which govern fixed-wing vehicles and how you can
actually control a fixed-wing vehicle by issuing
commands to the propulsion system and the control surfaces.