Let me talk about your eyes,
computer graphics, and computer vision.
Every robot, every human being,
every animal perceives its world through what's called sensors.
Your eyes are sensors. Your eyes
don't tell you whether your grandmother's in front of you.
Instead, it gives you maybe a set of receptive values or pixels of the surrounding scene.
And then your brain somehow is able to map into the state that you care about like,
am I facing my grandmother?
Same with robots. Robots have cameras.
They have magnetometers.
They have accelerometers.
These are all sensors.
And the estimation problem robots face is to understand,
what is a state given these measurements?
We're going to do this using Bayes' rule,
which you are familiar with, and here's the interesting insight.
In Bayes' rule, you care about P of X given Z.
Z is your measurement, your image,
and X is the state you care about like,
is my grandmother in front of me?
But Bayes' rule turns this around in the opposite.
Bayes' rule says, let's compute a P of Z given X.
Let's hypothesize, I'm facing my grandmother,
and then ask the question,
how likely is this image that I'm seeing right now under this hypothesis?
So in some sense, you solve the computer vision problem going from the image to
the state by implementing a computer graphics problem which is,
given the state, what is the likely image?
And the nice thing about this is,
the computer graphics problem is a physics problem.
It's a descriptive problem where sensors work.
So, all we have to do is we have to just model and
describe how sensors work in a forward way from
state to measurement and then we can use
Bayes' rule invert this for editing and come back to the state.