We talked a lot about rate gyros.
Now, let's talk about accelerometers and answer some very basic questions like,
how does an accelerometer work?
What does it measure?
You might be tempted to say that accelerometers measure acceleration,
but actually, they don't.
Think back to Newton's second law.
This law says that acceleration of a vehicle is equal to
one over the mass times the sum of all the forces acting on it.
Unfortunately, accelerometers don't measure
total acceleration, but specific acceleration,
and specific acceleration is the acceleration that's caused
by all the forces acting on the vehicle except for gravity.
To understand why that is the case,
we can look at a diagram for a simple accelerometer,
and this accelerometer consists of a proof mass that's attached
inside of some housing and constrained so that it can only move vertically.
Now, this proof mass is a attached between the top
and bottom of the housing with two springs.
And what the accelerometer is going to measure
is the difference between the upwards force
provided by the upper spring and the downwards force provided by the lower spring.
So when the accelerometer is sitting on the table,
we know the proof mass has zero acceleration.
To achieve this, the NET force from the springs on the accelerometer is going
to be upwards and equal to the m times g rate of the proof mass.
And because the springs have to provide a NET force upwards that's equal to m times g,
this accelerometer would measure a NET acceleration
upwards that's equal to g. On the other hand,
if the sensor were in free fall,
the housing and the proof mass would accelerate
downwards at 9.8 meters per second squared.
To keep the proof mass centered in the housing,
the two springs would be pulling equally so the NET force from the springs
would be zero and the accelerometer would measure zero acceleration.
So, this picture just shows one accelerometer.
A full three-axis accelerometer would need three of these in orthogonal directions,
and the output of a perfect three-axis accelerometer is
actually a measured a_accel that looks like this,
where this term is the total 3D force minus the force from gravity.
The accelerometers that we put on real drones are MEMS sensors,
but the physics underlying them is the same,
and this picture is still a helpful one to keep in mind when you try to
remember why accelerometers don't actually measure acceleration.