Even though accelerometers don't measure the true acceleration of a vehicle,
they are still incredibly useful.
I'd like to talk about two measurements that we can make with an accelerometer.
And for now, I'm going to assume that we are working for the perfect noise free
accelerometer that's attached directly to the center of mass of a vehicle.
So, what are the two measurements we can make?
First, we can use an accelerometer to measure the vehicles attitude.
Now we, can only do that correctly if
we assume there's no net force acting on the vehicle,
which means the vehicle isn't accelerating.
And remember, this is what an accelerometer measures.
If we assume that the net force is zero,
then that means that the accelerometer is actually measuring G directly.
So, A sub accel is going to be given by this equation,
but the measurements that we receive in the body frame are going to look like this,
and this equation just says that the measured components of
the accelerations equal to a rotation matrix times the gravity vector.
When we use ZYX all angles,
we can express the measured components of acceleration as
a function of the roll angle phi and the pitch theta.
If you solve these equations for theta and phi,
you get the following;
phi is just the inverse tangent of the measured Y over the measured set,
and theta is the inverse sign of the measured Y over G. Note that we can't measure
yaw is an accelerometer because
the gravity vector doesn't change when we change the yaw of the vehicle.
So, that gives you some idea of how we can measure attitude with an accelerometer.
The second thing we can measure with an accelerometer is acceleration*.
Now there's a big asterisk here,
because we can only measure the vehicle's acceleration when the body attitude is known.
And the reason is because we know the attitude,
we know the rotation matrix.
And when we know the rotation matrix,
we can write the acceleration of the vehicle like this.
And this equation gives the acceleration of the vehicle
in the body frame as the sum of the acceleration from
gravity plus the specific acceleration
from everything else as measured by the accelerometer.
And as you'd expect,
this acceleration can be integrated to get velocity in the body frame
and that velocity can again be integrated to get position in the body frame.
And whenever we want it to convert back to the old frame,
we just have to multiply by the rotation matrix again.