When we know the attitude of the vehicle we can use
the accelerometer measurements as measurements of the vehicle's acceleration.
But even if we only have an estimate of the vehicle's attitude we can still
use this estimate to convert accelerometer measurements into accelerations.
And luckily, we have a way to estimate the vehicle's attitude.
We can use the gyroscopes that we discussed earlier.
And this is the key idea behind what's called 3D inertial navigation.
First, we will use measurements from
the rate gyros to do dead-reckoning on the orientation.
And second, we will use the accelerometer measurements
to do dead-reckoning on the accelerations to get precision.
And each of these steps will be susceptible to drift
since each of these steps requires at least one integration.
And because of this, the arrows are going to grow with time which means
inertial navigation isn't a great approach to estimation on it's own.
But inertial navigation is a great complement to a position fixing navigation system like
GPS which has a low update rate but provides
drift-free corrections to the estimate you get from inertial navigation.
There's a good human analogy for both inertial navigation and position fixing.
Let's start with inertial navigation.
Right now, take a look around wherever you are sitting,
so that you've localized yourself in your environment.
Now, don't actually try this,
but I want you to imagine closing your eyes
and trying to navigate around this environment.
Initially, you'd have a very good estimate of value val.
But every time you took a step or turned,
you'd be able to update your belief,
but your uncertainty would grow just a bit.
This is analogous to pure inertial navigation.
And if you tried to only use inertial navigation as you wandered around an environment,
then eventually you're uncertainty would grow too
high and you would be lost and possibly run into a wall.
Now, imagine the rules changed a bit.
Imagine every five steps you were allowed to open your eyes.
This is similar to the position fixing you would get from a GPS measurement.
Because every time you open your eyes you would essentially use the new information
to correct the uncertainty you had
accumulated during the eyes-closed inertial navigation.
This example shows how slow but drift-free GPS measurements
can complement the faster but drift prone measurements you get from an IMU.