At this point, you've seen how noise can corrupt our sensor measurements.
But really there are several different sources of error which corrupt
our measurements and the best way to correct
these errors is by understanding where they come from.
So, with that in mind,
I want to show you a standard technical specification for an IMU sensor.
This is a real IMU spec sheet.
There's a lot here,
but I just want to walk through some of it.
The first thing to remember is that an IMU is a digital sensor.
This IMU happens to have a 16-bit resolution for the accelerometer and the gyroscope.
The maximum resolution for this IMU is given for the
chiral as degrees per second and for the accelerometer,
it's given in milli g's.
So, one milli g is one 1,000's of the acceleration due to gravity.
Then these next three are some of the most important numbers on the spec sheet.
This zero offset gives the bias of the sensors.
You can see for gyroscope the bias can be pretty big,
one degree per second can really add up and so we'll definitely need to correct for that.
Here we have TCO,
which stands for temperature calibration offset,
and you can see it's in units of milli g per Kelvin,
which makes this an acceleration per temperature.
So, this tells us how the bias of the sensor can actually change with temperature.
Then down here, we have the noise density,
and this has a funny unit of micro g's per square root of frequency.
To get the noise standard deviation,
this value is multiplied by the square root of
the cut-off frequency of
the low pass filter that you use to filter your measurement signal.
A good choice for that is 0.5 times the sampling rate.
So, if I had a sampling rate of 200 Hertz,
I'd have to multiply this number by 10,
the square root of 200 times 0.5 to get the noise standard deviation.
If I low-pass filter my signal more,
the noise goes down.
So, this datasheet already gives us some really interesting information.
We see that there's a bias,
there's also a temperature dependent bias,
and there's some random noise.