A typical sensor model looks like this,
and this says that the measured value of a sensor
comes from some bias plus this term here,
which is the identity matrix plus the scaling and cross-coupling matrix,
M. And that's multiplied by
the true value X and then there's always this additive component of random noise.
So these three terms, b, M,
and eta are the three primary sources of error.
First, there's the bias,
and you've seen that bias is just an offset in a measurement value.
And usually, we model bias as a random walk where the bias at
time t is equal to the bias at t minus one plus random noise.
And here, you can see some typical biases plotted over time.
And as you can see,
there's no real upwards or downwards pattern to these biases,
but they do generally tend to move away from zero.
Then, there's the scaling and cross-coupling matrix.
And if this is zero,
then we only have bias and noise.
But if it is non-zero,
then the diagonal terms indicate that there's a slope error.
So instead of measuring one,
I measure 1.1, and instead of measuring two, I measure 2.2.
The off-diagonal terms indicates some coupling.
So if this were a three-axis accelerometer,
this could indicate that the X accelerometer is actually influencing the Y accelerometer,
for example, or it might indicate that
there some misalignment between the sensor and the vehicle body coordinate frames.
Finally, there's also random noise,
and the key word here is random,
which means there's no correlation between past and future values.
And usually, this is assumed to be a zero mean Gaussian with some covariance sigma.