The easiest way to handle errors is by doing what's called, offline calibration.
Let's say I want to calibrate the accelerometers on this drone.
If I know this table is flat and I put my drone on it,
I would expect to see an accelerometer reading of 9.8 meters per second squared upwards.
If I look at the actual measurements and they say something different,
then I can introduce a correction,
and that would be offline calibration.
The other approach to calibration is online calibration,
and we have to use online calibration when the bias slowly changes in flight,
which is something that the IMUs are notorious for.
In online calibration, we actually add the bias into a vehicle state vector.
So instead of tracking the usual 12-state variables,
we might use a random work model and correct
the three additional accelerometer biases as well.
When we do offline calibration,
we generally need some calibration routine.
For example, remember when we looked at
the specs sheet and we saw the temperature calibration offset,
gyros and accelerometer biases have
a temperature dependent component that isn't a function of time.
To get the most out of an IMU,
we would like to know this function,
and the way we do that is with a pretty straightforward calibration routine.
So for this IMU,
we could just set it on a table with some known orientation and then
we can put it through a range of temperatures and observe the bias at each temperature.
Once we have our data,
we can use least-squares to fit a polynomial to the data,
and then we have a model of how temperature influences bias.