The next sensor I want to discuss is the compass or magnetometer.
The magnetometer is able to make measurements of
the vehicle's yaw when we know the vehicle's pitch and roll.
And this measurement of yaw is very noisy,
but it's free of drift,
which means we can fuse it with integrated gyro measurements much
like how we fused accelerometer data with gyro data to measure roll and pitch.
So the first question we need to answer is,
how does a magnetometer actually measure yaw?
The most high-level explanation goes something like this.
One, the Earth has a magnetic field that always points north.
Two, a magnetometer measures magnetic fields.
Three, if we know roll and pitch,
we can measure yaw by using the previous two facts along with a bit of math.
Facts one and two,
we're going to take for granted for our purposes.
If you're interested in learning more about
magnetic fields or the physics underlying magnetometers,
we'll include links to some additional content below this video.
To understand the math of step three,
you can think of looking at it from above.
So this is a bot pointing forward from this point of view,
and the Earth's magnetic field vector points like this.
And this vector is a three dimensional vector,
so it might be pointing towards the ground or away from the ground as well,
but we actually don't care about that.
What's important is that and in the x-y plane at least,
we know that the vector is pointing north.
So we can compare the vehicles forward direction to
magnetic north and we see that they differ by the amount psi,
which is equal to the yaw angle.
Now, the magnetometer that the vehicle has on board,
it's going to measure the x, y,
z components of the magnetic field vector in the vehicle's body frame,
so it will measure some x-component and some y-component and also some set component.
But since roll and pitch are zero in this case,
we don't have to care about that.
Now, you can see that the tangent of this yaw angle psi is
just the negative y component of the magnetic field divided by the x component.
So the yaw angle can be measured by just taking the arctan of these components.
This math was pretty straight forward only because we assumed roll and pitch were zero,
which let us ignore the set component of the measured field.
In the general case,
the math gets more complicated,
but conceptually, nothing really changes.
As long as you know roll and pitch,
you can use a magnetometer to measure yaw.