The magnetometer can be a tricky sensor to work with.
There are a few reasons why this is the case,
but by far the biggest challenge you'll have is magnetometers
will come from local distortions of the Earth magnetic field.
The reason this is such a problem is pretty intuitive.
If this quadrotor is flying along
and then it measures a magnetic field that points this way,
it's going to assume that this direction is north.
But this assumption isn't always correct,
and there are two main explanations for these distortions to the Earth magnetic field.
The first is magnetic material which may be
mounted on the quadrotor, near the magnetometer.
In this case, the additional material will add
some constant bias to every magnetic field measurement.
So, this can actually be handled pretty easily through calibration.
The second cause of these distortions is magnetic material in the environment.
Other vehicles, buildings, bridges, power lines,
these can all have a significant effect as well,
and can't be addressed through calibration.
That means you have to treat them as noise.
This makes magnetometer measurements really imprecise.
So how can we compensate for the systematic effects
that are constant with respect to the body frame?
For that, we can look at our standard sensor model with a bias,
a scaling matrix, and noise.
The standard calibration routine is pretty interesting.
Basically, we keep the sensor in
one location so we know that the magnetic field stays the same,
and then we turn it around a lot.
So, imagine the tip of this pen points in the direction of the Earth magnetic field.
Then what we do is we turn the vehicle in
all these different orientations and measure the magnetic field at each one.
Now from your perspective,
you see the quadrotor rotating when I do this.
But in the quadrotor frame,
the vehicle is stationary and it's the magnetic field vector that's rotating.
You can imagine the tip of this measured magnetic field vector should trace out
a perfect sphere if the magnetometer is working
correctly and if we cover enough orientations during calibration.
But instead of getting a sphere,
it turns out that what we actually measure is
some 3D ellipse which may not be centered at the origin.
It's a little easier to visualize this in two dimensions.
In 2D, we expect the magnetic fields to
trace out a circle instead of a sphere as we rotate.
We are going to normalize everything.
The magnitude of the magnetic field is not important here.
So, we expect this magnetic field circle to have a radius of one,
and it should be centered at the origin.
Now, let's imagine actually doing this calibration routine.
The magnetic field we measure may look something like this,
and this measured magnetic field clearly has bias since it isn't centered on the origin.
It also has some non-zero scaling matrix since it's too small and a bit stretched.
But that's fine, because that's the whole point of calibration.
After performing this routine and then doing
least scales to get the bias and the scaling matrix,
we would be able to transform our real measurements,
so that they match what we expected.