Let's talk about GPS.
If you ask me, GPS is one of
the most impressive technologies that humans have ever developed.
Think about it. Right now,
there is a system of satellites orbiting
20,000 kilometers above the surface of the earth.
On board of each of these satellites is a clock,
and each of these satellites constantly
broadcasts its clock time to the surface of the earth.
The system of satellites broadcasting clock times is
actually able to localize anyone at any position on
Earth to within a few meters of accuracy if
they have a GPS receiver and an unobstructed view of the sky.
That's pretty amazing.
At this point in the lesson,
I want to explain how GPS works and how we can take
advantage of this incredible technology to localize flying vehicles.
So, how does it work?
Well, GPS actually gives us
a direct and drift-free measurement of both position and velocity.
So let's start by discussing how we get position from GPS.
GPS uses something called trilateration to measure the position of a GPS receiver.
Trilateration requires a direct line of sight from
a GPS receiver to at least four satellites,
and it relies on the fact that we can measure the time of
flight from the transmitting satellite to the receiver.
To understand trilateration, it's easiest to think in two-dimensions first.
Imagine you have no idea where you are but you
do know the position of this single satellite.
If you know the time it takes a signal to get from the satellite to you,
then you can use the speed of flight to convert this time into a distance.
And this distance defines the radius of a circle around this satellite.
So with this one time of flight measurement,
you now know that your position must be somewhere on this circle.
Now, if we add a second satellite and measure the time of flight,
we'll get a second circle that intersects with the first circle at two points.
So now, you know that you must be either here or here.
A third satellite with a third measurement would give you
one more circle and then you would know with certainty exactly where you are.
In three dimensions, this changes slightly.
The first satellite would define a sphere of possible receiver locations.
The second satellite would add another sphere which,
taken together with the first one,
would give you a circle.
And then, the third satellite would give you
another sphere which intersected that circle in two points.
And actually, these two points are enough to locate you unambiguously,
because one of these points will be somewhere
near the surface of the Earth and the other will
be deep in space out past the orbital radius of the GPS satellites.
You might be tempted to think that this means we only
need three satellites to localize a receiver with GPS,
but we still need four.
The fourth satellite is used to correct for something called the clock error.