Trilateration relies on four distance measurements to
calculate the value of four unknown variables: the GPS receivers,
3D position, as well as its clock error.
When we measure the time of flight from a satellite to
a GPS receiver and then convert this to a distance,
we call the measurement a "pseudorange" measurement.
And the pseudo reflects that we have these clock errors.
Let's talk about what's called the Pseudorange Model.
The travel time for a GPS radio signal is
just the time of reception minus the time of transmission.
You can multiply that by the speed of light to get a distance Ps.
So T in this equation is the receiver clock time at reception,
Ts is the satellite clock time at transmission,
and c is the speed of light.
But the problem is that we have these clock errors,
so I'm actually going to write big T as lowercase t plus tau,
and big Ts as lowercase ts plus tau s. The
lowercase t's are the true receive and transmit times and the taus are the clock errors.
So, we can plug these equations into the pseudorange equation.
And we can do a little math.
And we see that the pseudorange is now the true range row
plus this other term which is the difference in clock errors times the speed of light.
So, this delta tau is something that we have
to estimate as well as the 3D position of the vehicle.
And this row is the true range of the vehicle which we could write like this.
And these terms represent the x, y,
and z positions of the satellite at the time of transmission, and these are known.
These terms are the x, y,
and z position of the receiver and they are unknown.
So, we have one equation here and it has four unknowns,
but we can generalize to multiple satellites like this.
And here, I'm using a notation where p1 is the pseudorange to the first satellite,
x y and z are for the unknown receiver location,
and tau is the receiver's clock error.
And we are assuming that the taus for each of the satellite clock errors is known.
So, now we have a system of four equations with four unknowns,
and this is a non-linear least squares problem that you could
solve using the techniques you have learned in the previous lesson