Welcome back, and welcome back Angela.
Thanks it's great to be here.
As you can tell this course is going to be jointly taught by Nick,
Angela and in the next lesson,
you'll need a third instructor Stephanie.
So, what are we going to learn in this lesson Angela?
This lesson is all about sensors and how a flying vehicle
uses imperfect but complimentary sensors like accelerometers,
rate gyros and GPS to accurately estimate where it is in the rock.
Right. Because up until now,
it's been pretty easy to forget about sensors when you're working in
a simulated environment where you just assume perfect knowledge of your vehicle.
That's right, but then you start working on real flying vehicles,
you are going to find that sensors are impossible to ignore.