In addition to giving us direct measurements of position,
GPS also gives us direct measurements of velocity.
I want to emphasize that these measurements really are direct.
They don't come from differentiation of two subsequent position measurements.
Instead, the velocity measurements we get from GPS
come from the Doppler shift of the received carrier frequencies.
I'm not going to talk about the Doppler effect here,
but I do want to mention just how accurate these measurements are.
In the horizontal x, y plane,
the velocity measurements have an accuracy of about 2-5 centimeters per second.
In the vertical direction the accuracies are within about 4-10 centimeters per second.
That's really pretty accurate.
It's really useful as a complement to accelerometers.
The position measurements that we get from GPS are accurate to
within about 5-10 meters which is also pretty amazing.
But where do these errors come from?
One source is atmospheric effects in the ionosphere,
where free electrons interfere with the transmitted signal
and corrupt the measurement by changing the signal travel time.
Then there's clock error.
If a satellite's clock is off by one nanosecond,
that translates into an error in position of about one foot or 30 centimeters.
There's also what's called multipath errors.
So, you can imagine if you're standing here,
then there might be some straight line path to a GPS satellite.
But there's other routes that the signal could take.
It might bounce off of a tall building and then into your receiver,
or it might bounce off the ground.
In either case, the measured distance would increase
substantially and this could lead to sudden jumps in your measure position.
You can correct for this by comparing
your GPS measurements to your estimate and looking for outliers.
If a new GPS measurement is outside of the three sigma bounds of your estimate,
then it's really unlikely to be correct.
There's one last thing to mention;
the process of GPS initialization.
Something you may have noticed when using GPS on your smart phone is that
sometimes it can take a while for your phone to get a GPS location fix.
This is also an issue for drones.
When you turn on your drone,
you usually want to use it right away,
but sometimes we have to wait for the GPS fix.
The reason we have to wait is because it takes some time for
a GPS receiver to actually find the signals from the satellites.
That's because the GPS signal strength is pretty weak,
and it takes some clever algorithms and a bit of time to actually identify the signals.