We've talked about several sensors in this lesson,
and the sensors we've discussed are likely to show up on just about any flying vehicle.
They are all relatively small, low-cost,
and ultimately really useful for state estimation.
When we use these sensors together,
we can get really accurate estimates of our vehicle state.
For example, we can fuse
the fast but drift-prone measurements that we get from an accelerometer,
with the slower but drift-free measurements we get from
GPS to make really accurate estimates about the vehicle's position.
But I don't want you to leave this lesson thinking
the sensor problem is solved, it is not.
For example, flying car companies are currently struggling with questions like,
how can we safely and consistently land an autonomous vehicle?
Or how can we do what's called the see and avoid flight?
And this is something that has to be solved before we can
substantially increase the density of flying vehicles in the air.
It's not at all clear what the solution to
these problems will be or even what sensors will be involved,
but likely, they will require sensors that we haven't even discussed in this lesson,
like stereo cameras, lidar, and radar.
So, when you start working in this field,
be prepared to analyze the pros and cons of
the latest sensors as you choose which is the best for your particular vehicle design.