Why is it important to have multiple sources of measurement?
Because none of them is perfect.
Compare the accelerometer to the GPS, for instance.
Each of these sensors can be used to get information about the position of the vehicle.
The GPS makes position measurements directly,
and the accelerometer can be integrated to get position.
So the question is,
why do we need both?
One important reason is because different sensors are accurate in different ways.
The accelerometer, for example,
gives us a really smooth idea of where are,
and that's because accelerometers are
constantly running at a really high rate with no drop outs.
So we can integrate those measurements to track our position.
The GPS isn't as smooth.
The measurements come at a much lower rate,
and they are susceptible to sudden jumps,
which can happen if we lose track of one of the satellites, for example.
We like that the accelerometer is smooth and low noise in the short term.
But it's susceptible to drift errors which grow with time.
So, if we had these measurements here,
the true trajectory might have actually looked something like this.
The GPS, on the other hand,
provides an external positional reference which doesn't drift.
So, even so these points are noisy,
they are at least generally centered on the true path of the vehicle,
which means we can use GPS measurements to help correct drift from the accelerometer.
So, you can see just from this high level view that GPS and
accelerometers can complement each other when measuring position,
and this is just one way that sensors can complement each other.
Later, you'll see how we can also balance the trade-offs of
accelerometers against gyros to get an accurate estimate of altitude.
The three main goals of this lesson are: one,
combine sensor measurements from different sensors
on board a flying vehicle to estimate the vehicle state.
You'll do this by using your knowledge of what these sensors
measure and their accuracy to derive measurement models for estimation,
and that's the second goal.
The measurement models that you derive will wind up
being crucial to the overall estimation of vehicle state.
Finally, you will learn how to use sensor calibration and
initialization to improve the quality of the measurements your sensors make.
In the next lesson, you will learn how to use
the measurement models that you derive here along with
a model of the vehicle in motion to maintain
a robust and responsive estimate of the vehicle state.
For the rest of this lesson,
you're going to go sensor by sensor to learn how each one works and what it measures.
Then we'll discuss how we can model the noise associated with each sensors,
because no sensor is perfect,
and then we'll discuss how we can reduce this noise by
designing the right initialization and calibration routines for each sensor.