A gyroscope measures the angular rotation about
a particular axis by measuring something called the Coriolis Force.
The Coriolis Force is something that shows up when
you try to do physics in a rotating frame of reference.
We are not going to get into the math behind this force,
but we can try to understand it intuitively.
Imagine you are looking from above at
a big spinning disk that's rotating with some angular velocity Omega.
You can think of it like a merry-go-round.
Now, what would happen if someone's standing in the middle of this disc
tried to throw a ball at the triangular target shown here?
Well, the ball doesn't care that the disk is rotating.
So of course it would move in
a straight line and by the time it got to the edge of the disk,
the target would have rotated far away from where it originally was.
This picture of the motion is from the world frame,
which is an inertial frame.
In this frame, there is no Coriolis Force.
But what happens when we transition into a rotating frame?
Imagine that you were standing on
the triangular target and someone threw the ball towards you.
From your point of view,
the ball wouldn't move in a straight line.
Instead, you'd see the ball take the strange curved paths.
In this rotating frame of reference,
you would think the ball were being pushed sideways by some force,
and that force is the Coriolis Force.
So, we can call it FC.
In fact, you could even measure the effect of the force.
Luckily for us, the size of this force is
a function of the rotational speed of the rotating frame.
So, if we are careful about the math,
we can use a measurement of FC to infer the rotation rate,
Omega of the rotating reference frame.
The Coriolis Force is a force that we can actually measure,
and it shows up only when the thing doing
the measurement is in a rotating reference frame.
This is the basic physical justification for how a gyroscope could possibly work,
but it doesn't tell us how we actually measure the Coriolis Force.
It turns out there are
several gyroscope implementations that have been used on flying vehicles.
Some of these rely on mechanically spinning some large view of ball
and then measuring the changes to its motions as the vehicle itself rotates.
But these large mechanical systems unpractical for smaller vehicles.
The gyros you're likely work with are called Vibrating Structure Gyroscopes.
These gyroscopes are small MEMS sensors,
and they are by far the most common gyro.
MEMS stands for Microelectromechanical Systems.
They work by having two tiny masses called Proof Masses,
which vibrate in opposite directions.
When there is no rotation these masses just move along a horizontal line.
Now, we can imagine a rotation Omega,
and you should think of this rotation axis as going into the screen.
And if we pause the motion here,
we can see that the mass on the right has some velocity to the right.
This rotation vector points into the screen so that those two vectors are orthogonal.
This is going to lead to a Coriolis Force which points upwards.
Note that this force is orthogonal to both the velocity and the rotation axis.
For the mass on the left,
the force is going to point down at this moment.
If you follow this logic,
as the mass vibrates,
the resulting motion of the proof masses is no longer going to be exactly horizontal,
but will instead have a vertical component as well.
By measuring this deflection in the vertical direction for both proof masses,
you can actually infer the rotational rate Omega of the sensor.
Now that we know how gyroscopes measure rotational rates,
we need to know how accurate these measurements are.
To know that, it will help to develop what's called a measurement model for gyroscope.