The number that you read from a gyroscope is
unlikely to be the correct value of the rotation rate.
In order to make sense of their imperfect measurements that we receive
from a sensor we first need a measurement model for that sensor.
Once we have the measurement model we can use the measurements we'll receive to estimate
the body rate of the vehicle and then we can integrate to get the actual altitude.
A simple measurement model for a gyroscope looks like this.
Here we see that the measured value of the rotation rate omega is equal to
the true angular velocity which gets corrupted
by some kind of bias that we may need to identify ahead of time.
Plus some additive zero mean Gaussian noise.
So, here the noise is something that changes for every measurement we get.
The bias might be temperature dependent,
and might change slowly,
but it's something that stays constant at least for some amount of time.
Now, I'd like to use this measurement to track my angle theta,
and also my uncertainty from time step to time step.
And we can use this army got tilda measurement to update an angle from
time t minus 1 to t and the equation we use looks like this.
And it's important to note that this is
a discrete approximation for computing the integral.
So, really there would also be some epsilon approximation error.
But we're going to ignore that for now.
We are also going to assume that any potential bias is
calibrated and removed from the Gyro measurements.
So, our make up tilda just looks like this.
And clearly, for this equation to be useful at time step t,
I would have needed to start with some initial angle theta not,
and then repeated this update with all my measurements up until now.
This type of navigation-by-integration is called dead reckoning.
Inertial navigation that is navigation based on
inertial sensors only is purely based on dead reckoning.
And as you might have guessed,
it's highly susceptible to drift.