How does our uncertainty estimate propagate?
We know how accurately we can measure the turn rate,
but what does that mean for our angle estimates?
So, if we use a very basic integration scheme,
and we neglect that we have additional integration error epsilon,
how does the noise in the turn rate measurements affect our angle estimates?
We can go step-by-step through that.
For example, Theta at time one is equal to our initial Theta,
plus our measured turn rate,
which is the true turn rate, Omega zero,
plus some noise representation Eta zero times delta t. So,
if we go through the equation,
we see that Theta one is corrupted by
some noise that has a variance of Sigma square, delta t square,
and that's because if I have a Gaussian or
any random variable and I multiply it by a number,
the variance is the original variance,
times the number squared.
So, this tells us how the noise in
the turn rate measurement translates into noise in the angle estimate,
and then, we can continue that for Theta two.
If we do that, we see that the noise variance in the angle is two times delta t square,
Sigma square, because now we have Eta zero, plus Eta one.
Assuming these are independent,
the variances of those two random variables add.
So, the overall variance doubles,
and then with every step, it increases.
So, if you look at the nth time step Theta n,
then our variance related to our estimate of Theta n
is n times delta t square, times Sigma square.
That means that our uncertainty about our angle estimate grows over time.
Of course, we can reduce this uncertainty by taking
fossil measurements which will lower delta t. But this n means that no matter what we do,
the uncertainty will have to grow with time.
Now, I can make a plot of angle on the vertical axis and show that over time.
If we assumes zero turn rate,
then our angle will be constant over time.
But because we have measurement noise in our turn rate measurement,
the uncertainty envelope cross,
and plotted like this as a plus minus three Sigma envelope,
you can see that the width of this uncertainty grows with the square root of time.
So, this is really problematic because over time, our uncertainty grows.
Which means our knowledge of the true angle decreases.
Luckily, there are some other techniques that we can
use to tame this increasing uncertainty.
But if you use dead-reckoning alone,
you will always have this growing uncertainty.