So, you've seen how to do dead-reckoning in some simple examples.
But how do we do the full 3D attitude update given gyro measurements?
If you remember from the control scores,
you can actually calculate the time derivative of
the Euler angles if we know the body rates and the current attitude.
And since the body rates are what the gyroscopes measure directly,
this is a reasonable approach.
The key equation looks like this.
Here, you can see that the derivative of the Euler angles is given by
some matrix that depends on the vehicle's current attitude times the body rates p, q,
and r. Then if we want to get the Euler angles at time T,
it's just the Euler angles from time T minus one plus the derivative times delta
T. This numerical integration technique is called the Euler forward method,
and it's the simplest numerical integration that you can do.
There are other similar approaches out there as well but this one works very well.