In this lesson, you crossed
the threshold into the third dimension of the planning problem.
We looked at the fact that while 3D grids are highly expressive geometry,
they can be prohibitively expensive to store in memory.
You saw that if you're willing to give up a bit of that expressiveness,
you can get a huge advantage by going to
a two and a half D representation of the problem.
We looked at how you can use
random sampling to generate a representation of your state space,
and how, through connecting those random states with edges,
you can form a probabilistic road map representation of your planning problem.
With the tools in this lesson combined with previous lessons,
you've actually got what you need to implement a receding horizon planning solution,
where you create a course plan or heuristic over your entire space in 2D
then continuously re-plan over a local volume as you execute your flight plan.
And with that, you're ready to complete the 3D motion planning project.
You can actually skip the next lesson as it is not
required to implement a passing solution of the project.
That said, if you want to take your planning project above and beyond,
then consider including some of
the advanced methods in the next lesson in your implementation.