Up to this point, you've looked at a couple of
different ways to solve the planning problem for flying cars.
And you've been working in two-dimensions.
We talked about 2D grids, and 2D graphs.
But flying cars exist in three-dimensions.
Now, we're going to take a look at how to actually solve
the planning problem for a three-dimensional vehicle in a three-dimensional world.
Remember, the things you need in order to solve the planning problem are the state-space,
an action space, a cost function,
and a start and goal state.
To get at the state-space,
you need to represent not just the geometry of the world in 3D,
but the configuration space.
This is not always an easy task.
Depending on the representation you choose,
some tasks may become easier,
and other tasks, harder.
The computer graphics industry, in particular,
has looked at a lot of the problems with representing objects in three-dimensions.
And you may have seen several of these issues previously if you ever worked in graphics.
For the purposes of motion planning,
what we care about in terms of a 3D representation
of the world is the same thing we cared about in 2D.
Namely, whether or not a particular location in
the configuration space is free or occupied by an obstacle.
Previously, we talked about how your configuration space is
a function not only of the position of the vehicle but orientation as well.
For the purposes of flight,
and particularly for quadrotors,
you can usually get away with using a simple 3D configuration space,
and ignore the effects of orientation or attitude.
However, the truth is that in moving from two-dimensions to three-dimensions,
planning gets more expensive.
You'll have choices to make in terms of what you want to optimize for,
which for the most part,
we'll come down to trade-offs in computational complexity,
and the completeness of your planning representation.