Let's start by looking at the most basic kind of 3D representation,
which is a grid with one cell per discrete X, Y, Z coordinate.
So here, I've got my X Y and Z coordinate axes,
and I'll have cells in a 3D grid like this.
And just like in the 2D case,
I'll label each cell as feasible or infeasible,
free space or obstacle.
3D cells are often called voxels,
which derives from pixels.
Pixel is short for picture element,
and voxel is short for volume element.
So, a voxel is the 3D version of a pixel.
In this sense, a 3D grid map is often called the voxel map.
You can build a voxel map from obstacle polyhedra using ray
tracing like the Bresenham line drawing algorithm just as you did in 2D.
Once you have a voxel map with obstacles labeled,
then you can use it for planning.
And so, having extended your statespace into this 3D grid,
you can use your planning algorithms like A* to
expand partial paths toward a goal just as in 2D.
Solving the planning problem into 3D grid does not require
much of anything new in terms of changes to your code that you used for the 2D case,
but the problem with this kind of representation
is these kinds of grids are considerably memory-intensive to store,
especially if you're trying to map a large volume at high resolution.
In this next exercise,
you'll get a chance to play with solving the planning problem using a 3D grid.