Because of the complexity and memory storage requirements of maintaining
a dense 3D grid of the configuration space with free and occupied cells,
a common alternative is to use so-called two and a half D maps,
where we assume that every obstacle extends from
the ground plane up to some height with nothing above it.
This means that you can actually store your planning map as a 2D map.
But instead of each cell being labeled with whether or not that cell is feasible,
each cell is labeled with the height of the obstacle,
or in other words,
the minimum altitude at which that cell becomes feasible.
This is essentially the representation that
you'll be working with in the upcoming project,
which consists of a polygon representation of
the ground plane footprint of each building in
the environment and the height of the building.
For example, the representation of a house
which has a pitched roof might look something like this,
where each one of these columns represents the height at which flight becomes feasible.
In the case where there are no obstacles,
then the minimum feasible altitude for those cells will be zero.
And again, we're not representing these columns as actual columns inside a 3D grid.
We're just representing the XY location of each polygon and the corresponding height.
Notice that what we've done here is implicitly separate the plan space, x, y,
z from the representation required to check if moves are feasible,
the x, y, and minimum flight altitude at each point.
This type of map works really well for a lot of flight applications.
In your planning solution in this case,
the state of the vehicle along the path
encodes the planned flight altitude of that location,
and that means that unsurprisingly,
your flight plans in 3D will often be longer than
2D plans because you need to take actions to change altitude.
In 3D, you might have a flight plan that goes up and over then down,
as the vehicle flies over this house.
But the storage required in the case of a two and a half D map representation
to check if a plan move is feasible is no worse than it was before on a 2D grid.
One drawback of this representation is that you
do lose the ability to represent complex geometry.
You can no longer represent the freespace, for example,
under the tree branches or under bridges.
For flying cars, that's probably okay because you can usually
assume that you don't want your flying car flying under a bridge or under a tree.