Now that you have a way to tell whether or not
a random sample is inside one of your obstacle polygons,
you basically have what you need in order to build a 3D graph
based representation of the feasible parts of the configuration space.
What we're going to look at here is a method called the Probabilistic Roadmap,
which is an algorithm for constructing a planning problem representation.
In short, this algorithm consists of three steps.
First, sample states at random in the environment.
Next, discard states that are in collision with obstacles.
And finally, build the graph and run search to plan a path through it.
Let's take a closer look at each of these steps.
So, you already know how to sample states at random,
and discard those that lie within obstacle polyhedra.
And now, those are your states for your planning problem,
but you also need the actions.
And for your graph, remember the actions are
the edges that you can travel along from state to state.
So, in 2D, you used a line drawing algorithm through the grid,
and you can use the same approach here.
You don't actually need to explicitly construct a 3D grid,
but rather just step along a discretized line and check for collisions.
In principle, you can use the same Bresenham algorithm the same line
drawing algorithm that you used before to
check to see if a line exists through free space.
All you need to do is for each discrete state along this edge,
check to see if it's inside an obstacle polygon.
As you run the line drawing algorithm from point p1 to p2,
you just keep checking to see if the point is inside any of the obstacle polygons.
And here, you can see that you are constructing a graph
that captures the conductivity of the free space.
This graph is not going to necessarily allow you to express
the optimal plan in terms of true minimum distance or minimum time or minimum cost,
but it's going to be a very efficient way to find
a trajectory through the 3D environment.
As an implementer and a designer of algorithms,
you're going to have to make design decisions in
terms of whether actually discretizing the edges and
testing whether or not each point is inside an obstacle is more efficient than testing.
For example, for the intersection of a line segment with any of the known obstacles.
These decisions could depend on the complexity,
length scale, and size of the environment, among other things.
To summarize, your graph construction algorithm looks like the following.
Sample states randomly, discard samples that are inside or too close to obstacles,
build the graph, and search through it to find a plan.
This method is called the probabilistic roadmap.
It's not a planning algorithm.
So much as an algorithm for constructing a planning problem representation.
One of the nice properties of the probabilistic roadmap
is that if you're careful about how you sample those points,
then in the limit of an infinite number of samples,
you're guaranteed to converge to a graph that contains all feasible paths.
This is what's known as being asymptotically complete.
Another nice property is that,
if you're careful about how you add the edges,
you're also guaranteed in the limit of an infinite number of samples,
to converge to a graph that contains the optimal path.
This is what's known as being asymptotically optimal.
So, random sampling techniques are surprisingly powerful way to construct
plan representations that will allow you to
search in high dimensional spaces efficiently.