The probabilistic road map is a great way to find feasible plans through
a full 3D environment without incurring
the costs of building and maintaining a dense 3D grid map.
But it's not a silver bullet especially over long time scales.
Why is that?
Well, let's think about the two sources of computational complexity.
The first is the cost of building the model.
And the second, is the cost of planning through the model.
I can build the probabilistic road map by sampling
points and building a graph around the obstacles, that's one phase.
If I know the environment perfectly ahead of time,
and the positions of obstacles don't change,
then I only need to build that graph once.
In the real world, that turns out to be a terrible assumption.
Obstacles appear and disappear,
and you need to be ready for the unexpected.
But, assuming that the environment is relatively fixed,
you're only going to run the probabilistic road map algorithm once.
Then, to find an actual plan,
you run search on the graph using something like A* to
find a plan from the start to the goal.
In reality, you're likely to run A* multiple times.
This is what's known as multiple query planning,
the opposite being single query planning.
And what that means for a fixed graph that you built using the probabilistic road map,
is that your computational cost will be dominated by the search.
From your implementation of A*,
you'll recall that the computational cost of the search is of order b to the d,
where for our road map the branching term b is the maximum number of edges out of a node.
And d, is the number of edges you have to travel to get from the start to the goal,
which is the length of the plan.
The best that you can do in terms of reducing
computational complexity given a fixed graph,
is reducing the branching factor and the total length of the plan.
You can try to find edges there as long as possible,
but if the environment doesn't cooperate,
then you're still going to pay in terms of computational complexity.
What else might you do?
Well, a common idea in planning and control is
to recognize the planning the entire trajectory from start to goal,
considering all state variables and
all possible features of the environment is often the wrong thing to do.
For instance, planning the entire trajectory in 3D, maybe overkill,
especially if they're obstacles that are going to pop up along the way.
A better strategy is to plan an approximate root in 2D using a coarse grid to graph,
and then as the vehicle travels,
keep improving that plan after some distance or
horizon using the global plan as a heuristic.
Given some obstacles like this,
you might plan a course trajectory to travel around the obstacles,
and then in a local region around the vehicle,
you could do higher resolution obstacle avoidance,
and that local plan might be a 3D plan.
As your vehicle moves,
you move the local region around with you,
doing the 3D planning in that small footprint.
The fact that the region in which you're constructing
the local plan moves as the vehicle is moving
is why this two level approach is often referred to as receding horizon planning.
And, there's a very similar concept in control called receding horizon control.
Next, we'll look at an example of how this works.