Let's look at an example of receding horizon planning.
The basic idea is that you construct an initial plan like this,
using some approximate model around the course features in the environment.
In this case, an approximate model might be to take
your 2D grid model with relatively large grid cells,
rather than a full 3D model,
and use that 2D model to construct a rough plan.
Then, you construct a local plan using a more detailed model considering,
for example, the full 3D polyhedra of the obstacles.
But you only compute the local plan out to some relatively nearby horizon.
The goal is not going to be inside that distance.
So, for the local model,
you can set the goal as the nearest state on the global plan,
outside the horizon, given by the global planner.
The local planner will plant inside
that horizon to the nearest state in the global planner.
The vehicle starts executing the local plan but the key
is that as the vehicle moves the states inside the horizon change.
As you see here,
the horizon is changing as the vehicle moves and
the vehicle keeps re-planning out to the new horizon.
An even better idea to modify this is,
instead of having the local plan be the next state in the global plan,
you could start instead by using breadth-first search
backward from the goal to every state in the 2D global model.
By running breadth-first search backwards from the goal,
you're computing the cost of the shortest path from each state to the goal.
In this way, you can label each state in the global model with the cost of the goal.
And now, the local planner can then try and find
the minimum cost path inside
the local model to the minimum cost state in the global plan.
What's nice is that you can keep
this global cost field fixed and then, as the vehicle moves,
it can keep picking new global states to fly to as the horizon moves outward.
Now, a couple of questions might be on your mind.
First, how do you pick the horizon for the local planner?
This is entirely a function of how fast the vehicle
is moving and how quickly the planner can re-plan,
which will be a function of how fast your flight computer is.
There isn't really a recipe or an algorithm for picking the horizon.
You just have to know how far out you can plan given
the constraints of how fast you're flying and your computational constraints.
In the next exercise,
you'll get a chance to implement a receding horizon planner and figure out what
works well in terms of resolution for both the local and global planner,
as well as horizon scale.