Just as obstacles can pop up or disappear,
small inaccuracies in the position estimate
are another source of uncertainty for flying car.
A real flying car is always going to encounter small disturbances and things
like how its rotors move or small disturbances from the environment like wind.
This means that no matter how good the autopilot is,
a real vehicle will never track a path perfectly.
Dealing with small disturbances can
often be taken care of with a minor course correction.
But in the case of large disturbances,
your planner may have to take more significant action.
For example, suppose that your vehicle is hit by
a gust of wind or a steady prevailing wind and blown
far enough off course that there is now a building or
some other obstacle in the way on the path to the next waypoint,
your planner will need to re-plan and that isn't always an instantaneous process.
So before re-planning, your state machine
may need to stop the vehicle and go into a hover,
or for a fixed-wing vehicle,
do some other safety maneuver like go into a loiter pattern.
The main point is that when a real flying vehicle is enroute to a waypoint,
it needs to be constantly checking if
the flight path is still feasible from its current position.
In the next lesson,
you'll get a chance to see the effect of wind
on your vehicle and detect the need to re-plan.