Welcome back. Up until now,
we've been focused on the longitudinal motion of the vehicle,
where we look at the aircraft from a profile view.
From this view, it was easy for us to define the angle of attack as
the difference between the direction the vehicles
moving and the direction that the body frame is pointing.
In this lesson, we're going to focus on the lateral motion of the vehicle.
To do that, we're going to look at the vehicle from above and from behind.
Once again, we'll find that sometimes the vehicles direction of
travel is not the same as the direction the body frame is pointing.
We're going to call this angle the sideslip angle and label it beta.
As you'll see in this lesson,
this sideslip angle is going to play
an important role in the lateral directional motion of this vehicle.
The overall plan for this lesson is similar to the previous lesson.
First, we're going to write down the non-linear lateral-directional equations of motion.
Then, we're going to really look at these equations
with a focus on what's called the side force.
We generally want both the side force and the sideslip angle to be equal to zero,
but that can sometimes be tricky when we want to turn a fixed wing vehicle for example.
To solve that problem,
we'll talk about something called the coordinated turn,
as a technique for properly managing the forces so that turns
can be executed safely and comfortably for the passengers.
Once we understand the forces on the vehicle,
will develop a linearize model.
We'll analyze the eigenvalues of this model stability matrix
and identify the three well-known lateral-directional modes.
By the end of this lesson,
you'll have an intuitive understanding for the cause of these three modes and you'll
be able to use linear algebra to predict the behavior of fixed wing vehicles.
For now, let's jump into the equations of motion in the lateral direction.
We'll start by writing the equations for the force free case,
and then afterwards we can add the forces back in.