These 11 equations, are the equations of motion
for a vehicle with no forces acting on it.
Below this video, you'll find the full versions of these equations with forces added in.
I'm not going to go over each of these equations individually,
but there is one equation that's worth discussing and that's the equation for v dot.
Remember, u, v, and w gives the velocity of the vehicle in the body frame,
along the x, y, and z axes.
So, v dot is the lateral acceleration of the vehicle in the left or right direction.
This lateral acceleration is caused by all the lateral forces on the vehicle.
Collectively refer to these forces as side force.
In general, we want side force to be as small as possible,
since lateral acceleration is generally an uncomfortable sensation for people.
But before we can minimize side force,
we need to understand where it comes from.
With forces added back in,
the full equation for v dot looks like this.
This first term comes from the component of the vehicle's weight,
that points are laterally,
when the vehicles rolled at some angle phi.
This next term is the dynamic pressure times the surface area of the wing,
multiplied by everything in these brackets here.
As you can see, the terms in these brackets depend on,
the size of angle beta,
the roll rate and r rate of the vehicle,
and the ailerons deflection delta a,
and the rudder deflection delta r. I encourage you to take
a few minutes to look at the lateral equations of motion, before moving on.