Something we haven't really discussed is how to turn a fixed-wing aircraft.
Consider an aircraft flying at constant speed in a circular trajectory.
Even though the magnitude of this aircraft's velocity vector isn't changing,
the direction is constantly changing,
and changing direction of the velocity is an acceleration.
This acceleration is always directed towards the center of
the circle so we call it centripetal acceleration.
For any object to move in a circle at constant speed,
there needs to be a centripetal force that provides this acceleration,
and the size of that force must be equal to MV squared over R,
where M is the mass of the object,
V is the speed, and R is the radius of the circle.
So, if you want an airplane to fly a circular trajectory like this,
we'd need a force directed inwards,
and the size of that force has to be equal to MV squared
over R. One option would be to generate a side force,
but we just talked about how lateral accelerations
are perceived as uncomfortable by passengers.
So what we really need is something called a coordinated turn.
A coordinated turn works by rolling the vehicle,
and using a component of the vehicles lift vector as the centripetal force for the turn.
Consider an aircraft viewed from behind.
From this angle, we can see the lift and weight vectors which point up and down.
The idea behind a coordinated turn is to roll the vehicle so that a component of
the lift force actually points towards the center of the circle we want to follow.
Here, we see the aircraft rolled to some angle phi.
Now, the lift vector has a vertical component given by L cosine phi,
and a horizontal component given by L sine phi.
This horizontal component is the centripetal force,
so it must be equal to M times V squared over R.
The vertical component bounces the weight so it must be equal to
M times G. If we divide these two equations,
we're left with this,
the tangent of phi is equal to V squared over R times G. Or,
we can take the inverse tangent of both sides.
We can use this equation to determine what roll angle
we need in order to follow a circle of a certain radius,
while moving at a certain speed.