At this point, you've seen some of the unexpected consequences of fixed-wing dynamics.
For example, you've seen how an aircraft needs to
roll to perform a comfortable, coordinated turn.
You've also seen how appear yawing motion will actually induce roll in an aircraft.
Neither of these are problems for the vehicle,
but there are real physical phenomena and the autopilot has to be aware of them.
At this point, we're ready to start talking about
the lateral stability of fixed-wing aircraft.
One way to understand stability is by taking the eigenvalues of the linearized dynamics.
This helps us understand what's called the dynamic stability of the aircraft.
We're going to do that shortly but we can also get some intuition by
looking directly at the forces and asking questions about those forces.
One question we might ask is,
when this vehicle is flying in a trim state and gets disturbed,
do the forces tend to restore
equilibrium or do they increase the size of the disturbance?
Let's start with roll stability.
We use the capital letters L, M,
and N for the moments about the vehicles body x,
y, and z axes.
So, L is the rolling moment.
This letter L is a bit overloaded since we also use it for the lift force,
but it should be clear in context which is being referred to.
The equation for the rolling moment has two terms.
One is proportional to the ailerons deflection as you'd expect.
The other is proportional to the side slip angle beta.
In general, we want to flight trajectories with zero side slip.
That means that the CL beta parameter is really important.
We call this parameter the Role Static Stability Derivative.
When it's negative, the vehicle will be statically stable in roll.
That means that when the vehicle rolls to any non-zero side slip angle,
this term will create a moment that tends to roll the vehicle back to zero side slip.
Next, we can talk about yaw stability.
The yawing moment also has two terms.
One proportional to rudder deflection and one proportional to side slip.
This moment tends to restore the vehicle to
zero side slip when this coefficient is positive.
This coefficient is sometimes called
the Weathercock Stability Derivative because if an aircraft is statically stable in yaw,
it will naturally want to point into the wind like a weather vane.
When designing fixed-wing aircraft,
a lot of thought goes into the values of these coefficients.
This yaw coefficient is heavily influenced by the design of the tail of the aircraft.
The larger the tail and the further off
the tail is of the center of mass of the aircraft,
the larger this coefficient will be.