The rest of this lesson is going to look pretty familiar.
We're going to start by developing
a linearized model of the lateral dynamics around a trim state.
This is going to allow us to express the dynamics in terms
of the stability matrix and a control effect matrix.
To analyze the dynamic stability of the system,
we're going to find the eigenvalues and eigenvectors of the stability matrix.
When we do this, we're going to find three lateral modes.
These modes are well known in aviation,
and are called the roll mode,
the spiral mode and Dutch roll.
Once we've identified these modes,
we're going to discuss them and try to get
some physical insight into the underlying dynamics of each mode.
To avoid boring you with math,
we're going to present the linearized model in text.
You're welcome to try to derive it yourself,
but you should also feel free to take it as it's given.