When we find the eigenvalues and eigenvectors of the lateral stability matrix,
we get four eigenvalues which correspond to three dynamic modes.
The first eigenvalue is real,
negative, and generally large.
This corresponds to what's called the roll mode.
The next eigenvalue is real,
generally small, and can be either negative or positive.
This corresponds to the spiral mode.
The last two eigenvalues are complex conjugate pair.
They correspond to a damped oscillatory motion called dutch roll.
Let's look at the roll mode first.
This is the simplest lateral mode.
It just describes the damping of roll rate towards zero.
If you imagine looking at a plane from behind,
as it rolls right,
the right wing hasn't increased effective angle of
attack since it's driving down into the airflow.
The left-wing has exactly the opposite.
Since lift increases with angle of attack,
this means the right wing will actually experienced more lift than the left-wing,
and this will cause a moment which tends to damp the roll rate towards zero.
Note that the effect of the roll mode is to damp the roll rate to zero,
doesn't damp the actual roll angle to zero.