The eigenvalue of the roll mode is generally large.
Which means that it's well damped.
This is largely due to how big the wings are.
The other real eigenvalue mode is called a spiral mode.
This mode is associated with an eigenvalue that can be positive or negative,
but it's generally pretty small,
which means it's slow to either damp or diverge.
To understand this mode,
we're going to look at two pictures of the same aircraft at the same time.
We're going to imagine this vehicle is disturbed from straight and level flight,
by a small roll angle phi.
This results in a small lateral side slip velocity
v. You can actually think of the vehicle is sliding downhill.
Note that there is a downwards component to this lateral velocity in the body frame,
since the vehicle is rolled.
As the vehicle moves sideways,
the vertical tail gets pushed to the left by the incoming air,
which induces a positive yaw rate.
As you saw, when you learned about roll yaw coupling,
this positive your rate will cause the left wing to experience more lift than the right,
which will cause the roll angle to increase even further.
If this mode is unstable,
and this behavior isn't corrected,
the aircraft would eventually fly a slowly diverging path in roll, yaw,
and altitude, and eventually the vehicle would spiral into the ground.
Fortunately, the spiral mode can be dealt with by airplane design.
Wing Dihedral can produce a restoring torque,
and a Small Vertical tail can also help reduce the impact of this mode.