The final lateral dynamic mode is called the Dutch Roll mode.
This mode corresponds to the only pair of complex eigenvalues from the stability matrix.
To understand this mode,
we're once again going to consider the same vehicle from two angles simultaneously.
I'm going to use curved arrows to denote the roll and yaw rates at each point in time.
We're going to start at T equals zero with this vehicle at some roll angle,
phi, and zero, your angle.
Then we're going to introduce some yaw rate as a disturbance.
As you saw earlier, this yaw rate will cause a rolling moment on the aircraft.
A few moments later,
the vehicle will look like this.
Now it has zero roll angle,
but due to inertia, it still has some non-zero roll rate in this direction.
At this point, the vehicle has reached it's maximum angle,
so the yaw rate has gone to zero.
A few moments later,
the roll rate from before will have rolled the vehicle to some new maximal roll angle,
and the lower right wing will lead to
a yawing moment which will have restored the vehicle to zero yaw.
Finally, inertia will yaw the vehicle to
an orientation like this as the vehicle rolls through wings level.
If we were to plot the roll angle versus time,
we can see that it should start high,
go through zero, reach some minimal value and then return.
We could also plot the yaw angle versus time and we get a plot like this.
These plots look very similar,
except we can see that there is about a quarter cycle or 90 degrees of lag between them.
Now, why is this called Dutch Roll?
The pioneering aeronautical engineer,
Hans Hacker from MIT,
coined the term comparing it to a type of skating called the Dutch Roll where
skaters skate on the outside of their blades swinging from side to side as they go.