We started this lesson with a full non-linear equations of
motion for the lateral-directional dynamics of fixed-wing flight,
and we use these equations to understand some important concepts related to flight.
For example, you learned about side slip
and its impact on the side force of vehicle experiences.
You also learned how to steer a fixed-wing vehicle
without introducing excessive uncomfortable side force,
by performing a coordinated turn.
You learned about the static stability,
including role stability and yaw stability of a fixed-wing aircraft.
But, as we saw in the last lesson,
there's only so much we can learn by studying the non-linear equations of motion.
In the last half of this lesson,
we linearize the equations of motion around trim.
We studied the eigenvalues of
the resulting stability matrix and identified three lateral dynamic modes,
the Roll mode, the Spiral mode, and the Dutch roll mode.
By now, you should have a good sense for just how unintuitive fixed-wing dynamics can be.
For example, you might not have guessed that
a yawing motion would induce a rolling moment but that actually does happen.
Now that we have some understanding about some of
the unintuitive dynamics that govern fixed-wing flight,
we're almost ready to start using that
understanding to actually control a fixed-wing vehicle.