Earlier in this lesson,
you implemented a P controller which only knew
about the actual error of the vehicle's position.
Just now, we implemented a PD controller
which also knew about the error in the vehicle's velocity,
which is the first derivative of position.
And there are many situations where PD control
is actually enough to track a reference trajectory.
In the exercises you've seen in this lesson,
the targets has just been some constant set of value.
But what about more interesting and realistic trajectories?
When the reference trajectory changes very rapidly,
we can make our controller's job easier by telling it
the desired acceleration or second derivative of position as well.
In this case, the control that we sent to the vehicle looks like this.
And this acceleration term is usually called feed-forward term.
In the ideal world,
z dot dot would move the vehicle along
the desired trajectory and e and e dot would be zero.
We would need no control action.
So we can think of the commanded control as being centered around
the desired acceleration but pulled
either up or down by the errors in position and velocity.