So far, we have this as our controller equation and we
can interpret this as saying the best control to command right now
is whatever the current target acceleration is plus some correction for
any error in velocity plus some correction for any error in position.
We can also see that Kp and Kd must be positive for
the corrections to be effective and for the system to remain stable over all.
But how do we decide how big these corrections should be?
Written like this, these coefficients Kp and Kd don't tell us
much and I don't know how to tune them to get good behavior.
But there's a way to rewrite this equation so that
the coefficients have more physical significance.
I'm going to walk through the mass now,
and then afterwards, you'll have a chance to play around with these ideas in code.
The first thing I want to do is write this equation like this.
And now, I can see that these terms in parentheses are just the derivatives of the error.
If you've ever studied differential equations,
then you have seen very similar equations before.
In fact, this looks like the equation for mass on a spring with
some damping term and the resulting motion is a damped oscillation,
which just means the motion has sinusoidal oscillation,
whose amplitude is modified by a decaying exponential.
Let me show you what I mean.
I'm using a tool called desmos to show graphs here.
Here, I've defined a function f,
which is just the cosine of omega t. And you can see that when I increase omega,
I increase the rate of oscillation.
So, this is pure oscillatory behavior.
I can turn that off and we can look at pure decay.
And here, you can see a graph of e to
the minus delta omega t and this is pure exponential decay.
And if I slide this delta,
you can see that I can control how fast this decay happens.
But the actual error as a function of time like the position of a mass
on a spring will display both of these behaviors simultaneously.
So down here, I've defined this third function h,
which is the product of the oscillation and the decay.
Let me turn that on now.
As you can see, we are left with this oscillation which is modulated by decay.
This wouldn't be the worst error for a flying vehicle.
But honestly, we'd like the error to converge to zero much
faster and we would rather not have so much oscillation.
Luckily, I can correct for that.
Now, I can modify my delta and my omega.
And since I have some intuitive sense of what those parameters do,
I can more easily tweak how the error will behave over time.
It turns out that when you solve this equation,
you find that Kp is just the square of
that natural frequency omega and Kd is two times delta times omega.
In practice, when you tune your controllers,
it is helpful to think of these coefficients instead of Kp and Kd.