There are very useful approximate relationships that one
can derive for this reparameterization.
For PD control double integrator system,
the response to a target altitude change looks something like this.
And there are some properties of this response that we might want to tune.
First, there's overshoot.
That's the amount by which the actual trajectory overshoots the target.
Generally, we want that to be small.
Next, there's the rise time.
That's the amount of time it takes to get to the target altitude.
Again, we'd like this to be small but often,
there are some system limitations such as actuation constraints,
that provide a lower bound for the rise time.
We can also think about the settling time.
We say that a system has settled when the oscillations are sufficiently small,
within plus minus two percent of the target value.
So, the settling time is just the amount of time the system takes to reach that point.
Once again, we want this to be small.
And since second order systems are so well understood,
we can actually come up with equations that will tell
us exactly what these quantities will be.
And what's really helpful is that each of these quantities has an associated design rule.
So, for example, if you want to decrease the rise time,
you have to increase the natural frequency of the system.
Most of the time,
you can get good performance by following a few simple rules of thumb.
Rule number 1, choose a damping ratio between 0.7 and 1.
If the damping ratio is 1,
the system will have no overshoot,
but the rise time will be a little longer.
When the damping ratio is 0.7,
the rise time quickens but you will see some overshoot.
Rule number 2, pick a large natural frequency.
Choose the natural frequency large to have a small rise and
settling time but make sure your control stays within the actuation limits.
In fact, often, control engineers think in time constants and define T is equal to
1 over the natural frequency omega n. And when your controller is parametrized like this,
the rise time is just 1.57 times T. So,
you can think of the desired rise time and that gives you the controller
parameter omega n. This results in much less time spent on tuning.
If the natural frequency is too large,
it may also amplify unmodeled dynamic effects and cause problems this way.
So, choose the damping ratio and then play
around with a frequency till you get some good results.