We begin this lesson by trying to solve the control problem with an open-loop controller.
And there we saw that a slight mass error
led to an exploding area in position of the vehicle.
So, let's see how close we are to actually solving that problem now.
Here we are in the PD controller class,
and note that even in the initializer,
the PD controller does know about the mass of the vehicle it's controlling.
Also note that I've defined this tune function which allows me to set
Kp and Kd in terms of these more intuitive parameters,
the damping ratio and this natural frequency.
But really, what we want to pay attention to it right now is this thrust control method.
And what this method does is first it calculates the error,
then calculates the derivative of the error,
and then it calculates this U bar.
U bar is the actual desired acceleration of the vehicle.
And U bar, we can think well, the desired acceleration,
first it's whatever fed forward acceleration we fast into
this controller plus we want to correct for error and derivative of error,
and we do that by multiplying Kp times error and Kd times the error dot.
And that gives us our desired acceleration.
We then need to transform this desired acceleration into a thrust,
and we do that by multiplying the vehicle mass by G minus U bar.
So, that's our control code.
Now, let's go to our little toy simulation code.
Here, we have our mass error, which I'm going to start with one.
And remember, this is a multiplier,
so one means no error actually.
Perceived mass is going to be the actual mass times this mass error.
So we use that perceived mass when we instantiate this controller here.
We get our step trajectory,
and that just means if the drone's going to start at a position of Z equals 0
this is just going to step the target of two Z equals negative 1 instantaneously.
And we're going to observe what's called the step response of the system.
And the rest of this code just sort of does what you'd expect.
We have this history variable which stores the history of the Z position of the system.
And we go through. We get a commanded thrust.
We set the drones thrust to that value.
We advance the state of the system.
And then we store the state into the history.
So, for a mass error of 1.0,
which means no real error,
let's run this cell and see what graph we get,
and we see some really nice behavior.
You can see the drone starts off down here at Z equals zero.
It goes up, it overshoots a bit,
but pretty quickly, after a couple of oscillations,
it gets right to the target path.
And this is a PD controller working well.
But what happens if we increase that mass error?
So, there was no mass error.
Let's make it so we're overestimating the mass by 50 percent. The mass here is 1.5.
Now, what happens if I run the cell?
As you can see, the trajectory looks basically the
same except that it's got this systematic bias where it's
consistently too high and it turns out we can never
correct for this systematic bias if we only use a PD controller.
We really need a little bit more.