To correct for systematic bias,
we need a full PID controller.
The I, in PID, stands for integral.
And if you remember from calculus,
the integral of a function is the area under the curve.
So, when you have an error function that looks like this one, well,
the integral of this function from let's say,
0 to 5, would be all of this area.
And the integral from 0 to 10 would also include all of this area as well.
The integral of an error like this over time,
is a very useful tool for accumulating error.
And that's exactly what the item in the PID controller does.
It accumulates error over time and then
adjusts the system to counter the accumulation of error.
Mathematically, we can write the full PID controller equation like this,
or reparameterized, we can write it like this.
With this reparameterization, similar to the PID controller,
we just need to choose a damping ratio between 0.7 and 1 and decide on a time constant,
which is directly related to the raised time.
This makes the tuning task so much more intuitive
compared to tuning these three independent parameters,
Kp, Ki, and Kd.
When we get this right,
the altitude will start to look more like this.
As the integrated error accumulates,
the vehicle is able to adjust its thrust until it reaches the target altitude.