We began this lesson with
a naive open loop approach to control a monorotor in one dimension.
But this approach had a big problem,
a single tiny error in how we modeled
the vehicle's mass led to a precision error that grew quickly overtime.
We tried to correct that with a proportional P controller which increased the thrust
when the vehicle was too low and decreased the thrust when the vehicle was too high.
This was an improvement but caused the vehicle to oscillate.
So we added a derivative or D term to our controller
which tried to get the vehicle's actual velocity to match the target.
And this helped a lot.
We are able to get rid of the oscillations and
generally stay pretty close to the target trajectory.
Then, you also saw how we could parameterize
this PD controller using parameters with real physical meeting.
At this point, the monorotor was flying quite well.
It just wasn't exactly hitting its target and
that was because of an underlying error in our model of the vehicle's mass,
which was causing it to hover at an altitude that
was close to correct but not quite right.
We corrected this by introducing an integral I term,
which accumulated this error and adjusted the control in the opposite direction.
Together, these PI and D terms made
a PID controller which could
precisely control the monorotor we built within this lesson.
In the next lesson, you'll see how things change when we move into two-dimensional control.