Welcome back. So, what are we going to learn in this lesson Angela?
In this lesson, we are going to learn how to make a quadrotor do what we want it to do.
And this may be as simple as hovering in the air.
But in the last lesson,
we already learned how to model the vehicle dynamics.
Shouldn't hovering just be as simple as
the upward thrust needs to balance the downwards weight?
Not exactly.
Our model was the simplification of the real world.
And if we try to use only that model to control the drone,
it would crash pretty quickly.
Okay. So, if our model of vehicle dynamics isn't enough, what else do we need to do?
What we really need to do,
is to actively control the vehicle.
And not only think about what the drone should be doing based on our models,
but also pay attention to what it actually is doing,
and make constant adjustments.
Okay. Sounds good. Let's get started.