In the last lesson,
you learned about vehicle dynamics by studying
the effect of forces and torques on a bi-rotor.
And this gave you some impressive predictive power.
Given the state of the vehicle and the rotational rates of the two rotors,
you could increment the state forward in time
to predict the trajectory of the vehicle in the future.
Then, at the end of the lesson, you went the other way.
Starting with a desire trajectory,
like vertical oscillations for example,
you were able to determine what sequence of rotor commands would
actually cause the bi-rotor to fly in that trajectory.
And if we lived in a perfect world,
a model of the vehicle dynamics would be all we need.
It will tell us how to design vehicle inputs,
the motor turn rates,
that result in a desired motion,
and the vehicle controls problem would be solved.
In the real world,
the control problem is all about managing the messiness of the real world,
and making sure the vehicle achieves the task despite wind disturbances,
neglected aerodynamic effects and model parameter uncertainties.
For example, your estimate of the rotational inertia of the vehicle may be slightly off.
In the next exercise,
you'll explore one of the problems that can
arise when our knowledge of the vehicle is off,
by even just a little bit.