You just saw a graph that looked something like this.
And this exploding simulation of prediction error came from a tiny difference between
the true mass of the drone and the mass that
the controller was using to make its thrust decisions.
So, where does this increasing error come from and
how can a single small mistake in mass cause it?
Remember, the only thing we directly control are the drone's rotor-rotation rates.
This cause forces and moments on the drone which in turn
cost translational accelerations and rotational accelerations.
But for now, let's just focus on accelerations and
let's ignore this whole part of the process.
So for our purposes,
we have direct control over acceleration but not velocity or position.
If we want to change those quantities,
we have to do so through acceleration.
We use the variable U to represent a thrust or torque control inputs to the drone.
Here we use U1 to represent the total thrust commanded in newton.
For a 1-D monorotor,
we have an equation of motion that looks like this.
And even so, this equation has an M and a G in it,
the most important thing to focus on is the U1 and Z double dot.
You can see that with U1 you can directly influence acceleration.
So often, we will write our dynamics equations in a slightly simpler form,
like this: Z double dot equals to U1 bar.
After we have computed a desired acceleration, U1 bar,
we can easily obtain the corresponding U1 that would achieve that desired acceleration,
using the following equation: U1 bar is equal to
G minus U1 over M. When we write it like this,
it's meant to remind us that the thing we get to control is acceleration.
So, we have direct control over the vehicle's acceleration.
And recall that velocity is the integral of
acceleration and position is the integral of velocity.
So, let's assume the vehicle is hovering and we want U1 bar to be equal to zero,
which would result in the vehicle to continue to hover.
If we overestimate our mass by
some small amount and we have some non-zero acceleration epsilon,
would the vehicle accelerate upwards or downwards?