The vehicle would accelerate upwards because
the vehicle is lighter than the controller has assumed.
But what will happen to our position over time?
Remember, we are assuming that the target Z is just some constant altitude.
We first need to integrate Z double dot to get velocity or
Z dot and then we integrate that with respect to time to get Z as a function of time.
With Z of zero being Z knot and Z dot of zero being zero,
the altitude was supposed to be Z knot forever.
But now, it grows quadratically with time and all because of a small error in the mass.
So the smallest error in our model can cause a huge mismatch
between what we think is happening based on our model and what actually happens.
This quadratic error appears anytime we have
a double integrator system like the one we have here.
We call a double integrator an unstable system.
A stable system would have
some self-correcting ability and the mismatch would not grow infinitely.
And it's important to note that these model errors are unavoidable.
Our dynamics models are always an approximation of the real word.
Understanding and addressing errors is so important to control that
we actually have different words for different types of error.
The type of error you just saw is called a model error,
which just refers to an error in our model of the vehicle itself.
In this case, our model misrepresented the true mass of the vehicle,
but there are many ways our model can fail to account for the true dynamics.
Next, we have disturbances.
These are errors caused by something external to the vehicle that we didn't anticipate.
For example, a strong crossbreeds would be a disturbance that could introduce error.
Finally, we have measurement noise.
Measurement noise refers to the unpredictable errors introduced
whenever we try to measure something about the quad or its environment.
You will learn a lot more about noise in particular in the next course on estimation.