The controller you just worked with,
its known as an open loop controller.
An open loop controller is a controller that doesn't
receive any feedback from the system it's controlling,
and this lack of feedback can make a simple control problem very difficult.
As an example, consider getting out of bed in the morning,
and brushing your teeth.
For you, this is probably not a hard problem to solve.
But if you were told to do it by wearing a blindfold,
it will probably be a lot harder. The lesson here,
effective control requires feedback.
In the world of control theory,
we use block diagrams to visualize
important information about a controller and the system it controls.
An open loop controller has a control diagram that looks like this.
For the controller, you just work with the system, was the drone.
The reference, was the target set location which was Z knot,
the input was the commanded thrust,
and the output was eventually,
the actual set location.
In general, the output describes what we can measure about the system.
If we can measure the velocity,
it would also include Z dot.
And as you saw,
this doesn't produce a very effective controller because it lacks feedback,
which means, any errors will be unnoticed and are able to grow unchecked.
To turn this into a closed loop controller,
we need a diagram that looks like this.
And if you look down here,
you'll see that we are using a sensor to measure the output of the system,
and we are feeding that measured signal back,
and comparing it with the target value, the reference signal.
This circular thing is called a summing junction,
and the plus and minus signs are used to indicate that
the arrow which this junction produces comes from the reference,
minus the measured output.
You might see these summing junctions in some of the control diagrams,
but sometimes they are also just omitted.
In these block diagrams,
arrows represent signals, and the boxes are functions or equations.
For example, the system block represents our model equation.