For the rest of this lesson,
we are going to be filling in the computational details of this box labeled controller.
And we do this for a monorotor that moves only in the z direction.
By the end of this lesson,
we will have what's called a full PID controller.
But we are going to get there incrementally.
So let's start with the simplest possible controller.
And the simplest type of controller sends
a control signal whose strength is proportional to the size of the error.
The error for a monorotor is the altitude error.
The larger the error,
the more the system has to do to correct that error.
So if the vehicle is just a little too low,
then we increase the thrust by a little bit.
But if it's way too low,
then we increase the thrust by a lot.
As a function of error, you can write the input as u of t is equal to Kp
times e of t. The control signal is equal to some constant times the error.
To make this an easier and more intuitive control problem,
we assume we can directly control the acceleration.
And this case of P term is a tunable parameter for this controller.
It is also called proportional or peaking.
We know how to compute the thrust,
the true system input from U bar 1 through a simple algebraic equation.
So now, you should implement this controller yourself and
take a look at the trajectories that this sort of controller produces.