The code for a P Controller is pretty simple.
And the output that this control strategy produces is already
much better than the quadratic error we saw with the open-loop controller,
which would have caused a crash.
But it's clearly not perfect.
I want to draw your attention to two problems.
The first and most obvious problem is the oscillating behavior.
The actual z, bounces up and down when it's supposed to be steady.
The second problem is the offset.
These oscillations aren't even centered on the target z.
We are going to address both of these problems,
but let's start with the oscillations.
At this point, you should spend some time playing
around with different values of this kp constant,
that relates error to command thrust.
As you do, keep the following question in mind,
why are these oscillations occurring,
and is it possible to get rid of them by tuning kp?