It turns out, that no matter how you adjust your Kp,
you'll never get rid of these oscillations.
To convince yourself that this is the case,
imagine a monorotor hovering exactly at its target altitude.
In a perfect world,
without any model errors,
a P controller would do a pretty good job keeping the vehicle in place
by commanding a thrust that is equal to the weight of the vehicle.
Now imagine that suddenly,
the target altitude is shifted upwards by one meter.
So now, the vehicle is here,
but the target said it's way up here.
What's the controller going to do?
Well, it's going to immediately command a large thrust upwards,
and that means that the vehicle is going to accelerate upwards.
And with a P controller,
as long as the vehicle is below the target z,
then it's going to continue to command a thrust that causes upward acceleration.
This means that by the time the vehicle gets to that target z,
it will have a substantial adverse velocity,
which will cause it to overshoot the target.
When plotted over time,
the resulting trajectory will always have the oscillations you've already seen.
Another way to think about these oscillations is mathematically.
Our controller commands accelerations in proportion to the error.
But this, unfortunately, does not lead to
zero velocity when the vehicle gets to the target location.
Instead, the vehicle gets to the target altitude with some vertical speed,
and this causes it to overshoot and it begins a cycle of oscillations.
Instead of a picture like this,
we want the trajectory where our vehicle reaches the target value and then stays there.
And that means we want a graph that looks something like this.