Now, that you've been through the backyard Flyer Project,
you've had a chance to implement a simple planning, control strategy for your vehicle,
but only in simulation.
We set it up, so that you can also run it on a real vehicle.
And to help me get your software onto a real vehicle,
I'd like to introduce my friend, Adrien.
Adrien, you are a Ph.D. student at Stanford, right?
I am, by practice.
Yep, but you're also a drone expert.
I am. Well, expert, it's a tough word to use.
I've been around drones for quite a while.
So since, I've been about 12, I've been flying.
Initially, it was just fixed wings.
I used to build some of them, and then,
realized that I enjoyed flying them a lot more than building them.
And it was easier to just buy them, and then fly them.
And I used to do kind of tricks and acrobatics basically with fixed wings.
And then, five years ago,
when I started at Stanford,
I found a project that required using, kind of a quadcopter.
And I figured, well,
if I'm going to kind of do something on a quadcopter,
I should probably learn how to fly those.
So, I've been flying quads for the past, probably five years.
Do you know Adam Bry from Skydio from under the program?
I'm not familiar.
I think I've heard his name before but.
Yes, he's a former grad student of mine and he's background is very similar to yours.
He started building vehicles and he's very young,
and competed and then,
went to grad school and worked with me for a while.
So, Adrien, what we got here?
This is the Intel Aero.
It's called the Ready to Fly Drone.
So, it's about everything you need to fly, right in the box.
It comes all together as one piece.
But this is just one of many different types of drones.
There is somewhere, kind of much more do it yourself,
where you buy a frame here, and an autopilot there, and you put it together.
But this is what we're going to work with today.
I should note that while we're working with this today for our script,
that same script is going to be able to work with any
of the PX4 family of drones, right out of the box.
And we're working to try and get integration to maybe some of those other platforms,
like what you see from Parrot or DJI,
or some other manufacturers.
So, this is just an option. If you happen to have a drone,
the software that you've written so far should work on one family of drones,
and we'll try and make it work for everybody's drones.
All right. Can we open it up?
Let's do it.
All right. Man, this thing is really sealed tight.
I wish there was some way that we could get this box cover off.
Thanks box fairy, that was awesome. All right, what do we have here?
So, we've got our instruction manuals on top.
Instructions?
Which you should read.
And then, we've got our drone and our remote control.
Everything we're going to need to fly it.
All right. Let's take the drone out first.
Put that there.
Do you want to grab the, and there is one extra box right there, as well.
Box of tricks.
All right.
So, this should look fairly similar.
It's got all the main components that you've already learned about.
Okay.
We've got our frame, that carries the four motors.
Here, the speed control as we talked about,
that control the motors, are a little bit hidden.
If we flipped them upside down, you can see them.
There's one for each motor, one in each arm.
And then, we've got this big box in the center and that's
actually a combination autopilot and full computer.
So, in addition to being able to have
all those functionality that you get from an autopilot,
keep it stable and allow you to fly,
we have, what they call,
a companion computer on-board.
So, that's actually running on Ubuntu,
and you can run quite a lot of stuff on there,
and that's going to be for later down the road.
But for this first project,
we're not necessarily going to be using that.
All right, terrific. What's that?
That's a power module.
So, what that's taking
is going to be the power from the battery and converting the voltages
it needs for the computer to run and for all the motors.
Okay.
And then, this big guy here is our GPS antenna.
Let me screw that in there.
And it sits on a mass,
nice and far from all the noise that you get,
all that kind of radio frequency interference that is generated by the motors,
the speed control is by the computer, that's
so we can get kind of a clean GPS signal for positioning.
So, we've got our vehicle.
Yeah.
And we can't fly the vehicle without some way to give control commands.
And that's what our remote control is for.
Excellent.
There's a lot of switches and knobs on there,
but for the most part, the important ones are the joysticks.
Much like you would with a kind of game controller.
You've got throttle, for up down.
That's yaw to rotates our vehicle.
We've got roll and pitch.
So, that's going to be a way for us to physically,
as a pilot, input commands to the vehicle.
Although, with the software the students had written,
they shouldn't need to use this very much.
Correct.
Will they need it all?
They will need it to do some startup procedures.
It's always safest to be able to have a way to fall back to manual control of vehicle.
In case something goes wrong with the script or some odd behavior,
you want to be able to flip back and take control yourself.
Okay. So, we'll hold on to this.
And the last thing we have is propellers.
Comes with plenty of spares.
Not that any student has taken our Nanodegree would ever need a spare propeller.
So, we have two black and two silver. All right.
And you'll see, they are color coordinated,
and part of that,
so the silver ones are going to go on the white tops,
black ones are going to go on black tops.
And part of that is,
since they're rotating in different directions,
you want the propeller to lock into the motor
in a direction such that as the motor spinning, it won't unscrew.
So, that's why it keeps it easy to color coordinate.
So normally, we wouldn't be really putting the propellers on indoors.
Usually, you're going to do that outside, just before you take off.
But just to demonstrate what it looks like fully built,
here is our quad almost all ready to go.
You at least, would probably never want to have the props on,
when the battery is in, until you were actually ready to fly.
Yeah.
Safety. Speaking of which, the battery.
So, that is one thing that doesn't come when you purchase an Intel Aero.
So, you need to make sure that,
in addition to buying everything you see here,
you buy either a 3-cell or a 4-cell lithium polymer battery.
Do you need to buy battery for this, as well?
Comes with batteries.
This one comes with batteries.
But the vehicle itself, does not.
Correct.
All right. So, if you want to get your laptop,
we can order a battery from Amazon.
It'll be here in two business days?
I wonder if there's an easier way to get a battery.
Awesome. Thanks, battery fairy. There we go.
So, this is a 3-cell battery,
that is going to work with our quad.
When you say 3-cells,
there's actually a three different batteries inside there.
That's correct. And this will actually work with something also called the 4-cell.
which brings us to a conversation of what does 3-cell,
4-cell even mean.
So, with lithium polymer batteries,
they're a little bit different than most of the different batteries that,
for example what's in here.
Looks like four regular double A batteries.
And the remote control needs four batteries.
This thing needs basically,
the equivalent of putting three in a row or four together.
And what that's going to do is, just change the voltage that the battery is running at.
Motors and speed controllers are paired to work at specific voltages.
And so, you can get batteries in a different set of voltages.
Does that make it hard to charge the battery?
It does mean that when you charge the battery,
you needed to charge it for a specific voltage.
So, in this case, I need to charge it as a 3-cell battery.
If I start to charge it as a four-cell battery,
that's when you can start to damage the battery and can cause other problems.
So, battery safety is a big deal.
And so, you do need to have the right charger.
And if your battery ever becomes puffy and looks a little angry,
you need to dispose of it carefully.
Disposing it carefully means different things in different places,
so you should either check with your local health and safety officer,
if you're at a company, or you should consult
your city on how to dispose of damaged lithium polymer batteries.
They are very high energy density, very high power density.
They're basically, like little munitions and they will explode if you're not careful.
And in addition to charging at the right voltage,
there's this other big number that you usually see when you're buying batteries.
So, this is called a three-cell 4,000 milliamp power.
Now, at 4,000 milliamp power is capacity. It's duration.
How long will effectively we'll be able to fly,
basically it's four amp powers.
Bigger the number, the longer you can fly.
But when you charge,
it's also going to be a function of this number,
in addition to that voltage.
So, for example, this 4,000 milliamp power battery,
you can charge safely at four amps.
Once you start to push it to five, six, seven amps,
that's when you can, again start to damage or destroy the battery.
You're also perfectly safe to charge it at one amp.
It'll just take four times as long to charge. Great.