Adrien, we're ready to go.
Why are we not flying it?
It's always nice to, kind of bench test to make sure
it works here before we go out and fly it.
Last thing you want to do is have everything set up,
be out on the field, turn on, it doesn't work.
Okay, we're going to do this with the props off.
Yeah, it's the safest thing.
If you're going to be right next to it,
you don't necessarily want these to start spinning up,
and do something that you don't expect,
maybe come and hit you.
So, it's always the nicest to take them off, set them on the bench.
Especially, if there are other quad-rotors around,
you wouldn't want somebody else's transmitter to bind
to your vehicle and take off with the props on.
Very much, so.
All right, cool. So, what's first?
So, first things first,
we'll turn on our transmitter.
So, we're going to have control when we turn it on.
We'll turn on our Aero.
Okay.
And that's going to take a minute to boot up.
And it creates a Wi-Fi hotspot that we're going to connect to,
and that's what's going to allow us to control and send different commands.
And this is very similar even,
if you don't have an Intel Aero,
if you have one of the 3D robotics vehicles,
or if you even have a DJI vehicles,
doing very similar things.
Yep.
Your password is 1-2-3-4-5?
No. It is always helpful when you log in.
Well done. I've got to change my login now.
So, couple of things I'm checking are,
one, up here, just to look at the fact that we have got GPS.
So, right now we've got 17 satellites.
And we've got a GPS lock.
It's a pretty good position.
Great.
So, we're showing up. The other things,
I'm just going to double check is that,
my mode switches are configured the way I want.
So, mode switches allow me, as the pilot,
to change the control methods of the drone.
So, whether I'm flying manually or in something called altitude hold.
So, where it's holding altitude or position control,
where it's holding position or most importantly,
off board, which gives the script the control of the drone.
So, I like to just quickly look here.
It says manual.
It says altitude position,
and then, it's going to reject off-board because it does run when it needs to.
So, I just always like to double check that my switches are configured the way we want.
Great.
So, I'm confident everything's working well on autopilot here.
So, we're going to close out a key ground control.
All right, so now, we're ready to run the script.
So, we're going to run the script and so, it's just going to
wait there for everything to be set,
for the pilot to give it control,
and then, it should take off.
Terrific.
So, what I'm going to do is, I'm going to arm the motors.
You see the motor started to spin and they're just idling.
And then, I'm going to give control of the vehicle to the script.
We see the motors spins, so it's armed.
And then, we hear the motor spin up.
As it's trying to take off.
Script actually fix as trying to run the vehicle.
Of course, a vehicle without the props on,
can't actually do the mission right now.
So, great, let's stop this.
And I'm actually, going to take it.
So now, I've taken it out of control.
I've killed the motors. Now, I can turn off the script.
Great.
So now, we know everything works.
We can put the props on and go fly the mission for real.
Yep.
Let's go do that.
Let's do it.
All right. So, Adrian, we're here,
we got the vehicle on the pad with the props on, ready to go?
Yeah. So, you can go ahead and get that script started.
Okay, before we do that, let's check to make sure the airspace is clear.
See, no one else is flying right now.
Nope.
And everyone is well behind us.
Great.
And we can see on the screen that the vehicle
is on the overhead map where we expect it to be.
Good. All right, I will go ahead and start the script.
And now, I'm going to arm the motors,
and now, I'm going to give control of the vehicle to the script.
I see the motors armed.
And there we go, and it's taking off.
Going to three meters.
And now, it's off to its first waypoint.
First waypoint, second waypoint,
third waypoint,
and coming home.
Very nice.
So, now I'll take control of the drone again.
So, I can then disarm it manually.
Okay, I'll kill the script.
There we go.
And that's another difference between what we've done with this script here,
and what we see on the simulator.
On the simulator, once it detects it's landed,
it will disarm the motors and kill the script.
While here, we're going to leave it to
the pilot to take back control of disarming the motors.
All right, terrific. And nice work on the autopilot.