All right, what's next?
We just need to plug this guy in and then.
Let's take the props off now.
Yup. When you plug it in,
you always want to make sure this cable can't be hit by a propeller.
So, for example, the way we have it plugged in
now is probably not the way you'll want to plug it in when we fly.
I find it's actually pretty useful.
You can run this connector through one of the legs.
So, you can bring it around and run the battery connected through one of the legs.
And you can see now that the cable is,
no matter how much it moves,
its not going to hit the propeller.
So, always before we turn on the drone,
we want to be able to turn on our remote.
So, we'll turn that on first. Big power switch.
All right.
Throttle should always be down before you turn on the drone.
Part of the reason we're doing this is to make
sure that we are going to be the ones in control of our drone.
The last thing you want is to turn this on and
some other guys remote to pair with your drone and all of a sudden they have control.
So, that's on, we'll turn our arrow on,
and give it a minute to boot up.
How do we know when it's done booting?
We'll actually see a Wi-Fi network
that's generated by this vehicle that we'll be able to connect to.
For other systems usually,
it's flashing light, an auditory signal.
Most have some way to communicate from the drone to the ground. Connecting.
Shall we do a motor spin test?
Yes, we can.
All right.
Here we go. And if you want to throttle up,
you'll be able to hear the motors speed up.
This is why you don't put the props on indoors,
because if I armed the motors accidentally,
and then I hit the throttle up, the vehicle will take off.
Yup.