Can I go ahead and fly?
Still one more thing.
We've talked that there are different kinds of control modes.
There are different ways that you can fly or
different ways that your input can affect the vehicle.
One of the most basic ways is manual,
which means every piece of information I put in is going directly,
more or less, to the motors.
It means that it's not going to try and hold the position.
It's not going to try and hold an altitude.
It'll drift, it'll bounce around.
So that's kind of the lowest level of control.
But the attitude loop is all the way running.
Correct, yes.
So the vehicles, you don't have to worry about keeping the vehicle level.
Correct.
That part will always work.
Yes. And then, there are a couple other modes that
I've configured the arrow to use that I recommend.
One is called altitude control.
So, what that does is it takes
you having to worry about the throttle out of the equation.
It holds a fixed altitude.
So while you're flying you can then focus on just where its horizontal position.
Note, that it still will drift with the wind.
It's not trying to hold this specific position.
So on a windy day, you've got to be careful,
or else it will get away from you.
The next one is position control.
And what now, we're doing is adding
just one more control loop that the autopilot is taking care of.
It's going to try and hold the position.
So now my commands are really just moving
around this fixed point that it's going to hold.
So on a windy day, should stay fixed.
The last mode, this can be of interest to something called off-board control,
and that's you as a pilot,
releasing control to the computer,
to our backyard flyers script.
So it's always called off-board mode, I know that.
It's kind of a misnomer, cause its really it's on-board control, isn't it?
That's well, I mean, it's off-board of the main auto pilot board,
it's a secondary computer.
Off-board this, on-board there.
Yeah. Correct.
Very good.
And so one thing that we can do is we've got
some of these switches are set up to change between those modes.
So we can look on the ground station to make sure that as I flip the switches,
it's correctly cycling between
the desired modes and rejecting the modes that it can't go into yet.