So, some of the basic controls you need to know just
to get started is arming and disarming.
So, that's going to be getting the motors ready to take
commands and releasing the motors from that state.
So, down into the right is going to arm the motors which gets them to start spinning.
And when you want to kind of turn everything off,
it's going be down and to the left.
And down to the right again to arm.
And I have throttle up and make the vehicle take off.
I can yaw and fly at high speed into the wall to the right,
fly at high speed into the wall to the left.
The only other set of switches on here that's going to be important to know,
are going to be the way we have it configured it's going to be these two switches.
Will the students running the same script have
the same configuration or do they have to know how to configure it?
One of the screencasts is to walk into the configuration,
so it's going to be through queue ground control.
We're actually able to change the configurations on the autopilot and one of them
is to configure the switches to be able to change different control modes.
So one of the things you're going to want to do is go through
that configuration process before you take your vehicle outside.
Very much so. So, we've got two sets of
switches are going to help us get
through all the different states that we're going to want.
When this switch is all the way towards you,
when both this switches are all the way towards you.
This one and this one.
Correct.
That's going to be manual control.
So, that's going to be the most basic amount of input that you can get.
This top switch in middle position,
is what we are going to call our main assisted modes.
So, middle position bottom that's going to be altitude mode.
So, the vehicle is going to try and hold
its altitude which means you don't have to worry as much about the throttling input.
But it will drift left and right. Correct.
Middle position is position control.
And that means it's going to be working to hold its position.
So, when you release your hand from all the commands,
it should hold where it is and not drift with any wind.
And then finally, when it's time to turn that script on
all the way up, puts it into off-board control.
So, that releases control from you the pilot, to the computer.
So, a process that I might go through is a fully manual mode.
Arming the vehicle, put it in an assist mode.
And now, I'm in off-board mode,
puts all the control, on-board the vehicle, and then we start our script.
Correct.
Very good.
Normally, you want to bring it back to manual before you disarm.
All right. Good point.
So, everything that we have here, this remote,
this vehicle, it's specifically for this this drone.
There are many different ones out there that you can get.
Most remotes actually do look more or less the same.
You're always have these two joysticks and some collection of switches.
So for your vehicle,
if you have your own custom build at home,
your switches may be configured differently,
and maybe you prefer to have right handed versus a left handed system.
But what's nice is with this autopilot,
if this doesn't really work for you in that screencast,
we'll show you how to configure it.
So, if you want to change up the switches,
you definitely can to something that's a little bit more your style.
Great.