Before we do go outside,
in addition to all the common sense safety things we've been talking about,
there are some regulatory issues you need to be aware of.
Depending on which country you're in,
and even depending on which part of which country you're in,
the rules may be different.
And so, the first thing you have to do is, know before you fly.
In the US, it's important that you follow the part 107 rules.
Which means that you,
as a pilot, especially,
if you're doing anything that is not just your personal hobbyist entertainment,
need to have an actual pilot's license for an autonomous vehicle.
And you can go on the FAA website,
and you take a paper test and then, you're good to go.
And if you are a hobbyist, you don't even need the part 107 license.
But it's really important that you actually
understand whether or not you're allowed to fly where you're planning to fly.
A good guideline is,
Adrien already mentioned, don't fly over people, don't fly over buildings.
Another important guideline is,
don't fly near airports.
Again, in the US, there are restrictions on how
close you can be to different kinds of airports,
and you need to know what those are.
And in other countries, it may be different.
Other regulatory issues?
The only thing that I would add is,
if you're strictly doing this as a hobbyist,
as you pointed out, you don't need to get a specific license.
But you do need to follow a community set of guidelines if there are.
So you can check out,
there's the Academy of Model Aeronautics.
They've got a lot of rules or guidelines,
and then, either way,
you do need, what they call register your drone.
It's a fairly painless process.
You go online, you put your name,
what kind of vehicle it is,
and you get a registration number that should be taped somewhere on the drone.