For those following along who have the Intel Aero.
In this video we will walk through a couple checks to
make sure the aero software is up to date and fully ready to go.
We can communicate with the Intel Aero by
connecting to a Wi-Fi hotspot that it generates.
And that's going to be the way that we're going to get information
down from the aero and commands up to the aero.
Using that same hotspot we can actually login to
the computer itself to make sure that the software is up to date.
So to do that, we're going to turn on our drone,
and it takes a couple minutes for it to boot up and get the computer up and running.
In the meantime what we're going to do is we're going to navigate
to our network settings to be able to
find and wait for the Wi-Fi hotspot generated by the Intel Aero to come online.
Here we go, so here we can look at our list of network names and
we'll see one that starts with an aero dash as the prefix,
for any of you who might have something that looks different,
now another option is that it might say AP or CAP dash and then long number here.
If you don't have aero dash as the prefix to the Wi-Fi hotspot it means that
the Intel Aero is running an outdated version of
the software and you'll need to go ahead and update the software.
So for updating the software the Intel has a pretty detailed Wikipedia with
tutorials on how to update different software and
navigate parts of the Intel Aero computer.
Provided that you have the correct firmware,
or software, we can connect to the network.
Again Intel has in their detailed documentation here,
a page all about network that reminds you of what the password is to the Wi-Fi hotspot.
So, they also list the IP address of
the drone so that what we're going to go ahead and connect to.
So we'll SSH into the drone and the only user is root,
so we'll SSH as root.
So we'll go ahead and connect as root to the Intel Aero.
So now we are the SSH-ed into the Intel Aero itself.
So this is the computer that runs on-board of our drone.
This computer manages that network connection to
the ground and it also manages the running of the autopilot on-board.
So the first thing we're gonna do is we're going to check to make sure that
we have the most up to date version of the software,
and with that Intel provides a simple script to be able to test,
to be able to print out the version information and that's
going to be aero-get-version.py,
which is also shown here in their tutorial.
So now we'll run that. And we can see that we're running aero version 1.00.13.
It has the flight control firmware version is 1.6.5 which at the time of this recording,
this is the most up to date version of the software and this is what you will
need to be running in order for backyard flyer to work properly on the aero.
If this is not the version number,
specifically if these top portions don't match
with what I have on my screen here or with what Intel shows as the most recent version,
then please go ahead and follow this initial setup Wiki that
they have and instructions to update your software.
You'll notice this last line says flight control firmware version and that's
just telling us the version of the autopilot that's running currently.
And so by default it runs the PX4 autopilot,
and should provide a number like that.
If for whatever reason it doesn't seem to be running
PX4 or it seems to have a different version number,
we can update just the autopilot software itself by running this set of commands.
If your version information matches this are the
most up-to-date version on Intel's website,
then means we are good to go and we can move on to the next step.
Before we can fully fly backyard flyer on our drone,
we will need to configure PX4,
the autopilot that's running on board but for that,
we'll be using a ground control software.
So see you in the next video for that.