Alright. So, one of the things we'll do to test out and
make sure everything is running properly on the autopilot is,
I'm opening up a piece of software called, QGroundControl.
This is an open-source ground station software.
It's not like the simulator or what you've been interacting,
what the students have been interacting with the simulator,
and during the project.
This is an open-source ground station that's used commonly
for a lot of these more DIY style drones.
And what it does is, it gives us state information.
It allows us to actually even see things like attitude information in real-time,
and other configurations that we might have to change from the defaults.
This is the basic interface for QGroundControl,
and we've got our main window with our map,
that's going to display where our drone is,
and we've got a couple of tabs along the top.
But really, there's not too much to look at until we connect a vehicle.
So, let's go ahead and turn on our arrow,
make sure remote control first and no propellers.
And once that's on,
and up and running, let's connect to its network.
Once its connected, QGroundControl will
automatically see that a new drone has been connected,
and will ask us to connect.
So, we'll go ahead and allow that connection, and now,
you'll see we've got a few more options along the top,
and we've got this green loading bar.
Once that green bar goes all the way across,
it means that all the parameters and settings
from the drone have been downloaded into QGroundControl.
So, just to walk through the interface that we have in front of us here,
I'm going to start from the top bar and work my way across.
This "Q" button here,
this purple "Q" button is configuration files for Q ground control itself,
and also communication links.
So, if it didn't automatically connect,
this is where you can manually add different types of links,
whether it's a serial connection,
if you're using something like
a 3DR radio to connect to your drone or an internet-based connection.
The next tab is going to be settings,
and this is where you'll find all the information
about the autopilot settings and configurations.
This is just a summary page that shows us
the quick view of all the different states and important information.
You'll see there's a bunch of green dots along these tabs,
and that tells us things are configured and ready to go.
If you just installed the autopilot,
you may notice some red circles,
and that tells you that you need to configure
some parameters before the autopilot will let you take off.
We got a whole list of different possible settings that we can look into,
which we'll come back to in a minute.
The next tab is for being able to do
high-level planning to use the autopilot's inbuilt mission handling.
We're actually not going to be using this tab for this Nanodegree,
however, feel free to explore this on your own.
The next tab is our main flight tab, and this is,
that's going to show us where our drone is currently on the map,
and information like our current orientation and heading speed, and other information.
And finally, this tab allows us to connect and look at logs that are on board the vehicle.
Again, we won't make too much use of this tab throughout this Nanodegree,
but it's just so you know it's there.
Next, we have a bull horn for messages.
Right now, there's no messages from the drone,
but this is where important information, for example,
it telling you something isn't calibrated,
or mode changes will appear here.
Next, we have our GPS status.
Right now, we are inside,
so it's going to show us that we're not connected to any GPS signals.
But normally, what you're going to be looking for before you take off,
that you've got to account in above,
probably eight is what you'll see,
and these numbers will be much smaller around one or two.
This tells us the controller information,
the connection status to the remote control,
which is on, but seems to be not providing data at the moment.
And finally, our battery status.
So, this is the voltage of our current battery,
and it's going to go from 100 percent to somewhere around 30,
40 percent, you should most definitely be landing.
This is our current flight mode that we have.
Right now, we're in manual,
which means that the pilot has the most basic amount of control,
and we'll be able to cycle through those different modes,
things like altitude hold or position hold that we've mentioned
before as we change through those modes with our remote control,
that will be updated here accordingly.
Finally, the armed versus disarmed state,
and that tells us, "Are the motors ready to spin and take commands?"