So let's head back to that settings tab and let's make sure
that we've got our autopilot configured in the way we want.
First thing down this list of interests is the sensors tab.
Just say okay to that.
In the sensors, it's going to tell you the state of calibration for our compass,
or gyro, the accelerometers,
what we define as level,
and here you'll see you've got green dots down the line
which means everything has been calibrated and taken care of.
However, as I mentioned,
if you just installed the autopilot,
these may have some red dots appear.
And in those cases,
what you'll need to do is click the appropriate sensor,
and walk through the configuration.
In this window here,
it'll show you the steps you need to take,
and it will walk you through the calibration process.
So the next one down the line is radio.
And the intel arrow should already come configured with the radio calibrations,
but in case it isn't or if you have your own drone,
you'll want to go ahead and make sure you calibrate the radio,
and once again it will walk you through that calibration process.
We're taking a quick stop through this page though because it's
a great way to monitor and look to make sure that everything's working.
So, for example as I move the throttle we'll see that throttle dot increase and decrease,
and the same for roll, pitch, and yaw.
Why we stopped here is before we go on to configuring our flight modes,
we want to know what switches we have access to.
And you may not know exactly how the radio is configured so that we can do is we can
go through and toggle some of the different switches on our radio.
For example, as I toggle this one,
we notice that channel five moves.
And we get actually an urgent notification,
which we'll ignore for the moment.
And as I change this switch,
I've got channel seven.
As I move the other switches,
I don't see other channels go so that tells me I have channels
five and seven have switches that will allow me to configure my flight modes,
which we'll go ahead and do now.
So, most likely when you came to the flight modes tab,
you were visited with a screen like this.
And it allows you to assign different flight modes to those three positions.
However it's a little bit limited because it only allows us to choose three options.
So what we're gonna do is use this multi-channel mode selection.
This allows us to couple switches on
channel five and seven to give us a wider range of flight mode options.
So we're gonna go ahead and do that and you'll see in the position I have it here,
it says it's stabilized main.
So now what happens is that channel five
switch which is a three positions which allows us
to choose between main, assisted, and mission.
We won't be using mission,
this is the PX4 mode that allows you to
execute those missions that you can configure up in this A to B tab.
Assist now defaults to using channel seven that second switch,
to be able to configure a second kind of set of flight modes.
So in this case, we can be in
an assisted mode in either altitude hold or position control.
And that's the way I have it configured.
I've changed, you can slide these for changing the thresholds.
So I can toggle between altitude and position control now,
and then finally I've set the last position in the switch
to be, I set it to channel seven to be off board control.
And you'll keep seeing as we get these notifications
reject position control or reject off-board control.
We can go ahead and take a look at those.
The reason those are being rejected right now is that we don't have GPS.
In order to be in either position control or off-board,
the autopilot is using GPS in the loop to make decisions.
So, it won't allow you to be in those modes if you don't have GPS.
Altitude hold actually just uses
the barometer on-board so it doesn't need GPS in order to work,
which is why it allows us to go into altitude hold.
Well let's bring it back into manual and I don't know if you've
noticed up here as I switch through these,
the mode is displayed appropriately at the top.
So now we have our switches configured,
and that allows us to switch through the different flight modes which will
be tremendously helpful when we go outside and actually fly.
The next one that we're going to look at is power.
And this is just to make sure that if you're flying a three-cell battery,
you've properly marked up three-cells or if you're flying a four-cell battery,
you've made that four-cells.
This just makes it possible for
the battery status to display correct information about the percentage.
If you have the wrong configuration here,
it may overestimate or underestimate the amount of flight time that you have remaining.
Finally, we're going to make a couple optional changes.
We're going to go down to this parameters tab.
And this lists all the different possible parameters for the PX4 autopilot.
I'll leave it to you to kind of flip through
and get an idea of what different options there are,
but what we're going to go through is we're going to go
into this multicopter position control.
These are the parameters that dictate the behavior of
our drone when it's under position control or autonomous control.
So really this is a lot of dictation of
the behavior that will happen when your script is running.
I'm going to make two changes in this file,
purely for point of view safety and just to slow things down a little bit.
It'll give you more time to kind of react if something goes wrong,
and just more time to enjoy watching Backyard Flyer do its thing.
So we're going to go ahead and change this MPC_XY_CRUISE.
So this is the cruise velocity.
This is the speed at which it's going to move in the XY plane.
And we're going to bring that down to four meters per second,
which sounds slow but it definitely allows you
to really watch and see what's happening with the drone while it's flying.
So we'll hit save on that,
and then we'll go down and change that maximum velocity.
We'll bring that down to five meters per second,
and we'll go ahead and save that.
As you get more comfortable with flying your drone,
feel free to increase these numbers and see just how
quickly the arrow can actually fly the Backyard Flyer loop.
But for now, we'll keep things nice and slow.
So with those last configuration changes made,
we are good to go.
We're ready to fly,
provided we were outside with GPS.
And now we can move on to making some changes to
the Backyard Flyer script to make sure it connects with our drone,
and we'll change a couple of the state machine elements.
But that's for the next video.