Just like how unbalanced forces cause translational acceleration,
unbalanced moments cause rotational acceleration.
And the equation that relates these quantities looks like this,
torque is equal to I times alpha.
This is the equation you might see in an introductory physics class.
Here, torque is the net torque around a given axis.
And remember, I'm using the word torque interchangeably with moment.
Alpha is the angular acceleration about the same axis,
so it tells me how fast my rotational speed is changing.
The units for alpha are radians per second squared.
And this I is a little more interesting.
It's a quantity called Moment of Inertia.
And it's a measure of how hard it is to change
an object's rotational velocity about a particular axis.
Remember that a quadrotor can roll around its x-axis,
pitch around its y-axis,
and yaw around its z-axis.
And in general, the moment of inertia can be different for each of these axes.
We will see later,
that to describe the three-dimensional quadrotor motion,
the moment of inertia will be a three by three matrix,
and torque and alpha are vectors.
For the purposes of this lesson,
we'll only be thinking about one axis of rotation at a time.
For our monorotor example,
we are only considering yaw about the z-axis,
so we only need to pay attention to Iz,
and alpha and the torque are scalar values.
In the world of quadrotor dynamics,
people tended to use the word moment over torque.
And we usually use the Greek letter psi to represent yaw.
So, another way to write this torque equation is like this,
Mz is equal to Iz times psi double dot.
And this is just another way of saying,
that a moment about the z-axis will cause an acceleration in the psi coordinate.
Now, let's try applying this,
first by answering a few questions,
and then by programming up a more general solution.
In the next few segments,
the vehicle we will be discussing is a co-axial helicopter,
which is just a body with two rotors on top of each other.
These rotors both produce upward thrusts,
but they do so by spinning in opposite directions.