In this exercise, you were asked to implement
three methods of this CoaxialCopter class.
The first was this z_dot_dot method,
and that just returned the current vertical acceleration
based on whatever the propellers were doing.
Then, you were asked to calculate the psi_dot_dot,
which is the rotational acceleration about the Z axis,
and then this function set-rotors-angular-velocities,
in this function, you actually set the correct angular rotation rates for each of
the propellers based on
whatever linear acceleration and angular acceleration you wanted the vehicle to have.
Now to show you how I solved this,
I want to show you a technique you can use in this and in future notebooks,
which is, first you click on this Jupyter icon up here in the top left.
And that takes you to this navigation page.
And you can see here, all of the notebooks for this lesson are at this navigation page.
Here I have coaxial drone dynamic solution, so I can click into that.
And if I scroll down to the CoaxialCopter class,
sure enough I will see that I have an implemented version of this z_dot_dot function.
And let me walk you through how this implementation works.
So first, step one, calculate the forces.
And for each propeller,
that was just k_f times omega squared.
Next, I had to calculate the force of gravity, the weight force,
and that's just M times G. Now to sum up this total force,
I had to be a little careful,
I had to remember that Z pointing down is positive,
so f_g is the positive one here,
and f_1 and f_2 are both negative,
and then the acceleration is just the total force divided by the mass.
So, that's what we want to return it.
The thinking is pretty similar for the psi_dot_dot,
so I'm not going to walk through that yet.
But this one's a little more interesting,
and really, there's a bunch of math going on here,
and I don't want to walk through actually solving out this math,
but I do want to point you to what equations this math came from.
And if I scroll up, you can see these two equations are the ones we really care about.
Remember that set rotors function,
it took a z_dot_dot and the psi_dot_dot as arguments,
so these are fixed for that function's point of view.
So now we have these two equations with two unknowns.
Omega one is unknown,
and Omega two is unknown.
If you solve these equations for those variables,
you'll find the math that you need to implement
to actually implement the function correctly.
Next, you're going to actually implement a function called advanced state,
which actually tracks the state of the vehicle over time.
And when you can implement a function like advanced state,
you've really proven that you understand the dynamics of the system,
because if you can advance the state forward in time,
well that means you understand how all the forces impact the motion of the vehicle.