In order to claim that I understand the dynamics of a system like the CoaxialCopter,
I need to be able to the track,
the motion of that system over time.
So at this point the first thing I need to do,
is make some changes right in
the initializer so that I can actually track the state of the system.
So I need to add some state variables,
and I'm going to add a variable for Z and psi.
I'm going to start those both off with values of zero.
Now, I want to advance these state variables forward in time by
however much dt time I want and I'm going to
do that in a method called advanced state uncontrolled.
And this uncontrolled, this just
emphasizes that what we're doing is we're pretending like the rotors aren't spinning,
that this copter is just in free fall.
It's actually not that useful of a function,
but I'm really just walking through the logic of how I think through
it so that you can implement the advanced state function yourself.
So the first thing I want to do in this function, well,
I want to realize that there's not going to be any rotational acceleration.
If the rotors aren't turning,
there's not going to be any torque on the system,
not any moment on the system,
and so there's not going to be any rotational acceleration.
So the first thing I have to do is only figure out
the linear acceleration of the systems, z_dot_dot.
And for a quadrotor,
or I should say a coaxial copter under free fall,
that would just be the acceleration due to gravity.
Now I have to think, what is this acceleration actually do to the system?
Well remember, I'm advancing the state forward by dt seconds.
And acceleration over time changes a velocity.
So a change in velocity alright is delta_z_dot,
and that's just going to be equal to z_dot_dot times this dt.
This change in velocity is actually reminding
me that I haven't written enough state variables up here.
It's not enough to just know Z and psi,
I also have to track z_dot and psi_dot.
And together these four comprise my state variables,
Z, psi and their derivatives.
So the new velocity,
vertical velocity of the system is equal to the old vertical velocity,
plus whatever the changes.
So just as I went through the process of figuring out how z_dot_dot changed z_dot,
now I have to figure out how the velocity changes the position.
Well, a velocity over time causes the delta_z. Just like this.
And this delta_z, gets just directly added to update my new Z value.
So my Z value is just the old Z value plus the change.
So I am going to execute the cell and
then that takes me down to this next cell right here,
which is just a bit of logic to actually
plot the course of the vehicle over two seconds of flight in the air,
or I should say two seconds of freefall.
So let's execute this cell,
and this is what I get.
And this plot looks pretty consistent for what the vertical position
should be doing overtime for an object in freefall.
Now, you should write the actual advanced state function.
And this one is going to be different in a couple of ways.
One, it's going to have to take into account what the rotors are doing.
And two, because the rotors are now doing something,
that's going to introduce the potential for a moment on the system,
which means you are going to have to track the change in rotational motion as well.