The function you just worked with is responsible for
advancing the state of the vehicle by dt seconds.
And for uncontrolled vehicle,
the only information we need to be able to do that,
is the current state of the vehicle,
which is captured in this reference to self,
and that's pretty amazing.
Now, the important thing I want you to notice about this code,
are these few lines.
Even so, we are working with a very simple system here,
these lines of code capture
much more widely useful mathematical strategy for
solving these sorts of state update problems.
And that strategy involves three steps.
Step number one, we figure out what the accelerations
and rotational acceleration of the system will be at the current instant.
For a quadrotor whose orders aren't spinning,
the acceleration just comes from gravity,
which is 9.81 meters per second squared.
Step two, we use this acceleration to
update the associated velocities or rates of change.
Step number three, we use the velocity to update the associated position.
Note, how similar step two and three look.
That's because mathematically, we are doing the same thing.
We're accumulating change by calculating,
well really we are numerically approximating the integral.
And because we need to integrate twice to figure
out how the acceleration ultimately influences the motion,
this is what's known as a second order system,
or a double integrator.
Mathematically, the reason this is a second order system,
is because the equations that govern how the system
evolves with time, includes second derivatives.
And this equation for a vehicle moving in the vertical directions just
says that forces directly influenced the second derivative of position.
And since we can generally figure out what the forces will be on the quadrotor,
you can generally figure out what the accelerations will be.
And then it's just a matter of integrating twice to go from acceleration,
to velocity, to position.
An important consequence of this,
is that we need to keep track of both the position,
and the velocity of the vehicle.
But nothing more, if we want to be able to keep
advancing the state of the vehicle forward by dt.