So this is my solution to the advanced state function.
And when I look through this code,
I actually see a lot of repetition.
And in particular, this code looks a lot like this code,
which looks a lot like this code,
which looks a lot like this code.
And in fact we have four of these repetitive blocks of code,
one for each of our state variables,
and each of them is doing essentially the same thing.
They're taking some quantity,
multiplying it by dt,
and using this result to update some other quantity.
It would be nice to have a more compact representation of this state than
just using these four separate state variables and updating each independently.
So what we're going to do is we're going to think in
terms of state vectors instead of state variables.
So here, first thing I'm going to do is I'm going to get rid of
these four variables, four state variables,
we're going to place them with
a single state vector which I'm going to call upper case X,
and it's just going to be an np.array with four values in it,
and these values correspond to z,
psi, z_dot, and psi_dot.
And what's going to be nice about representing state this way,
is if we do things right,
we're going to be able to update all of these quantities all at once.
So instead of this version of advanced state,
we're going to use this version of advanced state.
And in this version we just have this one vector called capital X_dot.
And we multiply this X_dot vector by this dt,
the amount of seconds we're advancing the state forward to get a single delta x,
which represents how all those state variables change all at once and then we
say the new state is just the old state plus this delta x.
And so written now, in terms of math which is probably a little easier to think about,
we have this updated state vector which is z, z_dot, psi,
psi_dot prime, which is just equal to
the old state vector plus dt times the corresponding derivatives for each of these.
And this is a pretty slick way of doing this state update,
and it's something you'll see more of in later lessons.
And honestly now, at this point,
we've said just about everything there is to say about this coaxial copter.
Now, we're going to move to
a more complex vehicle where the two propellers are side by side.