So far, you've written code to update
the state of a vehicle for two different situations.
First, for a controlled copter which moved only in the set direction,
and second, for an uncontrolled vehicle free falling in two dimensions.
And in both cases,
the forces were only in the vertical direction.
In both situations, you had gravity pointing down,
and in the first situation,
you also had thrust,
but that always pointed upwards for the 1-D case.
This made it easy to figure out the net force on the vehicle.
When the vehicle is allowed to pitch overall,
and actually turn on its rotors,
then we have to handle forces at weird angles like this.
In the next two sections,
I will show you how you can use trigonometry to decompose forces in two dimensions,
and then I will also show you an equation for calculating torques,
which you will need to use in calculating pitch and roll in a quadrotor.