Here, we have a vehicle inclined at some angle phi.
And note, when I say it's inclined at some angle,
I'm saying that the vehicle is inclined with respect to the world reference frame.
And the reference frame has a z-axis which points
downwards and a y-axis that points to the right.
And that means that the thrust vector makes
an angle with the vertical axis of the world frame.
Now, we want to decompose this vector into
vertical and horizontal components in
the directions of the coordinate axis of our world frame.
That will look like this.
Now, since this is a right angle,
we can use the tools of trigonometry to
solve for the horizontal and the vertical components of the thrust.
The way we do that is by writing out
trigonometric relationships and then solving for what we don't know.
So, for example, I know that the sine of phi is equal to
the opposite side divided by the hypotenuse,
which in this case, it's the horizontal component of force divided by the total force.
We can solve this equation to find that the horizontal component of
thrust is just the total thrust times the sine of the angle phi.
We can apply similar reasoning to find that the vertical component of
thrust is just the total thrust times the cosine of phi.
It's worth noting that we worked exclusively in the world frame here.
And generally, we can figure out this dynamics in
two dimension without having to work in the body frame,
which, remember, is the coordinate frame that's fixed to the vehicle body.
When we get to three-dimensional dynamics in the fourth lesson,
that will no longer be the case.