Now, we'd like to describe the full two-dimensional motion of the vehicle.
We've discussed how a rotor that's turning clockwise,
will introduce a counter-clockwise moment about the axis of rotation.
And we call this reaction moment,
because it's a rotational moment that is
an opposite reaction to some other rotational motion.
But reaction moments only explain yaw.
What about pitch and roll?
When the left rotors produce more stress than the right rotors,
the quad rotor will experience a clockwise acceleration.
And that's because the rotors on the left side,
produce a clockwise moment which is bigger than
the counter-clockwise moment produced by the rotors on the right side.
The moment that causes this rotation is
slightly different than the reaction moment that causes yaw.
This torque comes from a force that acts perpendicular to the axis of rotation,
at some distance from the center of the vehicle.
And the magnitude of this torque,
is found by multiplying this perpendicular distance by that force.
The example torque calculations below this video,
should make this calculation a little more clear.