At this point, you have some intuitive understanding of how the rotation rates of
four propellers can lead to four quantities that we are actually most interested in.
The collective upwards thrust,
the total moment about the x axis,
which causes the vehicle to roll,
the total moment about the y axis,
which causes the vehicle to pitch,
and the total reaction moment about the set axis which causes the vehicle to yaw.
When we analyze the dynamics of a vehicle with
a side-by-side rotor configuration that moves in two-dimensions,
we only need to consider the first two quantities.
As you'll see in the next segment,
it's possible to write code that directly translates
the rotation rates of the two motors into a collective thrust,
and a moment about the x axis.