At this point, we've actually covered all the underlying physics of
quadrotor flight or at least the physics that we'll be modeling.
You've seen how a propeller generates a thrust and
a yaw inducing reaction moment that are
both proportional to the square of the rotation rate.
You've also seen how gravity,
along with these thrusts,
influenced the translational acceleration of the vehicle.
And you've also seen how these thrusts produce
torques which can cause the quadrotor to pitch and roll.
And really, that's about it for the physics that we really need to consider for now.
Now, it's time to write
the advanced state method for a controlled drone that flies in two dimensions.
Writing this method will require you to put
together everything you've learned in this lesson.
We'll be providing a solution as well,
but try your best to solve this on your own.