Welcome to the first lesson of controls.
This lesson is called Vehicle Dynamics.
My name is Angela Schoellig and I will be your instructor for this course.
And my name is Andy Brown and I'll be
popping in occasionally to explain a concept or two,
but mostly I'll be helping you as you work through
the programming exercises that you'll encounter throughout this course.
So, Angela, can you explain what do we mean when we talk about vehicle dynamics?
Well, dynamics is concerned with the motion of bodies under the action of forces.
So for our purposes,
vehicle dynamics means understanding how the rotation of
the drone's four propellers creates
forces and how these forces generate motion of the vehicle.
And in this lesson,
you'll be learning how to model these forces
mathematically in Python and then you'll use those models
to advance the current state of the vehicle into
the future to actually predict the motion of flying vehicles.
Exactly, and there are plenty of reasons why we need to build these models.
But from a control standpoint,
having a good dynamic model of the vehicle allows us to
intelligently influences the output of the vehicle by properly setting the inputs.
And what do we mean when we talk about inputs and outputs for something like a drone?
Right. So for a drone,
the input would be the rotation rates of
the four propellers and the output would be the resulting motion of the vehicle.
Sounds good. Let's get started.