One way of thinking about the controller problem is this.
Given a desire trajectory,
find the continuous sequence of
propeller rotation rates that will cause the drone to fly along that trajectory.
A trajectory is a sequence of 3D positions and yaw,
and associated times at which you want to be at that position and yaw.
In this lesson, you've worked on a similar but reversed version of the problem.
In fact, the problem you know how to solve now is best described by this.
Given a continuous sequence of propeller rotation rates,
predict the trajectory that the drone will fly.
And you solve this for the 2D case when you implemented the advanced state function.
And solving this problem isn't trivial.
Starting with nothing but an ability to set
the rotational rates of the propellers, you had to do,
one, know how those rotational rates lead to thrusts and moments about the X,
Y and Z body axis.
Two, know how thrusts and moments affect the acceleration and rotation of the vehicle.
And three, know how accelerations when
integrated twice affect the actual position and orientation of the vehicle.
And then, on top of that,
you had to implement all of that in code. Good job.
In the next lesson,
you'll learn how to use something called a PID controller to go the other way,
and convert a desire trajectory into a continuous sequence of
rotor commands that actually control a drone to track the target trajectory.