To understand the dynamics that is the motion of a quadrotor,
we need to understand the forces that act on it.
In case it's been a while since you've taken a physics class,
we are going to do a pretty quick review of the basic physics in this lesson.
A force is just a push or a pull on an object.
In order to support this quadrotor,
my arms are exerting a force upwards,
which is equal in size to the force that gravity exerts downwards.
In flight, a quadrotor is not supported by anyone's arms.
Instead, a quadrotor supports itself with
this thrust force generated by its rotors as they spin through the air.
In fact, these two forces, gravity and thrust,
are the only two types of forces that
we will be thinking about or modeling in this course.
In reality, there's at least one more force which affects the motion of a quadrotor,
and that is air resistance or drag.
Drag is a friction force caused by the motion of a body through a fluid such as air.
For example, the quadrotor experiences a drag force because
of the difference in velocity between the vehicle body and the air.
And there's even drag related to each propeller's individual motion.
In practice, we usually treat drag as a disturbance when designing quadrotor controllers,
and don't model it explicitly as the effects are relatively small at
lower vehicle and wind speeds and
because it's difficult to identify the correct drag model.
So let's focus on these two forces,
the force from gravity or weight,
and the forces from each of the rotors, thrust.
As is all forces,
the size of these forces is measured in a unit called newton.
Force is a vector,
and that means that when we analyze a force,
we need to know both the size or magnitude of
that force as well as the direction that force points.
For gravity, the force always points straight downwards toward the center of the earth.
And the strength of the force is given by M times G where M is
the mass of the quadrotor and G is the acceleration due to gravity,
which is about 9.81 meters per second square.
This is the rate at which an object will
accelerate downwards when it's dropped here on Earth.
The strengths of the thrust vector depends on the size and
shape of the rotor's plates and on how fast they are spinning.
And the direction of a rotor's thrust vector is
always perpendicular to the plane that the rotor is spinning in.
When we control a quadrotor,
all we actually get is to control the magnitude of these four thrust vectors.
That's it.
What's really amazing is that by properly controlling the size of these four thrusts,
we can get quadrotors to do amazing things.
We can tell it where to go,
how fast to get there and can even commanded it to perform amazing fleets of agility.
The details of how this control
works is something you will learn over the course of this lesson,
but the intuition is something you might already have a sense for.