By the end of this course,
you will understand, in detail,
how to command these force thrust vectors to make a quadrotor
to do all sorts of amazing things.
But before we get into the full three-dimensional case,
it will be helpful to start simple,
and then add complexity.
So with that in mind,
let's start very simple.
Instead of thinking how a quadrotor moves,
let's first think about how a monorotor hovers.
In this lesson, and some of the lessons that follow,
you'll notice that we occasionally work with
different vehicle models to highlight different aspects of the underlying physics.
Sometimes we'll work with a full quadrotor moving in three dimensions,
but other times we will work with a simpler vehicle which moves in fewer dimensions.
The monorotor, as the name implies,
has only one rotor,
which means there's only one thrust vector to think about.
And when a monorotor is hovering,
it's in a state called translational equilibrium.
When an object is in translational equilibrium,
it means it's not experiencing any translational acceleration.
A translation is any non-rotational motion.
So, zero translational acceleration,
just means an object isn't accelerating towards the left or right,
or up or down, or forward or backward.
The only way an object can be in translational equilibrium,
is if the net force on the object is zero.
And this means that any upwards force is balanced by an equal downwards force,
and likewise, for right left and forward back forces.
If the weight of a hovering monorotor like this one
results in a force that is equal to 100 Newtons down,
what can we say about the total thrust provided by its one rotor.