If the weight vector of a monorotor is 100 newtons down,
then if it's hovering,
the thrust must be 100 newtons up.
To calculate the mass of this mono rotor we have to remember that weight is
a product of mass and the acceleration due to gravity, which is 9.81.
So 100 divided by 9.81 would give a mass of about 10.2 kilograms,
which means this is a pretty big quadrotor.
The last question was a little tricky,
and was really meant to get you thinking.
But actually, it's impossible for a monorotor to sit truly motionless in the sky.
And that's because a monorotor can never be in what's called rotational equilibrium.
At this point, I'd like to show you a video of what an actual monorotor can look like.
As you watch, notice the rotation of the monorotor's body.