The rotors that spin clockwise,
introduce a counterclockwise moment, and vice versa.
When the clockwise rotors are spinning faster than the counterclockwise ones,
then the counterclockwise moment produced by those clockwise rotors dominates,
and the vehicle will yar in the counterclockwise direction.
But at what rate will it yaw?
What are the magnitudes of the moments and forces that the spinning rotors produce?
We use the lowercase Greek letter, omega,
to represent the rotation rate of a rotor,
and this rate is measured in units of Radians per second.
So, when omega is two pi,
the rotor is doing one rotation per second.
It turns out, that when a rotor spins for the rotation rate of omega,
the thrust produced and the induced moment are both proportional to the omega squared.
The constant of proportionality,
we call k sub f for force,
and k sub m for moment.
The actual value of these constants depends on the size and shape of the plates,
the specific motors used,
as well as the density of the surrounding air they operate in.
In practice, we usually obtain these values empirically.