Unbalanced forces cause acceleration.
When an object experiences an unbalanced force,
it accelerates in the direction of the net force.
So if thrust is bigger than weight,
there will be an upwards acceleration.
A mathematical relationship between force and acceleration is this,
F equals mass M times acceleration A.
The F in this equation,
is the net force on whatever object we're talking about,
and the acceleration is measured in an inertial frame.
That is, a reference frame that is not accelerating,
like the world frame introduced earlier.
In general, F and A are vectors and have magnitude and direction.
But these vectors can be analyzed on a pure direction basis.
So, if we look in the vertical direction,
then the set component of force will cause an acceleration in the set direction.
Since acceleration is the second derivative of position,
we can say F sub Z is equal to M times Z double dot.
So, if a monorotor with a mass of two kilograms has these forces acting on it,
then the net force would be 23.6 minus 19.6, or 4 newtons.
And this would cause an acceleration of two meters per second squared for this vehicle.