We just incorporated the fact that phi is small,
and we got rid of our sines and cosines,
and now our equations look like this.
And what I really like about these equations,
is that the set acceleration depends only on U1,
and phi acceleration depends only on U2.
The one thing that's bothering me still,
is this Y term because it contains the product of two variables, U1 and phi.
At this point, it helps to remember that near hover U1 will just be
equal to MG plus some small deviation delta U1,
which can be positive or negative.
And likewise, when we linearize around hover,
phi will be close to its value at hover.
So phi will be zero plus some small deviation delta phi.
Now, if we plug these versions of phi and U1 into the equations for Y double dot,
we find the following.
After multiplying out these terms,
we are left with the equation for Y double dot.
The first term is G times delta phi.
And remember, we are assuming delta phi is very small,
so this product will be a small number.
But the second term has this delta U times delta phi,
which is a very small number times another very small number.
And the key insight behind most linearization is this,
the product of a very small number times a very small number,
is a tiny number whose value is so small that it can be safely ignored.
And that means, we can just cancel out this last term,
and we are left with the following equation.
And remember, near Hover delta phi and phi are the same thing.
So, this equation reduces to the following truly linear equation for Y double dot,
Y double dot equals G times phi.
And that gives us the full linearized decoupled dynamics.