Now that we have our linearized equations that should work well around the hover state,
we need to actually use these equations to control the state of the vehicle.
And looking at these equations,
it's easiest to think about how you would control the z position of the drone.
In fact, we have seen this very equation in the last lesson.
There, we have defined U1 bar to
remind us just how directly we can control a z acceleration.
By properly setting U1,
you can directly set the vertical acceleration of the drone.
And as time passes,
this influences the vertical velocity which over time influences the vertical position.
And in the last lesson,
you learned how to use a PID controller to control exactly this system.
And in fact, we will use a very similar controller in
this lesson to control the altitude of our 2D drone.
But how do we control the y position?
This is still a second order system and we are
still going to control y through its second derivative.
So we will still have something like this.
And when we look at equation 1,
we can see that we need to change phi to set y double dot.
But we don't have direct control over phi.
We only have control over its second derivative.
So this thing we have control over is U2.
We want to control y.
So what we need to do is to use U2 to set phi double dot.
After two integrations, this will give us a phi which relates directly to y double dot.
Then, after two more integrations,
this gives us y position.
In short, we can control y but we have to do it through phi.
And when we think about the system this way,
we can see that U2 bar is equal to the fourth derivative of the y position.
So we can enforce a step change in y for a triple dot,
but we cannot enforce a step change in any lower derivative.
Take a second to think about this.
What are the implications for control?