So we have these two equations,
u1 bar equals z double dot,
and u2 bar equals y quadruple dot,
and written this way,
it's easy to see why we can call these equations decoupled.
Now, u1 controls z and u2 controls y,
but this control is through the fourth term derivative rather than a second.
In the last lesson,
you learned how to design a PID controller for double integrator system,
like the first equation,
and we can draw a diagram to show how data flows in that 1D case.
Here, we pass in a target position velocity and acceleration from our trajectory planner,
as well as the measured position and velocity of the quadrotor.
And we use a PID controller to output a single thrust command you want to the vehicle.
Now, how do we get u2?
Remember we are controlling y indirectly.
u2 can be used to control phi,
and phi can be used to control y.
And each of these equations are double integrator equations which we know how to control.
And this indirect control can be accomplished by simply using a second PID controller.
This lower flow of data from y to phi to u,
is called a cascaded controller.
Using a cascaded controller like this,
it's good when there are multiple loops operating at different time scales.
So in this case, our y controller is the slow controller.
It might be running with a 10 to 100 hertz update rate,
and every time it gets called,
it provides a command at phi to the inner faster loop controller,
which is likely running with a 100 to 1,000 hertz update rate.
Practical reasons for running the outer loop at
a lower rate and the inner loop at a higher rate,
are the sensors that provide the information to close the loop.
For position, we use GPS outdoors or vision indoors,
which both usually have an update rate of around 1 to 10 hertz.
For angle and angle rate information,
we're using inertial measurement unit,
which has around a 100 times faster up update rate usually.
In the next few exercises,
you will implement the cascaded controller by first
implementing and tuning the inner faster loop.
Once this loop can be relied on to realize the phi commanded by the outer loop,
you can then implement the outer loop,
which takes all the y variables as input,
and produces a command at phi as an output.