Congratulations!
Hopefully at this point you've implemented your first Cascade controller.
I mentioned earlier that we want the outer loop,
in this case the right position loop of a controller to be
able to rely on the inner loop of the inner controller.
Why? Because the outer loop assumes it can actually command phi.
So, it basically assumes that the phi command is
achieved at the time it computes the next target value.
What that means is that whenever the outer loop gets executed the inner loop
should have reached whatever rule had been commanded by the outer loop previously.
And in order for that to happen the inner loop
needs to be running on a faster time scale than the outer loop.
In the next exercise,
you'll explore that idea a little more deeply.