The cascaded controller you have been working with
uses the Linearized Dynamics we discussed earlier.
And now it's time to convert that controller to
a non-linear controller based on the non-linear dynamics we started with.
And this isn't too much of a change,
we still aim to have three double integrator equations that we control but to get
those this time we need some non-linear transformations,
as a result there are two big changes to the overall data flow.
Now we have to recap all the z and y motions by
passing the commanded thrust to the by position controller as well as to the drone.
And notice that we chose the command thrust based
only on the desires that motion and the current measured angle phi.
We don't consider the effect that thrust will have on the y motion.
Even so that command thrust will wind up impacting both the z and y motion.
In the next activity,
you will turn the linear controller you've been working with into a non-linear one.
The actual mass that you'll implement is shown below.