Congratulations!
You've implemented some pretty serious control logic in
this lesson and learned quite a bit about control theory in the process.
First, you saw how the 2D plane of quadrotor is
an underactuated system because while it has three degrees of freedom, with its y, z,
and phi coordinates, they only directly control two quantities,
the thrust and the rotational movement,
which we called U1 and U2.
Then you saw how we could directly control two of those three degrees of freedom,
namely y and z, if we sacrifice control of the third degree of freedom.
Then we started thinking about how we would control y and z,
and you saw that when we linearize the dynamics of the system around the hover state,
the equations that governed y and z became decoupled,
which meant we could control each independently.
U1 could be used to control the altitude and
U2 could be used to control the lateral motion in the y direction.
Then we noticed something interesting,
and that was how U2 controlled the motion in the y direction.
Instead of controlling y directly,
it did so by first controlling the intermediate variable of roll, or phi.
This realization led us to use a cascaded control structure where you first
implemented and tuned the inner faster control loop which controlled the roll angle,
and once that was working,
you implemented a slower outer control loop which took information about
the y trajectory and used it to set the target roll angle for the inner controller.
In the next lesson,
you'll be taking the complexity and realism up a level by
designing a controller for quadrotor of that operates in a three-dimensional world.