Welcome back. In the last lesson,
you learned about PID control,
and how it can be used to control a vehicle
that moves purely in the vertical set direction.
The equation underlying these dynamics look like this.
And here, z double dot is the acceleration in the z direction,
and u1 is a total upward thrust control input.
And m and g represent mass and gravitational acceleration.
And since m and g are constants,
they actually aren't that interesting mathematically.
So, another way of writing this equation is like this.
Where u1 bar equals g minus u1 over n.
And this rewriting of that equation,
helps us to remember that we have direct control over z double dot.
This lesson is all about solving
control problems where the dynamics get a bit more complicated.
Recall from lesson one,
the dynamics of a 2D quadrotor moving in the yz plane.
The equations of motion looked like this.
And we're going to be dealing with these equations throughout this lesson.
And for now, I want you to focus your attention on this u1 and u2.
These variables represent the total applied thrust from the rotors,
and the total applied torque from the rotors respectively.
And they're both quantities which we can control directly.