In the previous lesson,
the vehicle could only move up and down.
Another way of saying this,
is that the vehicle only had one degree of freedom.
Likewise, the vehicle could be controlled through one control variable,
the total thrust. And this worked fine.
One controllable variable, thrust,
could control one degree of freedom, the z position.
But a quadrotor moving in the two-dimensional vertical plane is fundamentally different,
as is a quadrotor moving in three-dimensions,
but we'll get to that in the next lesson.
This two-dimensional system has two properties that
the one-dimensional system did not, under-actuation and coupling.
Let's start with under-actuation.
Notice, that now we have three degrees of freedom,
Y, Z, and phi.
But we only have two variables that we can set directly, U1 and U2.
If you try to use these two variables to
control all three degrees of freedom simultaneously,
you will find that it just cannot be done.
Such a system is under-actuated.
Luckily, for us, it's still possible to control two of the degrees of freedom,
as long as we sacrifice control of the third degree of freedom.
So, for our purposes in this lesson,
we will be able to define a trajectory with particular values of Y and Z for instance,
and you'll be able to write a controller that can actually follow that trajectory.