In the previous video,
I mentioned that if you want to control y and z,
you have to sacrifice control of phi.
And one way of understanding why this
is the case is to look at how these equations are coupled.
So, looking at the y equation,
we see there's a sine phi term.
So, this means that y behavior is somehow tied to the roll angle phi.
In the z equation,
you can see there's also a phi term,
a cosine phi, which means that z behavior is also tied to the roll angle.
So, we can say that y and z motion are coupled through the roll angle phi.
Let's think through what would happen if we tried to
simultaneously control y, z, and phi.
First, let's control some phi behavior.
Well, looking at the last equation of motion,
you can see that we can do this but
it will require spending one of our control variables,
in this case, u2.
Next, we could specify y behavior.
But since we've already fixed phi,
we have to spend our other control variable to fix y,
in this case u1.
Now, if you try to specify z, we find that we can't.
We've already used up most of our control variables and we have
no more control knobs left to turn to influence the system.
So, you can see that the messiness of the system,
is in some ways,
due to the coupling inherent in the system.
If you want a picture to demonstrate this coupling,
you can think of a vehicle pitched at some angle phi.
Any thrust that it commands will be shared in the y and z directions.
This coupling has important consequences for the controller architecture,
which you'll understand by the end of this lesson.