In this lesson, you will learn how to design and implement
a full cascaded control of an underactuated quad moving in two dimensions.
You've going to get there in three main steps.
First, we'll start by linearizing
the 2D dynamic equations that I've shown you a few times already.
Linearization is an incredibly useful mathematical tool
that's used throughout robotics to tame the math when it becomes hard to work with.
And in this case,
linearization will also lead to decoupling of
the dynamics of the system in the y and z directions,
which means we'll be able to think about each of these directions completely separately.
Next, we'll find that y control in the z direction can still use
a single PID controller like the one you have worked with in the last lesson.
The y direction won't be quite as easy.
To control the vehicle in the y direction,
we will need to introduce what's called the cascaded control structure.
Once you're comfortable with a cascaded control architecture,
we will reintroduce the nonlinear equations of motion
and you will implement a full non-linear cascaded controller,
which controls a drone that can move in the y or z plane.
This is an important stepping stone to watch the full 3D control of a quadrotor.
Remember, the quadrotor is symmetric and the
forward-back motion will be very similar to the left-right motion.