These equations are really useful equations.
They tell us what will happen for any angle and any thrust and any torque.
So, these equations are good because one,
they for the most part capture the true physics of the system.
And because of that, they can make
pretty accurate predictions about how the systems will change in time.
And two, these equations work at any angle for any controls.
They don't break down when numbers get too big or too small.
And in general, this is why you use non-linear equations when you choose to use them.
But these are not linear differential equations,
the equations would be linear if
the right hand side of each of the equations would be in a form like this,
where the cs are constants.
So, no sine, cosine or multiplication of input and state like u times phi.
If you try to plot them as a function of u1 of phi or any of the variables,
you would get straight lines.
And control theorists love when equations are linear.
We have a large tool set of linear control techniques
for which we can prove stability in a straightforward way.
We love linear equations so much that sometimes we'll bend over
backwards to find linear approximations for non-linear equations like this.
And in the next few segments,
I want to show you some intuition for how we linearize these sorts of equations.