The fundamental idea of linearization is to approximate
a non-linear equation locally by a linear equation.
To explain this idea,
let's leave the world of quadrotors and just talk about the mass for a second.
Take this quadratic function for example,
f of x = x squared.
And let's say we want to linearize this function around x = 1.
We call x = 1 the operating point.
We want to find a straight line that best approximates the graph at this point,
which means it has to pass through
this point and it has to have the same slope at this point.
We can find the slope of the parabola at
this point using calculus and pretty quickly find
that this is the tangent line to the graph of the parabola at the operating point.
Now, if you zoom in close to the operating point,
you can see that in this region,
the blue and the black line are really close to each other.
So the blue line is a really good linear approximation of y = x squared in this region.
Now, what's the equation of this blue line?
What linear equation gives a good approximation to
f of x equals x squared when x is close to 1?
Well, the equation for this line winds up being 2 x - 1.
But there's a more informative way we can write that.
Now, I wrote this equation in a very particular way.
Let me explain. First, look at this x - 1.
Another way to think of this term is as delta x.
It tells you how far x is from the operating point,
which in this case was 1.
Then there's this one over here.
That's just the value of the original function at the operating point of x = 1.
The original function was x squared and 1 squared is just 1.
Then there's this 2.
This 2 winds up being the slope of the original function at the operating point.
And you can get that by taking the derivative of the original function.
And so we are left with this very general result.
This says that the equation of the best linear approximation of a function around
an operating point is just the value of
that original function plus this other term which is just the slope,
f prime, times the deviation from the operating point delta x.