The first thing we did in the previous example,
was to choose the operating point that we wanted to linearize around.
The first step in linearizing any non linear system is
to choose some state of the system to linearize around.
Now, let's think about quadrotors again.
What state of the system does it make sense to linearize around?
What should we choose as an operating point?
Since our approximations are only valid in a small region around the operating point,
it's helpful to linearize around an equilibrium state.
An equilibrium exists when we can find certain fixed and non changing control inputs,
where the velocities and accelerations in the y,
z and phi dimensions are all zero.
Intuitively, this is a state that the vehicle can
actually stay at for an extended period of time.
For a quadrotor, the only state that is in equilibrium is usually called hover.
I'm going to ask some questions about hover.
You can answer any of these by thinking mathematically,
or intuitively about what it means to hover.
But try to use both approaches before you submit any of the answers.