When hovering, role must be zero.
If it variant then y double dot would be non-zero.
y and z can be anything,
and this makes sense intuitively.
A quadrotor can hover here or it can hover over there.
The values of its y and z coordinates don't matter.
It's thrust, u1 must be empty to support the weight.
And u2 must two zero to ensure zero rotational acceleration.
So we are linearizing around the state in the system where these statements are true.
And I want to point out that while
these exact values must hold for the quadrotor to hover.
We want to linearize around hover.
When we linearize around an equilibrium point,
we aren't just solving the control problem for that one equilibrium configuration.
In this case hover,
but we find an approximation for other configurations that are nearby in the state space.
So, the next thing I want to do in this derivation is
figure out the consequences of phi being close to zero.
As you can see phi shows up in the sine in the y term and the cosine in the z term.
And both of these contribute to the non-linearity of the system.
So it will be good to simplify this part.
So let's look at what happens to the one term sine of phi when phi is close to zero.
And to do this let's zoom in.
When we measure phi in radians and then zoom in very close to phi is equal to zero.
The graph of y equals to sine of phi looks almost identical to y is equal to phi.
Linearization finds the line that is the tangent to the operating point.
And here the line tangent to sine of phi at phi equal to zero is y equals phi.
So, if we are trying to approximate
sine of phi in the neighborhood of phi is equal to zero.
It seems like we should just replace sine of phi with phi.
Likewise, if we zoom in on the cosine function.
We can see that cosine of phi and
its tangent line are about equal to one when phi is small.
So we can replace cosine of phi with
one and that will change our z double dot equation.
This is a big step.
We've gotten rid of our sines and cosines.