In this lesson, I'm going to start off by giving you a little bit of
history and the context around autonomous flying robots.
This program is all about flying cars which present their own set of challenges,
but autonomous flying machines are not necessarily a new thing.
In fact, if you've ever been on an airplane,
you've traveled inside of an autonomous flying robot.
So, I'll talk a little bit about the history of
flight and where we're at today on the cusp of a transportation revolution.
After that, I'll introduce the experimental platform you'll be
working with and the projects for this program, the quadrotor drone.
I'll go over the main components of the quadrotor and how each needs to be
selected considering the task or mission you want your drone to do.
With this bit of background on autonomous flight and basic knowledge about quadrotors,
you'll be ready to move on to the next lesson where
you'll write code to fly autonomously in a simulator.