The autopilot is a computer that is responsible for knowing
just how much thrust to apply to each motor in order to hover,
pitch, roll or yod a vehicle.
The autopilot is responsible for adjusting that thrust in order to
level out once the vehicle is moving at a particular speed,
and then once it gets close to its destination to
pitch backwards in order to decelerate and stop.
So, we're always moving the vehicle body.
We're pitching it forward and backward,
we're rolling it left and right in order to move from one place to another.
So how can the autopilot, a piece of electronics,
actually know how to control the speed of
the different propellers in order to achieve the desired result?
To make this happen, the autopilot first needs to know about
the current thrust vector magnitude and
direction and then make
small adjustments to the speed of each of the four spinning motors,
in order to make sure that the intended thrust vector matches what you want.
But it's not possible for the autopilot to figure
out how fast the vehicle is going or what
the total thrust is without actually
knowing something first about the attitude of the vehicle.
So, we've arrived at a conundrum.
The autopilot is required to control the vehicle attitude,
but in order to apply proper control,
it must first know the attitude of the vehicle.
So, how can the autopilot get this information?
Well, that requires sensors.