So, we said that the autopilot can control
the attitude of a quadrotor by controlling the motors,
but in order to know what thrust to apply to each motor,
it must first know the attitude of the vehicle as well.
Thankfully, there is a solution.
By far and away, the most common sensor the drones used for sensing
their attitude is what's known as an inertial measurement unit or IMU.
Have you ever wondered what kind of magic allows your phone to
understand which way you're holding
the screen or what direction you're pointing the camera?
That magic in your phone is an IMU inside.
So, the IMU is a bit of a complicated device.
Most IMUs consists of three gyroscopes and three accelerometers.
Let's first talk about the gyros.
You could think of a gyroscope like a spinning top.
In fact, here's a gyroscope right here.
Let's spin it up and mount in on our quadrotor.
You have a gyroscope inside a drone,
and the drone changes its attitude.
In this case, it turns its role of pitch.
The gyroscope maintains its orientation.
So, you can directly measure how much the drone has changed
its attitude relative to the gyro inside.
And if you have three of them spinning inside the vehicle at right angles to each other,
then you can measure how much the vehicle is moving
and rotating in each of those three directions.
So, gyroscopes are like spinning tops and they maintain
their orientation to the world over short periods of time slowly drifting.
So, they can serve as a reference over short periods of time.
The gyros inside the IMU in your drone
can tell you how the vehicles attitude is changing,
but we'd like to know exactly how it is
changing relative to some reference coordinate frame.
To do that, we need to have accelerometers in our IMU as well.