We started off this lesson with a bit of
a history of flight and in particular, autonomous flight.
Fast-forward to the modern day,
and we're on the cusp of a transformation in technology,
where flying cars will become a reality.
I introduced our test platform for studying autonomous flight, the quadrotor drone.
I covered the basics of what components go into a quadrotor and
how they function together as an autonomous flying machine.
While the sensors and
mechanical components of a drone are interesting in their own right,
the flight computer is the brain of the whole operation and really,
where the most exciting stuff happens.
So, in this program,
we'll be focused primarily on writing software for the flight computer.
We'll look at how to do basic autonomous flight,
3D motion planning, implementing different control loops,
state estimation, and much more.
That said, we won't lose sight of
the fact that the software you write for your flight computer,
needs to actually function on real hardware at the end of the day.
So, while the projects you complete for
this program will be carried out in a simulator at first,
we'll also be showing you how to port your project code onto a real vehicle,
should you be inspired to do so.
Next up, your first project: event-driven programming for autonomous flight.