We'll be using the quadrotor drone as our test platform for learning about flying cars.
But first, I figure we should pause for
a moment and talk about just what to call these things.
Within the world of flying robots,
you'll hear people argue about whether the proper name is UAV or UAS,
which stands for unmanned aerial vehicle or unmanned aerial system.
You'll also hear the names quadrotor,
quadcopter, multirotor, and drone used to describe these.
For our purposes, the name is not particularly relevant, call it what you will.
We'll be working with a small helicopter that has four rotors.
I might sometimes called the drone a quadrotor or maybe even just a quad,
but just know that I'm always referring to the same thing.
You might also wonder why four rotors,
why not three or six or eight?
The truth is that other multi rotor configurations
would be equally valid as an experimental platform.
But the convenience symmetry of quadrotors and
the fact that they are the most common drones available for purchase,
make them an obvious choice for this program.
So, why are people talking so much about drones these days?
Well, a couple of things have changed in recent years.
They make this an exciting time to be working on them.
One is that we now have low cost high power microelectronics that have allowed us to take
the autopilots that have kept aircraft flying on
a straight and level for many decades and make them much cheaper,
smaller, and lighter so that we can put them on much smaller aircraft.
We want these tiny aircraft to perform more and more complicated missions so that as
we take the human pilot out of
the equation we need to replace that human with a computer.
So another advantage of cheap microelectronics
is that small computers are widely available and
capable of performing complex in-flight data
crunching tasks that used to require a human brain.
Another thing that has changed is how we power our aircraft.
Most aircraft for the past 100 years had been powered using
carbon-based fuels such as jet fuel or gasoline.
But now we have access to high energy density batteries and
high power density batteries that can be used to power small aircraft like a quadrotor.
And finally, a major development in the last 30 years or so has
been the availability of the global positioning system or GPS.
A small drone can now be outfitted with a GPS receiver and get
constant updates on its position which is a tremendous aid to autonomous navigation.
So with the advent of
powerful lightweight computers and batteries as well as GPS for navigation,
we're at an amazing moment in history where tiny flying machines can
autonomously perform incredibly complex tasks and that is
why the modern quadrotor drone serves as
a perfect test platform for developing algorithms to control the flying car.
Now, you might already own a quadcopter or you might be
considering building one to test your code on as you go through this program.
So next, I'll talk a bit about
the various components that make up a quadrotor drone and what
the trade-offs are in each case when deciding
which components to select if you decide to build your own drone.