The frame for your quad is really just a rigid mount for the motors and electronics.
For the vast majority of quadrotor helicopters,
there really isn't anything that special about the frame.
It's just the base to which everything else is connected.
The frame has to be strong enough to support the components of the vehicle,
yet light enough that it can be lifted along with
all the other components by the motors and propellers.
But other than that, you don't need to worry
much about aerodynamics or other complications.
That said, there are people working on
different materials and different designs for frames.
So, I don't mean to say that there aren't a lot of interesting questions to be answered,
but frankly, you can make
a perfectly serviceable quadrotor frame out of household materials.
There's even a company out there that sells
drone kits where you build the frame out of Lego.
The simplicity of the frame is one of the big differences between multi rotor drones and
other more conventional aircraft where things like
aerodynamics and structural integrity are a much bigger concern.