The next component of your quadrotor to think about is the power supply, the battery.
Most quadrotors and other electric propulsion aircraft
use lithium polymer or LiPo batteries, like this one.
These are basically the same battery technology that's in your cell phone or your laptop.
However, quadrotor batteries are a little bit different in
their design because they need to be able to discharge very quickly.
This makes them a lot more dangerous than
the batteries in your laptop or your cell phones.
And consequently, LiPo batteries also have to be charged very carefully.
It's worth noting that in most quadrotor batteries,
there are actually multiple batteries in one.
And so you have to think about making sure that
each cell of the battery is charged the same as the others,
so that one cell of the battery isn't discharging into another.
We'll talk more about safety and balancing batteries later on in the program.
For now, suffice it to say that in choosing a battery,
you just need to make sure it has
enough capacity to fly the kinds of missions you want to fly,
which means first and foremost,
that it has enough power to lift the vehicle and payload,
but also that it be able to comfortably last for the duration of the mission.