Hello. Welcome to our autonomous systems interview course.
I'm Michael, the learning technologist from our self-driving car team here at Udacity.
I'm a graduate of the School of autonomous systems myself,
as I completed the self-driving car engineer in
every program prior to joining Udacity and now,
I'm responsible for leading constant updates we make to the program.
Today, we're here to help you interview for a job and all things autonomous,
whether it be robotics,
self-driving cars, flying cars and more.
First, we're going to show you some example interviews.
You'll watch to see how the interviewees responds to each question,
how they worked through the problem at hand and how
they show their interviewer their thought process.
After each video, you'll have the chance to
reflect on what you thought the interviewee did well,
what they didn't do well and then hear from
the interviewer themselves on what they thought of the approach and answer.
A big item to note here is the focus is not just on solving the problem quickly,
the interviewer wants to see your thought process behind tackling the problem.