Aaron did a great job in is deep learning interview.
He went through and clearly stated
what all made up semantic segmentation and how it works.
He did a very good job in going through the technical nature
of a neural network and explaining the encoder to decoder network,
and especially when he started getting into
his loss functions which are extremely important for semantic segmentation.
It was clear that he knew what he was talking about.
One of the things I would probably ask Aaron to do, otherwise,
is maybe to even code a little bit of his neural network perhaps in TensorFlow or Keras,
just to show his knowledge of those deep learning libraries.
Other than that, though, I really liked Aaron's answer.
He showed his technical knowledge really well,