Well hey, welcome today Aaron.
I'm really glad to have you here in the interview for a motion planner position.
To start things off, I actually have a question
about motion plan that I'd like to go with.
Are you ready to get started?
Sure, let's do it.
All right. So my question for you is assume we have a vehicle
that's driving down a highway and there's other vehicles on
the highway but you're also stay in a country area where it's a small town,
there might be a stoplight or pedestrians also involved.
In this case, could you construct for me
a behavior tree of finite state machine perhaps to what behaviors your car's do.
Sure, so we're talking about a finite state machine.
So let's think about the different states of the car might find itself in.
Great.
So let's say that we have a three lane highway and maybe our car is sitting right here.
So let's think of this simple situation first.
We don't have any other cars that we're worried about,
we just want to stay in our lane.
So, we actually have perfect localization and
control and we're just generating these waypoints along our lane.
We want to know what speed to be following this trajectory.
So, there's a target speed on this highway.
That is one of our parameters.
If we're going less than that target speed,
then we want to accelerate.
So, if our speed is less than a target speed,
we need to go faster.
However, if our speed is too great,
we don't want to get pulled over by the cops so we want to deaccelerate.
This helps us out with just staying in this lane.
Now let's think about the situation where we have other cars.
So sooner or later we're going to run into this following car
and we can have a sensor that helps us out with this.
We can use radar and the radar can tell us how close we are to this other vehicle.
So now, we have another parameter that we're dealing with which is the radar distance.
Okay.
Let's say that we have some safe following distance.
So, if the radar distance becomes too small from the safe following distance,
then we need to deaccelerate.
However, there's other options that we have too.
We are on a three-lane highway.
So we could actually try to change lanes and to do that,
we can use another sensor such as Lidar to see if there's any cars in this window here.
If that's open, we can actually switch over to the other lane.
If it's occupied, we could just deaccelerate and just keep following this car.
We also have other options to if we're in the middle lane,
we can actually go to either lane depending on this strict like lane passing rules.
Yeah, great.
Then we'll find ourselves in this situation for
this country side where we have this crosswalk.
In this case, we actually want to stop at this crosswalk if there's
a stop sign and then use perception to see if there's any pedestrians crossing it.
If there aren't any pedestrians and it's clear,
then we can proceed with where we want to go.
We can either go straight, go off to right,
go off to the left, depending on where our final destinations at.
Pretty similarly if it's a stop sign or if it's a traffic light,
we can actually use perception to see if the light is green or
red and then proceed as needed.
Great.
Where it gets pretty interesting is when we're
generating this trajectory for changing lanes.
So, part of our motion planning scheme is actually figure out how this trajectory looks.
So, we can have these different cars when changing lanes.
For doing this, we actually want to take into consideration the other cars nearby.
So, as well as the passengers in this car.
We want to look at and monitor acceleration and jerk and how close we're
getting to say other cars and how fast they're going.
We're predicting out into the future.
One interesting way of doing this.
So you can have a cost function do is actually.
Okay.
Generate a polynomial curve this way.
You could actually use an MPC,
Model Predictive Controller to figure out how to generate this trajectory.
To do that, you're actually creating the right cost function where you
want your acceleration to be low,
your jerk to be low and to have a nice safe following distance between cars.
Great, you mentioned the model predictive controller,
have you implemented that in something you worked on?
Yeah, actually I have.
It's a pretty interesting case.
It was for doing parallel parking.
Really? How did you do that with parallel parking?
Yes. So let's say you have your car right here
and you're trying to park it right in between these two other cars.
It's all about generating the right cost function to do this.
So we have our center of the car and we have a target as
well and we have our heading and we have the heading that we want to end up in.
So at the end of the day, we'd want our car to fit perfectly right in here.
So that's per our cost function.
We want to minimize this distance and how the headings are lining up.
Where it gets very interesting is we don't want to collide into these other cars.
So we can go ahead and construct some boundary lines that we're dealing with
and we'll accumulate lots of negative points
if we're actually intersecting in-between these
and we can actually monitor this by looking at the vertices.
Great.
If we do this and we make sure that it's differentiable by
basically using these s-curves,
then we can actually have this cost function and I've
gotten pretty good results doing parallel parking with this MPC.
Great, that's a really interesting application I think.
Yeah, there's a lot of fun designing it.
Awesome. Well, that's all I have for
this question and let's go ahead and move on to next topic.
Sure.