Aaron had a great answer on motion planning.
He went through and went from very basic steps and slowly
advanced up from a single car driving on the highway by itself,
to adding an additional vehicles,
and then having even the crosswalk,
which was in my original question of how to go through.
That really showed he was indicating from a very base case to the more advanced case,
how he would build out a more complex environment for his motion planning.
He also went into model predictive control,
which I thought was interesting,
and when I asked him about that,
it showed that he really had experience above and beyond what I would
probably expect for people coming into the company at that point.
So, for those reasons,
I thought it was a great answer.