Overall, I thought Mike did fairly well.
He went through and told me about how satellites work correctly,
and also ascertain that you would need more than
just a single satellite to be able to localize position correctly.
He also was right in knowing that in robotics applications,
especially for a self-driving car,
the amount of distance that GPS is accurate to is not always sufficient.
He also was very helpful in coming up with correct applications that you could use in
robotics or self-driving cars such a particle filter
and the fact that he had worked on this before,
that show me that he would be a good fit for this position.
One thing I would say that he could do is
perhaps diagram this out for me a little bit more clearly,
but other than that, I thought he gave a sufficient answer.