Michael did a great job in his interview,
actually he did a really good job of kind of highlighting the problem,
explaining the problem, and taking me through it step-by-step.
I even asked him a couple of questions in his process of going through this problem,
and that allowed him to kind of stop and explain that,
and kind of break his train of thought.
Things I like to see is if somebody can actually go through and explain something
when they have their thought broken because
sometimes people might try to rehearse something,
and not really understand it very well.
But it really showed that Michael had really good knowledge in the area,
and understood where he could go to make improvements.
Michael also showed a great depth of knowledge in the area,
and seemed to be really interested in what he was talking about.
I think he did a really good job explaining the Convolutional Neural Net,
and explaining how the encoding and decoding works.
It was really great to see how
all this passion and excitement come through during his interview.