Nice work watching and reflecting on each of the interviews.
We hope you gained some valuable insight
into how to approach some of these types of questions.
Below this video, we've included
some additional resources for you to use in
preparing for your autonomous systems interview.
Some are focused on building up your skills,
some typical programming problems you'll solve.
We suggest to do them in
the programming language you'll need for the jobs you want to apply for.
Again, for autonomous systems roles,
this typically means C++.
We also have linked some resources to help you build up your knowledge of
data structures and algorithms including runtime and complexity as well.
Again, make sure you refresh yourself on any topics listed in job responsibilities,
minimum requirements, or if you've put something on your resume.
For instance, if the job description mentioned
systems architect and real time operating systems,
you should make sure you feel comfortable in those areas.
Of course, don't forget to research the company itself.