After watching and reflecting on the example interviews, it'll be your turn.
You'll get a chance to choose questions from an area of your interest,
like deep learning engineer or controls engineer,
and answer a few questions for that role.
Along with the more role-specific questions,
you'll also be asked to respond to a question about a recent project you've worked on,
to help show your expertise and passion in that area.
This can be a deceptively important question.
Can you articulate why you chose this project?
What steps along with missteps you took along the way,
why the end result was interesting,
and potentially, even what you'd do to further improve it?
Now, before we get started on the interviews.
Let's talk through a few more important areas to
consider for interviews in autonomous systems.