Hi, Vienna.
It's really nice to meet you and I'm glad to have you in today for our position.
Yes, nice to meet you, too. I'm glad to be here.
So, one of the first things I want to ask you is
specific to the role for perception around sensor fusion.
Say, you had a robot or a self-driving car that had radar and lidar sensors on it,
how would you go about fusing that data to help you do something like object detection?
I think I'd probably just go for a common filter
that tends to be really useful for doing things like that.
I can take some of the the less
precise location estimates that you would get with a radar,
for example, fuse that with
the more exact lidar and come up with the optimal estimation for that.
Great. In that situation,
say that you had different refresh rates between the radar and lidar,
how would you be able to deal with that?
Can you give me an example of when that might come into play?
Sure. Say, if you had a radar that refreshed at, say,
80 Hertz and the lidar only refreshed at 10 Hertz,
what would you do in that situation,
or would you need to do anything?
I'm actually not sure.
I'd have to look into that a little more.
Okay. Great.
It's not something I've really been exposed to so far.
Sure. Along with that, if you also,
say, had camera data coming in, how would you use that?
Would you bring that in as an input or would you have it, say,
that you bring the data out of the radar and lidar,
and then use that towards something else?
I think I definitely want to incorporate
the camera data as well and just really make use of
as many sensors and as much data as I could to build
up the most accurate estimation of the world around,
and really playing to the strengths of each sensor and where they
can overlap and share to help correct for each other's weaknesses.
Great. Very interesting.
Have you worked with any of these types of sensors before?
I've been exposed to them a little bit at a high level
but not so much the hands-on aspects.
Okay. Great. That's all I have here on this topic,
so let's go ahead and go into the next one.
All right. Sounds good.