Vienna very quickly identified that
a Kalman filter would be a great application for sensor fusion.
That's definitely something that I would expect us to use in
her actual job role so it's great
that that was the first thing that popped into her mind,
and she explained it well.
Going forward from there, it was okay that she didn't know
exactly what she would do with different refresh rates.
It's not something, unless you've done a lot of hands on work,
that you necessarily have the experience with.
It's good that she didn't necessarily just try to come up
with a completely random answer that didn't really apply here.
So, it was great that when we got into the camera data,
she definitely identified that camera data would be important for our application,
that having more data of different types
only can become better for your perception system,
and it's important to know that that should be something we should include.
After that, again, we got into some of
the hands-on type of thing whether she'd worked in this yet,
but a lot of people don't have it.
It was something that we considered nice to have beforehand,
and it's not something that we're going to
necessarily count off for if they don't have that yet.